<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>YEG on opgenorth.net</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/YEG/</link>
    <description>Recent content in YEG on opgenorth.net</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 15 Oct 2010 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/YEG/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>YEG Open Data, the 2010 Edmonton Municipal Election, and Android</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/archives/yeg-open-data-the-2010-edmonton-municipal-election-and-android/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Oct 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/archives/yeg-open-data-the-2010-edmonton-municipal-election-and-android/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;(Or, things to do when you have a sick kid)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;&lt;img style=&#34;border-right-width: 0px; display: inline; border-top-width: 0px; border-bottom-width: 0px; margin-left: 0px; border-left-width: 0px; margin-right: 0px&#34; title=&#34;election&#34; border=&#34;0&#34; alt=&#34;election&#34; align=&#34;right&#34; src=&#34;http://www.opgenorth.net/wp-content/uploads/2010/10/election.jpg&#34; width=&#34;126&#34; height=&#34;162&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;One of the new &lt;a href=&#34;http://data.edmonton.ca/&#34;&gt;data catalogues&lt;/a&gt; that the City of Edmonton has put up is the &lt;a href=&#34;http://data.edmonton.ca/DataBrowser/coe/Election2010Results#param=NOFILTER--DataView--Results&#34;&gt;2010 Election Results&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;#160; This Thanksgiving Long Weekend I was kind of “grounded” at home when my son came down with a nasty inner ear infection.&amp;#160; I was hanging out with him, and thought I could use the time to see how hard it would be and how quickly I could put together an Android application that would poll these results and show leading candidate in each contest for a given ward.&amp;#160; Turns out it was not that hard at all.&amp;#160; Development time was less than one day, and then I had the application running on my phone for a couple of days.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>New Version of YEG Buildings up</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/archives/new-version-of-yeg-buildings-up/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Aug 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/archives/new-version-of-yeg-buildings-up/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Last night I pushed a new build of &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.androidzoom.com/android_applications/reference/yeg-buildings_icyx.html&#34;&gt;YEG Buildings&lt;/a&gt; out to the Android Market. The two changes with this one:&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;ul&gt;   &lt;li&gt;Rather than showing the latitude/longitude of were you are, the application will try to translate that into a more human-friendly address.&amp;#160; Note that the address might not be 100% accurate.&amp;#160; It depends on how much accuracy the GPS has.&lt;/li&gt;    &lt;li&gt;The application no longer uses Google Maps and a KML feed when show where all the historical buildings in Edmonton are.&amp;#160; The map of Edmonton is now rendered locally, and all &lt;/li&gt; &lt;/ul&gt;  &lt;p&gt;Just for fun, I also &lt;a href=&#34;http://contest.apps4edmonton.ca/apps/21&#34;&gt;submitted YEG Buildings&lt;/a&gt; as part of the &lt;a href=&#34;http://contest.apps4edmonton.ca/&#34;&gt;Apps4Edmonton contest&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;#160; So, feel free to check out the contest page – there are a lot of neat applications there.&amp;#160; Also feel free to vote mine up.&amp;#160; :)&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>New Version of YEG Buildings (formerly Historical Buildings)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/archives/new-version-of-yeg-buildings-formerly-historical-buildings/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Aug 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/archives/new-version-of-yeg-buildings-formerly-historical-buildings/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;After a few months of neglect, I put a new version of my Edmonton Historical Buildings application up on the Android Market.&amp;#160; I’ve renamed it to just &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.androidzoom.com/android_applications/reference/yeg-buildings_icyx.html&#34;&gt;YEG Buildings&lt;/a&gt;, as I’d like to eventually include buildings that aren’t historical, but interesting in general for some reason.&amp;#160; The previous version had a nasty bug that would crash when you tried to view the location of a building on the map.&amp;#160; Was one of those curious things where it worked in the emulator but not on a real device.&amp;#160; I’ve tried it out on my HTC Dream running &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.cyanogenmod.com/&#34;&gt;Cyanogen 6.0 RC3&lt;/a&gt; (this is Android 2.2), and it seemed to work.&amp;#160; &lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Induction Into the Android Army â the Aftermath</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/archives/induction-into-the-android-army-the-aftermath/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Jun 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/archives/induction-into-the-android-army-the-aftermath/</guid>
      <description>Thanks to all who attended my “Induction into the Android Army” talk this afternoon at the monthly &lt;a href=&#34;http://groups.google.com/group/ejug&#34;&gt;Edmonton Java User’s Group&lt;/a&gt; meeting.&amp;#160; I’d say it was a good turn out, especially when one considers that this is only the second monthly meeting for EJUG.&amp;#160; It was a pretty basic talk, and didn’t dive to deeply into the “fun” Android stuff.&amp;#160; If anybody from EJUG wants a follow up presentation that’s a bit more in depth, give a shout out on the EJUG mailing list.&amp;#160; If there is enough interest, I’d be happy to put something together.  &lt;p&gt;If you want to &lt;a href=&#34;http://developer.android.com/resources/samples/NotePad/index.html&#34;&gt;browse the code&lt;/a&gt; and don’t want to download the Android SDK, you can do so at the Android website.&amp;#160; Otherwise if you have downloaded the SDK,&amp;#160; you can the samples/Notepad folder.&amp;#160; For those who want the PowerPoint slide deck, please hang tight and I’ll get a link to that shortly.&amp;#160; Basil already has a copy of it, and he’ll probably post it to the Google Group shortly as well.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Android at the Edmonton Java User Group</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/archives/android-at-the-edmonton-java-user-group/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Jun 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/archives/android-at-the-edmonton-java-user-group/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Just a heads up for those interested:&amp;#160; On Tuesday, June 15th the Edmonton Java User’s Group is having it’s monthly meeting at noon at the Canadian Western Bank Building.&amp;#160; The speaker is none other than yours truly.&amp;#160; I’ll be giving a brief introduction to application development to Android, using my trusty G1 and IntelliJ.&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;It’s free to attend, so stop by if you’re so inclined.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Tulips are Lovely this Time of Year</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/archives/the-tulips-are-lovely-this-time-of-year/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 May 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/archives/the-tulips-are-lovely-this-time-of-year/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&amp;#160;&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;You have to love spring time in Alberta.&amp;#160; The tulips have such a contrast against the snow at 21:30 on a Saturday evening:&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.opgenorth.net/wp-content/uploads/2010/05/omvt.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img style=&#34;border-bottom: 0px; border-left: 0px; display: block; float: none; margin-left: auto; border-top: 0px; margin-right: auto; border-right: 0px&#34; title=&#34;omvt&#34; border=&#34;0&#34; alt=&#34;omvt&#34; src=&#34;http://www.opgenorth.net/wp-content/uploads/2010/05/omvt_thumb.jpg&#34; width=&#34;364&#34; height=&#34;484&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Quick Update to HistoricalBuildings</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/archives/quick-update-to-historicalbuildings/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Apr 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/archives/quick-update-to-historicalbuildings/</guid>
      <description>I just &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.opgenorth.net/misc/HistoricalBuildings.apk&#34;&gt;uploaded an update&lt;/a&gt; to &lt;a href=&#34;http://github.com/topgenorth/historicalbuildings&#34;&gt;HistoricalBuildings&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;nbsp; The list of historical buildings used to be sorted alphabetically, by name.&amp;nbsp; Now they are sorted by the distance from your current location (assuming the GPS can figure that out).&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;zemanta-pixie&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;zemanta-pixie-img&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;http://img.zemanta.com/pixy.gif?x-id=fd558971-287a-8b68-8a02-ced06dd1630f&#34; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>YEG OpenData and their Historical Buildings on your Android phone</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/archives/historical-buildings/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Apr 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/archives/historical-buildings/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.opgenorth.net/wp-content/uploads/2010/04/worksonmymachinestarburst.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img style=&#34;border-bottom: 0px; border-left: 0px; margin: 0px 10px 0px 0px; display: inline; border-top: 0px; border-right: 0px&#34; title=&#34;works-on-my-machine-starburst&#34; border=&#34;0&#34; alt=&#34;works-on-my-machine-starburst&#34; align=&#34;left&#34; src=&#34;http://www.opgenorth.net/wp-content/uploads/2010/04/worksonmymachinestarburst_thumb.jpg&#34; width=&#34;154&#34; height=&#34;149&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Well, for the brave, criminally insane, curious, or otherwise bored I have a alpha version of Historical Buildings – &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.opgenorth.net/misc/HistoricalBuildings.apk&#34;&gt;download the APK&lt;/a&gt; if you want to try it out.&amp;#160; This is just, at this time, the application just shows a simple list of &lt;a href=&#34;http://data.edmonton.ca/DataBrowser.aspx?Container=coe&amp;amp;EntitySet=HistoricalBuildings&#34;&gt;historical buildings&lt;/a&gt; in Edmonton (according to the &lt;a href=&#34;http://data.edmonton.ca/&#34;&gt;City of Edmonton&#39;s Open Data Catalogue&lt;/a&gt;).&amp;#160; Click on a building, and it will show you on Google Maps where the building is in the city.&amp;#160; The &lt;a href=&#34;http://github.com/topgenorth/historicalbuildings&#34;&gt;code&lt;/a&gt; for this is, in my opinion (and to say the least) - rough.&amp;#160; But it is a start.&amp;#160; Definitely needs some improvement.&amp;#160; Or maybe I just need to change my thinking to more of a Android/Java mindset.&amp;#160; Anyway the usual caveats apply:&amp;#160; use at your own risk / batteries not include / do not eat / void where prohibited by law, etc, etc, etc&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Me, Android, and YEG OpenData</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/archives/me-android-and-yeg-opendata/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Apr 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/archives/me-android-and-yeg-opendata/</guid>
      <description>&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.opgenorth.net/wp-content/uploads/2010/04/YegDataList1.png&#34;&gt;&lt;img style=&#34;display: inline; margin-left: 10px; margin-right: 0px; border: 0px initial initial;&#34; title=&#34;YegDataList&#34; src=&#34;http://www.opgenorth.net/wp-content/uploads/2010/04/YegDataList_thumb1.png&#34; border=&#34;0&#34; alt=&#34;YegDataList&#34; width=&#34;164&#34; height=&#34;244&#34; align=&#34;right&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Not that long ago, the City of Edmonton announced it&#39;s &lt;a href=&#34;http://data.edmonton.ca/&#34;&gt;Open Data Catalogue&lt;/a&gt;.  I noticed that one of the data catalogues was a list of &lt;a href=&#34;http://data.edmonton.ca/DataBrowser.aspx?Container=coe&amp;amp;EntitySet=HistoricalBuildings&#34;&gt;historical buildings&lt;/a&gt; in the city.  Yeah, I know that some people in other cities might consider this a pretty weak list.  I mean, the oldest building in Edmonton isn’t even 150 years old.  I’d wager that some parts of the world consider 150 year old buildings to be “new construction”.  Anyway, as I&#39;ve been dabbling with &lt;a href=&#34;http://developer.android.com&#34;&gt;Android&lt;/a&gt; now for about the past year, I thought a handy little project to try out would be to write an app for Android that would show me where the historical buildings are in the city.&#xA;&#xA;I&#39;ve got the foundation of a simple application started over a GitHub called, not surprisingly, &lt;a href=&#34;http://github.com/topgenorth/historicalbuildings&#34;&gt;Historical Buildings&lt;/a&gt; (if you pull the source code, then just a heads up that I use &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.jetbrains.com/idea/&#34;&gt;IntelliJ&lt;/a&gt; for my Android development).  This application currently works in the emulator, my next step is to installing it on my phone and trying it out for real.  Right now all the application does is present you with a list of buildings.  You click on one, and you&#39;ll see on Google Maps where the building.&#xA;&#xA;Some other ideas for features that may or may not happen:&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&#x9;&lt;li&gt;Figure out the whole unit testing story in Android.  Then setup a build script.  Then a build server.  CI rocks, but as I’m trying to learn the Android framework and figure out what all the parts are, I’m not to focused on that at the moment.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&#x9;&lt;li&gt;Don’t always fetch the data – store it locally&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&#x9;&lt;li&gt;I don’t think the way I’m parsing the JSON result is very efficient or “proper”, but it does get the job done.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&#x9;&lt;li&gt;Notify the user when they are within a certain distance of a historical building.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&#x9;&lt;li&gt;Currently YEG has a PDF explaining the significance of the building.  Not very friendly/convenient for mobile devices.  Need something better.&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&#x9;&lt;li&gt;One thought would be to create Wikipedia entries and link to that.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&#x9;&lt;li&gt;Another thought is to petition the City of Edmonton to convert their PDF’s to a more neutral format (HTML anyone)?&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&#x9;&lt;li&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.epl.ca&#34;&gt;Edmonton Public Library&lt;/a&gt; has some information about the “&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.epl.ca/EPLPhotoBuildings.cfm&#34;&gt;Lost Building of Edmonton&lt;/a&gt;”.  Maybe incorporate that somehow – perhaps showing what buildings used to exist at a given address?&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&#x9;&lt;li&gt;Perhaps allow the user to update their coordinates for YEG’s historical buildings.  I’ve notice (on the emulator) that sometimes the lat/long isn’t exactly accurate.  If you look at the image below for the old Arlington Apartments, you notice that the marker should be over the pile of rubble slightly to the left of where it currently is.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&#x9;&lt;li&gt;Maybe include buildings that aren’t necessarily designated as historical, but are interesting architecturally or otherwise.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&#x9;&lt;li&gt;Instead of using YEG OpenData, perhaps an independent cloud based data store (&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.microsoft.com/windowsazure/&#34;&gt;Azure&lt;/a&gt; maybe?)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;If you’ve got any other suggestions, I’m happy to hear them.&#xA;&#xA;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.opgenorth.net/wp-content/uploads/2010/04/MapList.png&#34;&gt;&lt;img style=&#34;display: block; float: none; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; border: 0px;&#34; title=&#34;MapList&#34; src=&#34;http://www.opgenorth.net/wp-content/uploads/2010/04/MapList_thumb.png&#34; border=&#34;0&#34; alt=&#34;MapList&#34; width=&#34;219&#34; height=&#34;326&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&lt;div class=&#34;zemanta-pixie&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;zemanta-pixie-img&#34; src=&#34;http://img.zemanta.com/pixy.gif?x-id=e1a8a615-56c6-883e-b52b-35084586f039&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Edmonton Code Camp: What Do You Want?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/archives/edmonton-code-camp-what-do-you-want/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Aug 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/archives/edmonton-code-camp-what-do-you-want/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Well, it’s coming up on fall, which is traditionally the time of year for the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.edmontoncodecamp.com&#34;&gt;Edmonton Code Camp&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;#160; It seems that there is still a spot or two left for speakers, so if you’re in Edmonton why not think of something programmy and give a talk.&amp;#160; Doesn’t have to be .NET – anything that is related to software development will do.&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;Anyway, I’ve put my name down for a talk at ECC.&amp;#160; There are several options available for me and I’m not sure which one to go with.&amp;#160; So, I figured that perhaps a straw poll would help me decide.&amp;#160; Feel free to add a comment about which topic you’d prefer:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How Much TDD is Enough?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/archives/how-much-tdd-is-enough/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Aug 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/archives/how-much-tdd-is-enough/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;At the last &lt;a href=&#34;http://groups.google.com/group/eamug&#34;&gt;Edmonton Agile Methods User Group&lt;/a&gt; meeting, we had a brief discussion around &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Code_coverage&#34;&gt;code coverage&lt;/a&gt;, and what should be an acceptable number to shoot for.&amp;#160; Is it okay when the unit tests cover 80% of the code?&amp;#160; Or should 100% be the only acceptable value?&amp;#160; After all, how can you be confident in your code knowing that 20% of it isn&#39;t tested.&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;Allow me to go out on a limb here, and state with absolute certainty that the correct answer is &amp;quot;It depends on your situation&amp;quot;.&amp;#160; Allow me to elaborate.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rod Paddock at EDMUG</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/archives/rod-paddock-at-edmug/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Jun 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/archives/rod-paddock-at-edmug/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Last night (Thursday, June 26th) &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.dashpoint.com/&#34;&gt;Rod Paddock&lt;/a&gt; gave a talk on using &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.silverlight.net&#34;&gt;Silverlight&lt;/a&gt; 2.0 to the Edmonton .NET User Group.&amp;#160; I&#39;d say that Rod did a pretty good job, despite the fact that the beta of both &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.silverlight.net&#34;&gt;Silverlight&lt;/a&gt; and Expression Blend didn&#39;t exactly want to play nice all the time.&amp;#160; It&#39;s definitely perked my interest in the technology, and I can see a lot of business potential for it. &lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;The rich user experience that &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.silverlight.net&#34;&gt;Silverlight&lt;/a&gt; brings to the web-browser, will, I think raise the bar for what web applications will do for businesses.&amp;#160; Forget all the buzz about ASP.NET MVC or MonoRail or ASP.NET 3.5.&amp;#160; This is just another layer of makeup on the tired, old, hooker that is application development in .NET.&amp;#160; &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.silverlight.net&#34;&gt;Silverlight&lt;/a&gt; is what will make business users oh and ah and get excited about web apps again.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>EDMUG Presentation on MonoRail</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/archives/edmug-presentation-on-monorail/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Apr 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/archives/edmug-presentation-on-monorail/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;On Thursday, April 24, at the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.edmug.net&#34;&gt;Edmonton .NET User&#39;s Group&lt;/a&gt;, I did a presentation on &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.castleproject.org/monorail/index.html&#34;&gt;MonoRail&lt;/a&gt; (and a bit on &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.castleproject.org/container/index.html&#34;&gt;Windsor&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.castleproject.org/activerecord/index.html&#34;&gt;ActiveRecord&lt;/a&gt;).&amp;#160; Thanks to all for coming out hear me talk.&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;I found it to be a pretty hard topic to cover in not quite 120 minutes.&amp;#160; There is just so much to cover and explain.&amp;#160; As well, it seemed that there were a couple in the crowd that felt a bit overloaded.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>EDMUG and Me</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/archives/edmug-and-me/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Apr 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/archives/edmug-and-me/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Well, this month &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.edmug.net&#34;&gt;EDMUG&lt;/a&gt; was hard up for speakers, so out of desperation they asked if I had anything to say.&amp;#160; I figured I could talk for about 30 minutes on MonoRail, and then read the newspaper out loud for the next 90 minutes.&amp;#160; Oddly, the EDMUG executive was okay with that.&amp;#160; This morning they sent out their notice to the membership:&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;blockquote&gt;   &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Thursday, April 24th&lt;/strong&gt; will not just be one of the greatest EDMUG evenings of all time, but it will also be the opportunity of a &lt;strong&gt;lifetime&lt;/strong&gt;.&amp;#160; It will be your chance to rub shoulders with&lt;strong&gt; a legend that walks like a man&lt;/strong&gt;.&amp;#160; And the name of that legend is:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/archives/one-hundred-years-old/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Apr 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/archives/one-hundred-years-old/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.opgenorth.net/wp-content/uploads/2010/03/101EdmontonFusiliers_2.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img style=&#34;border-bottom: 0px; border-left: 0px; display: inline; margin-left: 0px; border-top: 0px; margin-right: 0px; border-right: 0px&#34; title=&#34;101EdmontonFusiliers_2&#34; border=&#34;0&#34; alt=&#34;101EdmontonFusiliers_2&#34; align=&#34;right&#34; src=&#34;http://www.opgenorth.net/wp-content/uploads/2010/03/101EdmontonFusiliers_2_thumb.jpg&#34; width=&#34;115&#34; height=&#34;161&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; In April, 1908 the 101st Edmonton Fusiliers were established as Alberta&#39;s first infantry regiment.&amp;#160; The first commanding office was Lieutenant-Colonel E.B. Edwards.&amp;#160; The 101st developed slowly, as most in the Edmonton area were attracted to the 19th Alberta Dragoons, a cavalry regiment which had been established in January of 1908. &lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;When war broke out in 1914, there was some question about the legality of using the existing militia regiments to fight overseas in Europe.&amp;#160; As such, the newly formed Canadian Expeditionary Force was comprised entirely of new battalions and the 101st was not allowed to go overseas.&amp;#160; The 101st Edmonton Fusilier recruited and contributed 1,200 men to these new battalions of the 1st Canadian Division, C.E.F in 1914.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
