<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Home on opgenorth.net</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Home on opgenorth.net</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Ballistic Data</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/labradar/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/labradar/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The data files from my  &lt;a href=&#34;http://mylabradar.com&#34;&gt;Labradar&lt;/a&gt; for various ammunition.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>.22LR Ammo Evaluation - Sterling Cross</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/22LR-ammo-sterling-cross/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/22LR-ammo-sterling-cross/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Over the past couple of years there has been a surge of interest in .22 Rimfire in Canada (at least from my perspective). Arguably, it could be traced to the start of &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.mapleseedrifleman.com&#34;&gt;Project Mapleseed&lt;/a&gt; back in 2017, which then spawned the &lt;a href=&#34;https://rimfireprecision.ca&#34;&gt;Canadian Rimfire Precision Series&lt;/a&gt; in 2018, and now this year the &lt;a href=&#34;https://outlawrimfire.com&#34;&gt;Outlaw Rimfire Precision Series&lt;/a&gt;. My friends south of the border have &lt;a href=&#34;https://appleseedinfo.org&#34;&gt;Project Appleseed&lt;/a&gt; and the &lt;a href=&#34;https://nrl-22.org&#34;&gt;National Rimfire League&lt;/a&gt;. As you can see, plenty of opportunity to participate/compete with the humble .22LR cartridge.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reforming Brass: From One Cartridge to Another</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/reforming-brass-for-8mm/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/reforming-brass-for-8mm/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The 8mm Mauser (7.92x57mm) round, in it&amp;rsquo;s current incarnation, has been around since 1903. It is a improvement of the original 7.92x57mm cartridge that was developed in 1888 by Peter Paul Mauser.  Arguably, 8mm Mauser has been one of the world&amp;rsquo;s most popular cartridges, having seen significant military and civilian use over the past 100+ year. It also influenced the design of many of today&amp;rsquo;s cartridges, such as .30-06.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/images/2018-09-28-reforming-brass-for-8mm/01.png&#34; alt=&#34;8mm Mauser cartridges&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ballistics of the Norinco 7.62x51</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/norinco-762x51-ballistics/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/norinco-762x51-ballistics/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;After an amateur attempt at trying to calculate the &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/blog/2017/05/07/norinco-762x39-ballistics/&#34;&gt;BC of the Norinco 7.62x39mm&lt;/a&gt; ammunition, I thought I would do the same thing with Norinco&amp;rsquo;s 7.62x51mm ammo. As one would expect, this stuff is fairly inexpensive as well, running aroun $0.50/round. I don&amp;rsquo;t think this is &amp;ldquo;precision ammo&amp;rdquo;, but it works well enough in my rifle.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/images/Norc76251.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;First off, I pulled one bullet apart, and weight it. The projecticle itself weight 146.1 grains, so I guess this is supposed to be 147gr ammo. I measured ~ 42.0 grains of &amp;ldquo;mystery gun powder&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ballistics of the Norinco 7.62x39</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/norinco-762x39-ballistics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/norinco-762x39-ballistics/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;On of the great things about 7.62x39mm rifles (like the SKS) is that (for the time being) ammo is fairly inexpensive. A fellow who keeps his eye open for a deal can find 7.62x39mm in the range of $0.16CAD (for corrosive) to $0.30CAD (for non-corrosive) ammo. Of course being surplus ammo, finding ballistics data on this ammunition can be a bit of a trick. Granted, the 7.62x39 cartridge isn&amp;rsquo;t exactly a &amp;ldquo;precision&amp;rdquo; round, but intellectual curiousity had me wondering what the ballistic coefficient (BC) of this Norinco ammo was.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Don&#39;t Let Crud, Corruption, and Communism Kill Your Smart Watch</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/dont-let-crud-corruption-and-communism-kill-your-smartwatch/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/dont-let-crud-corruption-and-communism-kill-your-smartwatch/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I have a &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.samsung.com/global/microsite/gear/gearlive_design.html&#34;&gt;Samsung Gear Live&lt;/a&gt;. One day, all of sudden, it wouldn&amp;rsquo;t turn on after I had it charging in it&amp;rsquo;s little charging dock. I thought the problem was with the watch, and Google the symptoms led me to one of two conclusions:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The watch was defective, and I should send it back under warranty.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;I could fix the problem by taking the watch apart, disconnecting the battery for a minute, and then reconnecting the battery. Or something like that.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I was a bit dismayed that for a device not even a year old that these were my options. I was mulling over the options, and I flipped the watch over to see what tools I would need to take the watch apart (who doesn&amp;rsquo;t like disassembling electronics), when I notice that the contact points on the watch were filthy (as one the NCOs on my infantry course used to say when inspecting rifles – &amp;ldquo;crud, corruption, and communism&amp;rdquo;). You can see the contacts for the charging dock right in the picture below:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Getting Started with Data Binding in Android</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/android-data-binding-intro/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/android-data-binding-intro/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;(Note: This is an updated version of a post from June, 2015)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In May, 2015 at Google announced &lt;a href=&#34;https://developer.android.com/tools/data-binding/guide.html&#34;&gt;a data binding library for Android&lt;/a&gt;. The data binding library is currently in beta, so things might change and make what I am saying here irrelevant/obsolete. When in doubt, consult the official documentation.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s long overdue – developers no longer have to come up with their own schemes for displaying or retrieving data from their views. With two-way data binding, it&amp;rsquo;s possible to remove a lot of redundant boilerplate code from the activities and fragments that make up an application.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Wiring Up a Nest</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/wiring-up-a-nest/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/wiring-up-a-nest/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This weekend I finally broke down and installed a &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.nest.com&#34;&gt;Nest thermostat&lt;/a&gt; in my house. They have a nice &lt;a href=&#34;https://nest.com/widget/compatibility/&#34;&gt;compatibility wizard&lt;/a&gt; which does a pretty good job of showing you how to wire up your Nest based on the wires you can see in your existing thermostat.  There were two gotchas that their wiring diagram didn&amp;rsquo;t cover. Here is a picture of the old thermostat (a Rodgers-White):&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/assets/old_thermostat.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Notice that there were two &lt;code&gt;W&lt;/code&gt; wires. I&amp;rsquo;m not to sure what is up with that, I suspect that that one wire leads up to the humidifier. I ended up splicing the two wires together with a marette, and then connecting the spliced wire to the &lt;code&gt;W&lt;/code&gt; connection on the Nest. This was not documented anywhere on the Nest website.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The other thing that the &lt;code&gt;Rc&lt;/code&gt; post on the thermostat was jumpered over to the &lt;code&gt;Rh&lt;/code&gt; post. All I had to do here is remove the jumper and just plug the wire into the &lt;code&gt;Rh&lt;/code&gt; connection on my Nest. This issue was &lt;a href=&#34;https://nest.com/ca/support/article/How-do-I-install-Nest-if-my-old-thermostat-had-a-short-wire-connecting-Rh-and-Rc&#34;&gt;documented on the Nest website&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;All in all, the process was quick and easy. Now to see if the Nest actually makes a difference in my energy bill.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>My First QuadCopter</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/my-first-quadcopter/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jul 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/my-first-quadcopter/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Just recently I acquired a new quadcopter – a WL Toys 959. Total cost to me was about $75.00 and I ordered from Amazon.ca. I picked this because of the low cost and the fact that it came with camera that can do both photo and video and it was relatively inexpensive.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;First attempts at flying the quadcopter proved somewhat crash prone, so I ended up reading the manual and checking out some YouTube vidoes on quadcopter flight. Most informative was &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=LCret4rv0HE&#34;&gt;this YouTube video&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Vortex_ring_state&#34;&gt;Vortex Ring State&lt;/a&gt; and how to deal with it (thanks to colleague Joel Martinez for the tip). I have a video of my first flight – it&amp;rsquo;s nothing fancy I just wanted to take off, hover, and then land.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reloading 8mm Mauser</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/reloading-8mm-mauser/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jul 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/reloading-8mm-mauser/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;8mm Mauser is a great round, problem is that in North America it&amp;rsquo;s not always easy to find good 8x57mm ammunition. When you do manage to find it, it tends to bit a bit expensive, &amp;gt; $1.00/round. Here is where hand loading pays itself off. I used to handload my own 8x57mm, however I stopped for a few years and now I can&amp;rsquo;t seem to find my old load data.  This isn&amp;rsquo;t a horrible thing as it means I get to go to the range to test out new recipes.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nexus 5 Retrieving Shots from Shooting Chrony Beta Master</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/nexus-5-retrieving-shots-from-shooting-chrony-beta-master/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/nexus-5-retrieving-shots-from-shooting-chrony-beta-master/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I spent a little bit of time since Christmas working on an Android application that will download velocities from my Shooting Chrony Beta Master. First I pair my Android phone to my Shooting Chrony &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.opgenorth.net/blog/2015/01/21/adding-bluetooth-to-your-shooting-chrony/&#34;&gt;via bluetooth&lt;/a&gt;. A couple of taps on the screen, and lo, shot data is retrieved:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://s3.amazonaws.com/opgenorthnet-blog/hayha_0-2-1-8.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The app itself isn&amp;rsquo;t ready for public consumption, but as a proof of concept it is encouraging to see. I uploaded a &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=f86lG9KTMf8&#34;&gt;video of this to YouTube&lt;/a&gt; so you can see the application in action.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Adding Bluetooth to your Shooting Chrony</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/adding-bluetooth-to-your-shooting-chrony/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/adding-bluetooth-to-your-shooting-chrony/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;re into reloading, you know about chronographs. Odds are you might have a &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.shootingchrony.com/&#34;&gt;Shooting Chrony&lt;/a&gt;. I myself happen to own a &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.shootingchrony.com/products_SCMMCM.htm&#34;&gt;Shooting Chrony Beta Master&lt;/a&gt;. These are pretty well made devices, and Shooting Chrony has a no nonsense replacement policy.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The only way to interact with the device is via a proprietary &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.shootingchrony.com/products_ibmpcinterface.htm&#34;&gt;9-pin-female RS-232 cable&lt;/a&gt;, like an old modem. Now, this techique was all the rage circa 1994 when dial-up internet was king and everybody had PC&amp;rsquo;s with two or more serial ports. This is really sub-par when you want to try and connect your smartphone to a Shooting Chrony (yes, this is possible, but more on this later).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Using Estimotes with Xamarin.Android</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/using-estimotes-with-xamarin-dot-android/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Feb 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/using-estimotes-with-xamarin-dot-android/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I recently bought some &lt;a href=&#34;http://estimote.com/&#34;&gt;Estimote&lt;/a&gt; beacons (a 3rd party iBeacon-like device) - largely because they seem like a cool and nerdy kind of thing. It has an &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/Estimote/Android-SDK&#34;&gt;Android SDK&lt;/a&gt; which will allow Android devices to interaction with devices. With a little big of effort, I managed to create &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/topgenorth/Estimotes-Xamarin/&#34;&gt;Xamarin.Android binding&lt;/a&gt; and port the sample Android project provided by the Estimote SDK.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;You can see an example of the app in these screenshots:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://s3.amazonaws.com/opgenorthnet-blog/estimote1.png&#34; alt=&#34;image&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Measuring Distance with Arduino</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/measuring-distance-with-arduino/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/measuring-distance-with-arduino/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.parallax.com/product/28015&#34;&gt;Ping)))&lt;/a&gt; is ultrasonic range finder that is pretty easy to use in an Arduino project. In my case, I&amp;rsquo;m using it to monitor the water level in a sump pump. I have an Arduino Uno R3 (with Ethernet Shield) connected to a Ping))) and a &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.sparkfun.com/products/10988&#34;&gt;TMP36&lt;/a&gt; temperature sensor that is perched above my sump pump. Every 2 minutes the Uno will send out a ping, and figure out the distance to the water below. The TMP36 is used to account for the air temperature in the speed of sound calculations.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Animate a ListView deletion in Xamarin.Android</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/animate-a-listview-deletion-in-xamarin-dot-android/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Sep 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/animate-a-listview-deletion-in-xamarin-dot-android/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A visually pleasant effect when deleting items from a ListView is to animate the row being deleted by gradually change the &lt;code&gt;.Alpha&lt;/code&gt; value of the view from 1.0 to 0.0. If you&amp;rsquo;ve tried to animate the deletion of a row from a &lt;a href=&#34;http://developer.android.com/reference/android/widget/ListView.html&#34;&gt;ListView&lt;/a&gt; in a Xamarin.Android application, you may observe some curious behaviour when rapidly scrolling through a ListView with many rows: the animation may appear on rows other than then one that is being deleted.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sublime Text 2 and Arduino</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/sublime-text-2-and-arduino/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/sublime-text-2-and-arduino/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;re looking to get into Arduino, and you&amp;rsquo;re a programmer, the first thing that will jump out at you is the Arduino IDE. It&amp;rsquo;s best described as &amp;ldquo;spartan&amp;rdquo; (to say the least). As I&amp;rsquo;m used to full featured IDE&amp;rsquo;s I started looking for a replacement to the default Arduino IDE.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;There are extensions to use Visual Studio, but that means me starting up a VM to run Windows which I don&amp;rsquo;t really want to do for Arduino development. There is a another IDE which looks promising called Maria Mole - but it&amp;rsquo;s Windows only so not really a contender for me.  I need something for OS X. I looked at setting up Eclipse as my default IDE, but ran into some issues with that. Nothing to major, but as I don&amp;rsquo;t like Eclipse in the first place I wasn&amp;rsquo;t to motivated to sort things out, so I abandoned Eclipse as an IDE choice.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The next thing I tried was &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.sublimetext.com/&#34;&gt;Sublime Text&lt;/a&gt;. There is an Ardunio plugin called &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/Robot-Will/Stino&#34;&gt;Stino&lt;/a&gt; that turns Sublime into a not bad IDE. In terms of writing your programs, Stino can pretty much do everything the Arduino IDE can do: compile programs, upload them to your Arduino board, import libraries, etc.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Writing GPS information to a JPEG</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/writing-gps-information-to-a-jpeg/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Feb 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/writing-gps-information-to-a-jpeg/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;One of the handy things about the JPEG format is the ability to store meta-data inside the image using &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Exchangeable_image_file_format&#34;&gt;EXIF&lt;/a&gt;. There are a few libraries out there for the various programming languages that can help you out with this, and Android actually has something built in to the SDK - the class &lt;a href=&#34;http://developer.android.com/reference/android/media/ExifInterface.html&#34;&gt;ExifInterface&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Google&amp;rsquo;s documentation on writing latitude and longitude to a JPEG are a bit light on details - they loosely hint at the format that latitude or longitude should have. (See the documentation for &lt;a href=&#34;http://developer.android.com/reference/android/media/ExifInterface.html#TAG_GPS_LATITUDE&#34;&gt;ExifInterface.TAG_GPS_LATITUDE&lt;/a&gt;). The API itself is pretty straight forward, but what Google doesn&amp;rsquo;t tell you is HOW the GPS coordinates should encoded.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>rake your Xamarin.Android Application</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/rake-your-mono-for-android-application/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Feb 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/rake-your-mono-for-android-application/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Deploy early, deploy often is a popular goal in Agile methodologies. One easy way to support this to automate your build process. Last year at this time I would just use &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.finalbuilder.com/finalbuilder.aspx&#34;&gt;FinalBuilder&lt;/a&gt; to automate the builds of my Xamarin.Android pet projects. It doesn&amp;rsquo;t take much to set FinalBuilder, and it does provide support for a lot of tasks such as versioning .NET assemblies, manipulating XML, dealing with the file system, and so on.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The problem is that FinalBuilder is Windows only. OS X and Linux types are left out in the cold. As I find myself working almost exclusive in OS X when developing my Xamarin.Android applications, I was looking for a Windows free way to automate my builds.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Enter &lt;a href=&#34;http://rake.rubyforge.org/&#34;&gt;rake&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://albacorebuild.net/&#34;&gt;albacore&lt;/a&gt;. rake is, of course the build system for Ruby.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Windows 8 64-bit and Android Debug Bridge (Where is my Galaxy Nexus?)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/archives/windows-8-64-bit-and-android-debug-bridge-where-is-my-galaxy-nexus/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Sep 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/archives/windows-8-64-bit-and-android-debug-bridge-where-is-my-galaxy-nexus/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Setting up a new VM for development - this one based on Windows 8 64 bit. Not that I really want to, but it seems that I need to for work (yes, yes, first world problems). So the usual fun with standing up a new VM:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Install OS&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Download Chrome and Firefox and ditch IE&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Download Resharper&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Remember that you need Visual Studio for Resharper so install that.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Install Java SDK&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Install Android SDK&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Install Intellij and Eclipse&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;etc.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Of course, then I notice that my phone, a Galaxy Nexus, isn&amp;rsquo;t being recognized by Android Debug Bridge.  This is a problem as I much prefer to develop using a device as opposed slow emulator that Google ships for Android, and you can&amp;rsquo;t deploy to the device without ADB.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>PreferenceFragment.getPreferencesFromIntent</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/archives/preferencefragment-getpreferencesfromintent/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 May 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/archives/preferencefragment-getpreferencesfromintent/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;One of the new classes that Honeycomb introduced was the &lt;a href=&#34;http://developer.android.com/reference/android/preference/PreferenceFragment.html&#34;&gt;PreferenceFragment&lt;/a&gt;. This class is meant to simplify the creatation of a setting / preferences screen in Android applications. It handles a lot of the displaying, saving, and changing of an application&amp;rsquo;s settings. There are a couple of ways to create a &lt;code&gt;PreferenceFragment&lt;/code&gt;. The simplest way is to subclass, override &lt;code&gt;onCreate()&lt;/code&gt; and then use either &lt;code&gt;getPreferencesFromResource&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;getPreferencesFromIntent&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;There are many examples on how to use &lt;code&gt;getPreferencesFromResource&lt;/code&gt;, but I noticed that there aren&amp;rsquo;t that many on how to use &lt;code&gt;getPreferencesFromIntent&lt;/code&gt;. Here is one such quick example.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Galaxy Nexus - an Update</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/archives/galaxy-nexus-an-update/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 May 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/archives/galaxy-nexus-an-update/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In my last post I flashed a new firmware for the radio on my Galaxy Nexus. I notice that, after a day or so, my problems with connection to Wind Mobile returned. My phone would just not register on Wind&amp;rsquo;s network, regardless of where I was.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Once again I did a bit of search, and read something peculiar (I wish I had booked marked it for reference sake). Some people were claiming that by setting the minimum clock speed of their Galaxy Nexus to 700MHz, that their radio problems had disappeared.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Galaxy Nexus - Why don&#39;t you stay connected?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/archives/galaxy-nexus/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 May 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/archives/galaxy-nexus/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I recently got a Galaxy Nexus, and like a typical geek I &lt;a href=&#34;http://androidforums.com/international-galaxy-nexus-all-things-root/452146-how-root-gsm-hspa-samsung-galaxy-nexus.html&#34;&gt;unlocked the bootloader and then rooted it&lt;/a&gt;. Life was good running Android 4.0.1. Well sort of. I had problems tethering my MacBook Pro via the WiFi hotspot, but no problems using Bluetooth. So nothing I couldn&amp;rsquo;t work around.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Then I received an OTA update to Android 4.0.4 recently.  And this was when things started going not so good - specifically, for some blasted reason, I kept losing connectivity to Wind Mobile&amp;rsquo;s network. At first I thought it was Wind Mobile having issues. This would be odd, because for me, Wind Mobile has been pretty solid. To troubleshoot I pulled my SIM card and dropped it into my Nexus One. Everything worked fine. So apparently something with my phone.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Using AutoCompleteTextView and SimpleCursorAdapter</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/archives/using-autocompletetextview-and-simplecursoradapter-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Sep 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/archives/using-autocompletetextview-and-simplecursoradapter-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I have a simple little pet project (for Android), and one of the things I wanted to do was to to have a text field that would show me previous values as I typed in the text box (see screenshot below). Of course, this control is already a part of the Android SDK - it&#39;s our good friend the &lt;a href=&#34;http://developer.android.com/reference/android/widget/AutoCompleteTextView.html&#34;&gt;AutoCompleteTextView&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://www.opgenorth.net/wp-content/uploads/2011/09/AutoCompleteTextView.png&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;To populate the drop-down, I have an SQLite table called vehicle_descriptions, which looks something like the screenshot below. What I want is for a given vehicle (a value derived from another control on my Activity) to show me the value of the description column in the table.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Slide deck and code from Prairie Developers Conference 2011</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/archives/slide-deck-and-code-from-prairie-developers-conference-2011/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jun 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/archives/slide-deck-and-code-from-prairie-developers-conference-2011/</guid>
      <description>For those wanted the slide-decks and code from my talks at &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.prairiedevcon.com/&#34;&gt;Prairie Developer&#39;s Conference 2011&lt;/a&gt;, you can find them up on &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/topgenorth/PrDC2011&#34;&gt;GitHub&lt;/a&gt;. Thanks to all who attended.&amp;nbsp; Maybe we&#39;ll see you again next year.&lt;br /&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Picking Apart PDF with Ruby and Linux</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/archives/picking-apart-pdf-with-ruby-and-linux/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/archives/picking-apart-pdf-with-ruby-and-linux/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I ran into a curious problem for a side problem of mine where I had some information in PDF files, both text and images.&amp;#160; What I want to do is display the information from the PDF&#39;s on a mobile (Android) device.&amp;#160; PDF isn&#39;t exactly a mobile friendly format, so I got the idea use HTML.&amp;#160; The next trick then becomes how to get the content out of the PDF&#39;s I want into HTML.&amp;#160; Tux to the rescue!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Purging your Privates (MSMQ with Powershell)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/archives/purging-your-privates-msmq-with-powershell/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/archives/purging-your-privates-msmq-with-powershell/</guid>
      <description>A project I’m currently on makes heavy use of MSMQ and private queues.  Every so often, it’s necessary to purge messages from the queue during development. I got tired of always using the MMC snap-in to perform this task, so I whipped up this quick PowerShell script to handle the dirty work for me.  Granted, it’s pretty crude, but it gets the job done.  Any suggestions or improvements, feel free to let me know.&#xA;&#xA;&lt;pre lang=&#34;powershell&#34; line=&#34;1&#34;&gt;&#xA;$queuename = &#34;.\private$\myprivatequeue&#34;&#xA;[Reflection.Assembly]::LoadWithPartialName(&#34;System.Messaging&#34;) | Out-Null &#xA;$queue = New-Object -TypeName &#34;System.Messaging.MessageQueue&#34;&#xA;$queue.Path = $queuename&#xA;$messagecount = $queue.GetAllMessages().Length &#xA;$queue.Purge() &#xA;Write-Host &#34;$queuename has been purged of $messagecount messages.&#34; -ForegroundColor Yellow&#xA;&lt;/pre&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>WIND Mobile and my Nexus One</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/archives/wind-mobile-and-my-nexus-one/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Dec 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/archives/wind-mobile-and-my-nexus-one/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Just recently I switch my mobile carrier from Rogers to &lt;a title=&#34;WIND mobile&#34; href=&#34;../../www.windmobile.ca&#34;&gt;WIND Mobile&lt;/a&gt;. Their &lt;a title=&#34;Holiday Miracle Plan&#34; href=&#34;http://www2.windmobile.ca/en/Pages/unlimitedtalktextdata.aspx&#34;&gt;Holiday Miracle plan&lt;/a&gt; was just to good to pass up - even paying the penalty to break my Rogers contract I will still save money in the long run.&#xA;&#xA;Anyway, once the number got transferred over, I didn&#39;t have a 3G connection, even after selecting the WIND Home APN. &amp;nbsp;After a bit of google, it seems that what I had to do is to setup an APN. &amp;nbsp;In case I can&#39;t find it later, here are the APN settings:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>TFS 2010, VS2010 Database Projects, and CI</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/archives/tfs-2010-vs2010-database-projects-and-ci/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Nov 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/archives/tfs-2010-vs2010-database-projects-and-ci/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I’m currently working on a project where there are some functional tests that require a SQL Server database. Before in the past I’ve always handled this by using Redgate’s excellent SQL Server tools to create a monolithic script that would deploy the DB Schema, and then another set of scripts to set up the data.&amp;#160; Then it’s pretty trivial to use OSQL.EXE to run the scripts and setup the database.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>First Impressions: Windows Phone 7 Development</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/archives/first-impressions-windows-phone-7-development/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Nov 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/archives/first-impressions-windows-phone-7-development/</guid>
      <description>I’ve spent a bit of my spare time in the past week looking at Windows Phone 7 from a developer’s point of view.  I’d have started sooner, but honestly, I didn’t see the point until there were actually devices that I could hold and use.  I know that in the U.S., some guys got developer phones from Microsoft, but I don’t think that anybody up here in Canada was that lucky.&#xA;&#xA;So, over the past year or so I’ve been dabbling with Android and I actually like programming for Android.  The biggest issues I’ve run into with Android are my lack of Java skills – I keep doing things the C# way (you really don’t realize how handy Linq is until you don’t have it) and the fact that Android doesn’t have a decent UI designer.  But otherwise, I like Android.&#xA;&#xA;So, I was curious what the developer experience was for WP7.  In a nutshell – it’s not bad, and in some ways better than that of Android.&#xA;&#xA;Things I like about WP7 development:&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&#x9;&lt;li&gt;Being a C# guy, it was pretty easy and fast for me to get going with WP7.  Of course, Novell now has &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.monodroid.net&#34;&gt;MonoDroid&lt;/a&gt; which in theory should lessen the learning curve for a C# guy to create Android applications.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&#x9;&lt;li&gt;It’s nice to have good tooling to help with creating my UI’s.  Blend and Cider are pretty decent. Android does have &lt;a href=&#34;http://droiddraw.org&#34;&gt;DroidDraw&lt;/a&gt;, but I’ve never really found that tool to be good to work with.  Eclipse has some sort of an GUI designer thingy, but again, I’ve found it to be kind of lack-lustre at best.  That, and I don’t use Eclipse – I prefer IntelliJ.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&#x9;&lt;li&gt;The Emulator seems to start up faster to me that the Android emulator – but that could just be me.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&#x9;&lt;li&gt;The MVVM pattern.  I know the theory, and am now learning the more practical side of it.  Was worried that WP7 was going to decent into the path of darkness and pain that was/is Web Forms.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&#x9;&lt;li&gt;I think that the debugger integrates better with the WP7 emulator.  Not that, generally speaking, I spend a lot of time in the debugger, but when you need it, it does seem to be more natural to me.  Again, this could just be because by day I do a lot of C# development so I’m more used to the Microsoft tooling to begin with.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;Some things I didn’t like about WP7 development:&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&#x9;&lt;li&gt;You have to have Vista or Windows 7.  Yes, I know, XP is almost 10 years old, time to move on.  Call me an O/S curmudgeon.  I don’t mind Windows 7, but Vista sucks/sucked.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&#x9;&lt;li&gt;It seems like to build your apps, you have to use Visual Studio 2010.  Not a problem for a developer, but I’m old school when it comes to compiling applications, and your build server shouldn’t be tainted by your IDE.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&#x9;&lt;li&gt;I’m use to the relatively easy going Google marketplace and the fact I have numerous avenues available to me to distribute Android applications.  No such joy with WP7 apps.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&#x9;&lt;li&gt;Editing XAML by hand.  But, I suppose it’s no worse that the XML resource files that Android uses.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&#x9;&lt;li&gt;Not seeing a lot of projects whose code I can read.  Granted it’s still early, so hopefully that will change.  Or not.  .NET doesn’t seem to have the same OSS community spirit that Java does.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;Microsoft has always tried to be pretty good to developers (sometimes to their own detriment), but I think Windows Phone 7 does have some things going for it, from a developer’s point of view anyway.  Here’s to hoping that strategy pays off – that cool apps will get written for WP7, and that it will be commercially viable.  Competition is good – it will keep Apple and Google on their toes.  &lt;img class=&#34;wlEmoticon wlEmoticon-smile&#34; style=&#34;border-style: none;&#34; src=&#34;http://www.opgenorth.net/wp-content/uploads/2010/11/wlEmoticon-smile.png&#34; alt=&#34;Smile&#34; /&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>YEG Open Data, the 2010 Edmonton Municipal Election, and Android</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/archives/yeg-open-data-the-2010-edmonton-municipal-election-and-android/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Oct 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/archives/yeg-open-data-the-2010-edmonton-municipal-election-and-android/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;(Or, things to do when you have a sick kid)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;&lt;img style=&#34;border-right-width: 0px; display: inline; border-top-width: 0px; border-bottom-width: 0px; margin-left: 0px; border-left-width: 0px; margin-right: 0px&#34; title=&#34;election&#34; border=&#34;0&#34; alt=&#34;election&#34; align=&#34;right&#34; src=&#34;http://www.opgenorth.net/wp-content/uploads/2010/10/election.jpg&#34; width=&#34;126&#34; height=&#34;162&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;One of the new &lt;a href=&#34;http://data.edmonton.ca/&#34;&gt;data catalogues&lt;/a&gt; that the City of Edmonton has put up is the &lt;a href=&#34;http://data.edmonton.ca/DataBrowser/coe/Election2010Results#param=NOFILTER--DataView--Results&#34;&gt;2010 Election Results&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;#160; This Thanksgiving Long Weekend I was kind of “grounded” at home when my son came down with a nasty inner ear infection.&amp;#160; I was hanging out with him, and thought I could use the time to see how hard it would be and how quickly I could put together an Android application that would poll these results and show leading candidate in each contest for a given ward.&amp;#160; Turns out it was not that hard at all.&amp;#160; Development time was less than one day, and then I had the application running on my phone for a couple of days.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Monster</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/archives/monster/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Sep 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/archives/monster/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Life has been a bit busy as of late.&amp;#160; On Sept 4, 2010 a little monster invaded my house.&amp;#160; A savage beast, suitably evolved for our Canadian winters and a fearless hunter of snow-snakes.&amp;#160; Oh, that, and it turns out that she is a distant cousin to my last dog Bailey.&amp;#160; This is my new puppy Casey, who is just shy of 9 weeks old.&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.opgenorth.net/wp-content/uploads/2010/09/P9050049.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img style=&#34;border-bottom: 0px; border-left: 0px; display: block; float: none; margin-left: auto; border-top: 0px; margin-right: auto; border-right: 0px&#34; title=&#34;P9050049&#34; border=&#34;0&#34; alt=&#34;P9050049&#34; src=&#34;http://www.opgenorth.net/wp-content/uploads/2010/09/P9050049_thumb.jpg&#34; width=&#34;436&#34; height=&#34;328&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>New Version of YEG Buildings up</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/archives/new-version-of-yeg-buildings-up/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Aug 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/archives/new-version-of-yeg-buildings-up/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Last night I pushed a new build of &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.androidzoom.com/android_applications/reference/yeg-buildings_icyx.html&#34;&gt;YEG Buildings&lt;/a&gt; out to the Android Market. The two changes with this one:&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;ul&gt;   &lt;li&gt;Rather than showing the latitude/longitude of were you are, the application will try to translate that into a more human-friendly address.&amp;#160; Note that the address might not be 100% accurate.&amp;#160; It depends on how much accuracy the GPS has.&lt;/li&gt;    &lt;li&gt;The application no longer uses Google Maps and a KML feed when show where all the historical buildings in Edmonton are.&amp;#160; The map of Edmonton is now rendered locally, and all &lt;/li&gt; &lt;/ul&gt;  &lt;p&gt;Just for fun, I also &lt;a href=&#34;http://contest.apps4edmonton.ca/apps/21&#34;&gt;submitted YEG Buildings&lt;/a&gt; as part of the &lt;a href=&#34;http://contest.apps4edmonton.ca/&#34;&gt;Apps4Edmonton contest&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;#160; So, feel free to check out the contest page – there are a lot of neat applications there.&amp;#160; Also feel free to vote mine up.&amp;#160; :)&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>New Version of YEG Buildings (formerly Historical Buildings)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/archives/new-version-of-yeg-buildings-formerly-historical-buildings/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Aug 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/archives/new-version-of-yeg-buildings-formerly-historical-buildings/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;After a few months of neglect, I put a new version of my Edmonton Historical Buildings application up on the Android Market.&amp;#160; I’ve renamed it to just &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.androidzoom.com/android_applications/reference/yeg-buildings_icyx.html&#34;&gt;YEG Buildings&lt;/a&gt;, as I’d like to eventually include buildings that aren’t historical, but interesting in general for some reason.&amp;#160; The previous version had a nasty bug that would crash when you tried to view the location of a building on the map.&amp;#160; Was one of those curious things where it worked in the emulator but not on a real device.&amp;#160; I’ve tried it out on my HTC Dream running &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.cyanogenmod.com/&#34;&gt;Cyanogen 6.0 RC3&lt;/a&gt; (this is Android 2.2), and it seemed to work.&amp;#160; &lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Using IntelliJ for Android Development â the Sequel</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/archives/using-intellij-for-android-development-the-sequel/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Aug 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/archives/using-intellij-for-android-development-the-sequel/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A while ago, I posted a blog article about &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.opgenorth.net/2009/06/19/using-intellij-for-android-development-2/&#34;&gt;using IntelliJ for Android development&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;#160; Given that was a year ago, and one version of IntelliJ later, I thought I would do a follow up post.&amp;#160; Long story short (and to sound like a TV commercial):&amp;#160; I liked IntelliJ IDEA 9 so much, I bought a license.&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;Since I blogged last year, the Android plug-in for IntelliJ has really matured.&amp;#160; I guess the only draw back to it is that you only get the Android plug-in when you buy the Unlimited Edition of IntelliJ – it’s not in the Community Edition.&amp;#160; Here are some general comments/thoughts/observations of mine:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Javascript IDE&#39;s</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/archives/javascript-ides/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Aug 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/archives/javascript-ides/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Lately I’ve found myself doing a lot more web application development in JavaScript.&amp;#160; Typically, I always seem to fall back on plain old Notepad++ or Visual Studio.&amp;#160; As a developer, the user experience in either is, IMHO, somewhat lacking. &lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;However, for the past week, I’ve been using &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.jetbrains.com/ruby/index.html&#34;&gt;RubyMine&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;#160; &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.jetbrains.com/ruby/index.html&#34;&gt;RubyMine&lt;/a&gt; is a Ruby on Rails IDE from &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.jetbrains.com&#34;&gt;Jetbrains&lt;/a&gt;, but it seems to work rather well for editing JavaScript and HTML files.&amp;#160; Plus, as an added bonus, it automatically comes with built in support for &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.jquery.com&#34;&gt;jQuery&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Android, MapView, and your Google apiKey: Part 2</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/archives/android-mapview-and-your-google-apikey-part-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Aug 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/archives/android-mapview-and-your-google-apikey-part-2/</guid>
      <description>Just to follow up on my &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.opgenorth.net/2010/04/07/android-mapview-and-your-google-apikey-part-1/&#34;&gt;last post&lt;/a&gt; about embedding Google Maps into your Android application (this part is kind of anti-climatic).&#xA;&#xA;So, by now you’ve signed your application.  This is the “hardest” (i.e. busiest part) of the whole process.  The next part, getting your Goggle apiKey, is the easy part.  First you  need to get the MD5 fingerprint of your keystore:&#xA;&#xA;keytool -list -alias androiddebugkey -keystore &amp;lt;path_to_debug_keystore&amp;gt;.keystore -storepass android -keypass android&#xA;&#xA;Once that is done, you and register for a &lt;a href=&#34;http://code.google. com/android/maps-api-signup.html&#34;&gt;Google Maps API key&lt;/a&gt;.  You need a Google account, and have to agree to some terms of service legal mumbo-jumbo, but it’s pretty simple.  Once you click “Generate API Key”, you will get your key string.  You then simply add the Maps API key to your MapView in your application.  There are a couple of ways to do this, heres how you would do it if you were using the XML layout files:&#xA;&#xA;Of course, after all this is done, the next trick is managing these keys.  You see, when you are working locally, your application is automatically signed using a debug key.  This is fine and dandy for most development.  However, when you deploy your application, you sign the application using your keystore that you created in &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.opgenorth.net/2010/04/07/android-mapview-and-your-google-apikey-part-1/&#34;&gt;Step 1&lt;/a&gt;.  You may have a brief moment of clarity here and realize that the apiKey from your debug keystore and your deployment keystore are different.  I’ve got some ideas on how to deal with that that, but that will be for another day.&#xA;&#xA;&lt;a href=&#34;http://code.google.com/android/add-ons/google-apis/mapkey.html&#34;&gt;Full documentation&lt;/a&gt; for all this can be found on the Android developer’s website.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Induction Into the Android Army â the Aftermath</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/archives/induction-into-the-android-army-the-aftermath/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Jun 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/archives/induction-into-the-android-army-the-aftermath/</guid>
      <description>Thanks to all who attended my “Induction into the Android Army” talk this afternoon at the monthly &lt;a href=&#34;http://groups.google.com/group/ejug&#34;&gt;Edmonton Java User’s Group&lt;/a&gt; meeting.&amp;#160; I’d say it was a good turn out, especially when one considers that this is only the second monthly meeting for EJUG.&amp;#160; It was a pretty basic talk, and didn’t dive to deeply into the “fun” Android stuff.&amp;#160; If anybody from EJUG wants a follow up presentation that’s a bit more in depth, give a shout out on the EJUG mailing list.&amp;#160; If there is enough interest, I’d be happy to put something together.  &lt;p&gt;If you want to &lt;a href=&#34;http://developer.android.com/resources/samples/NotePad/index.html&#34;&gt;browse the code&lt;/a&gt; and don’t want to download the Android SDK, you can do so at the Android website.&amp;#160; Otherwise if you have downloaded the SDK,&amp;#160; you can the samples/Notepad folder.&amp;#160; For those who want the PowerPoint slide deck, please hang tight and I’ll get a link to that shortly.&amp;#160; Basil already has a copy of it, and he’ll probably post it to the Google Group shortly as well.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Android at the Edmonton Java User Group</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/archives/android-at-the-edmonton-java-user-group/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Jun 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/archives/android-at-the-edmonton-java-user-group/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Just a heads up for those interested:&amp;#160; On Tuesday, June 15th the Edmonton Java User’s Group is having it’s monthly meeting at noon at the Canadian Western Bank Building.&amp;#160; The speaker is none other than yours truly.&amp;#160; I’ll be giving a brief introduction to application development to Android, using my trusty G1 and IntelliJ.&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;It’s free to attend, so stop by if you’re so inclined.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Tulips are Lovely this Time of Year</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/archives/the-tulips-are-lovely-this-time-of-year/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 May 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/archives/the-tulips-are-lovely-this-time-of-year/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&amp;#160;&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;You have to love spring time in Alberta.&amp;#160; The tulips have such a contrast against the snow at 21:30 on a Saturday evening:&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.opgenorth.net/wp-content/uploads/2010/05/omvt.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img style=&#34;border-bottom: 0px; border-left: 0px; display: block; float: none; margin-left: auto; border-top: 0px; margin-right: auto; border-right: 0px&#34; title=&#34;omvt&#34; border=&#34;0&#34; alt=&#34;omvt&#34; src=&#34;http://www.opgenorth.net/wp-content/uploads/2010/05/omvt_thumb.jpg&#34; width=&#34;364&#34; height=&#34;484&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Gotta Love JetBrains</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/archives/gotta-love-jetbrains/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 May 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/archives/gotta-love-jetbrains/</guid>
      <description>Gotta love companies that &#34;get it&#34;.  Late last night I was hacking away on some Android stuff using IntelliJ 9.0.2 (on Ubuntu 10.04). For reasons unknown to me, none of my breakpoints seemed to be working.  In fact, IntelliJ just didn&#39;t seem to be working.  I narrowed it down to the breakpoints I was setting - it seemed that every time the breakpoints were being hit.  I managed to narrow it down to this error:&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34; style=&#34;border-collapse: separate; color: #000000; font-family: &#39;Times New Roman&#39;; font-style: normal; font-variant: normal; font-weight: normal; letter-spacing: normal; line-height: normal; orphans: 2; text-indent: 0px; text-transform: none; white-space: normal; widows: 2; word-spacing: 0px; font-size: medium;&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34; style=&#34;border-collapse: collapse; color: #444444; font-family: arial,sans-serif; font-size: 13px;&#34;&gt;[ 166030]  ERROR - lij.debugger.impl.InvokeThread - null&#xA;java.lang.UnsupportedOperationException&#xA;at com.sun.tools.jdi.ReferenceTypeImpl.sourceDebugExtension(ReferenceTypeImpl.java:774)&#xA;at org.jetbrains.plugins.ruby.jruby.debug.JRubyPositionManager.getPath(JRubyPositionManager.java:141)&#xA;at org.jetbrains.plugins.ruby.jruby.debug.JRubyPositionManager.getPsiFileByLocation(JRubyPositionManager.java:156)&#xA;at org.jetbrains.plugins.ruby.jruby.debug.JRubyPositionManager.getSourcePosition(JRubyPositionManager.java:51)&#xA;at com.intellij.debugger.engine.CompoundPositionManager.getSourcePosition(CompoundPositionManager.java:51)&#xA;at com.intellij.debugger.engine.ContextUtil.getSourcePosition(ContextUtil.java:63)&#xA;at com.intellij.debugger.impl.DebuggerSession$MyDebugProcessListener$2.compute(DebuggerSession.java:462)&#xA;at com.intellij.debugger.impl.DebuggerSession$MyDebugProcessListener$2.compute(DebuggerSession.java:460)&#xA;at com.intellij.psi.impl.PsiDocumentManagerImpl$3.run(PsiDocumentManagerImpl.java:298)&#xA;at com.intellij.psi.impl.PsiDocumentManagerImpl$4.run(PsiDocumentManagerImpl.java:321)&#xA;at com.intellij.openapi.application.impl.ApplicationImpl.runReadAction(ApplicationImpl.java:695)&#xA;at com.intellij.psi.impl.PsiDocumentManagerImpl.commitAndRunReadAction(PsiDocumentManagerImpl.java:317)&#xA;at com.intellij.psi.impl.PsiDocumentManagerImpl.commitAndRunReadAction(PsiDocumentManagerImpl.java:296)&#xA;at com.intellij.debugger.impl.DebuggerSession$MyDebugProcessListener.paused(DebuggerSession.java:460)&#xA;at com.intellij.debugger.engine.DebugProcessAdapterImpl.paused(DebugProcessAdapterImpl.java:28)&#xA;at sun.reflect.NativeMethodAccessorImpl.invoke0(Native Method)&#xA;at sun.reflect.NativeMethodAccessorImpl.invoke(NativeMethodAccessorImpl.java:57)&#xA;at sun.reflect.DelegatingMethodAccessorImpl.invoke(DelegatingMethodAccessorImpl.java:43)&#xA;at java.lang.reflect.Method.invoke(Method.java:616)&#xA;at com.intellij.util.EventDispatcher.dispatch(EventDispatcher.java:87)&#xA;at com.intellij.util.EventDispatcher.access$100(EventDispatcher.java:33)&#xA;at com.intellij.util.EventDispatcher$1.invoke(EventDispatcher.java:64)&#xA;at $Proxy84.paused(Unknown Source)&#xA;at com.intellij.debugger.engine.SuspendManagerImpl.notifyPaused(SuspendManagerImpl.java:306)&#xA;at com.intellij.debugger.engine.SuspendManagerImpl.b(SuspendManagerImpl.java:299)&#xA;at com.intellij.debugger.engine.SuspendManagerImpl.voteSuspend(SuspendManagerImpl.java:318)&#xA;at com.intellij.debugger.engine.DebugProcessEvents$1.contextAction(DebugProcessEvents.java:412)&#xA;at com.intellij.debugger.engine.events.SuspendContextCommandImpl.action(SuspendContextCommandImpl.java:62)&#xA;at com.intellij.debugger.engine.events.DebuggerCommandImpl.run(DebuggerCommandImpl.java:44)&#xA;at com.intellij.debugger.engine.DebuggerManagerThreadImpl.processEvent(DebuggerManagerThreadImpl.java:148)&#xA;at com.intellij.debugger.engine.DebuggerManagerThreadImpl.processEvent(DebuggerManagerThreadImpl.java:36)&#xA;at com.intellij.debugger.impl.InvokeThread.run(InvokeThread.java:135)&#xA;at com.intellij.debugger.impl.InvokeThread$WorkerThreadRequest.run(InvokeThread.java:52)&#xA;at com.intellij.openapi.application.impl.ApplicationImpl$5.run(ApplicationImpl.java:329)&#xA;at java.util.concurrent.Executors$RunnableAdapter.call(Executors.java:471)&#xA;at java.util.concurrent.FutureTask$Sync.innerRun(FutureTask.java:334)&#xA;at java.util.concurrent.FutureTask.run(FutureTask.java:166)&#xA;at java.util.concurrent.ThreadPoolExecutor.runWorker(ThreadPoolExecutor.java:1110)&#xA;at java.util.concurrent.ThreadPoolExecutor$Worker.run(ThreadPoolExecutor.java:603)&#xA;at java.lang.Thread.run(Thread.java:636)&#xA;at com.intellij.openapi.application.impl.ApplicationImpl$1$1.run(ApplicationImpl.java:125)&#xA;[ 166036]  ERROR - lij.debugger.impl.InvokeThread - IntelliJ IDEA 9.0.2  Build #IU-95.66&#xA;[ 166036]  ERROR - lij.debugger.impl.InvokeThread - JDK: 1.6.0_18&#xA;[ 166036]  ERROR - lij.debugger.impl.InvokeThread - VM: OpenJDK Server VM&#xA;[ 166036]  ERROR - lij.debugger.impl.InvokeThread - Vendor: Sun Microsystems Inc.&#xA;[ 166036]  ERROR - lij.debugger.impl.InvokeThread - OS: Linux&#xA;[ 166036]  ERROR - lij.debugger.impl.InvokeThread - Last Action: Debug&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;So, the problem to me seemed to be something wonky with IntelliJ.  I e-mailed Jetbrains, explaining the symptoms and the above stack trace.  This morning, I was pleased to find an e-mail from Serge  at Jetbrains.  He suggests disabling the Ruby plug-in that I have installed.&#xA;&#xA;BINGO!&#xA;&#xA;Worked like a charm.  Problem goes away, and in less than 12 hours since I asked for help.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Quick Update to HistoricalBuildings</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/archives/quick-update-to-historicalbuildings/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Apr 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/archives/quick-update-to-historicalbuildings/</guid>
      <description>I just &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.opgenorth.net/misc/HistoricalBuildings.apk&#34;&gt;uploaded an update&lt;/a&gt; to &lt;a href=&#34;http://github.com/topgenorth/historicalbuildings&#34;&gt;HistoricalBuildings&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;nbsp; The list of historical buildings used to be sorted alphabetically, by name.&amp;nbsp; Now they are sorted by the distance from your current location (assuming the GPS can figure that out).&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;zemanta-pixie&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;zemanta-pixie-img&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;http://img.zemanta.com/pixy.gif?x-id=fd558971-287a-8b68-8a02-ced06dd1630f&#34; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>YEG OpenData and their Historical Buildings on your Android phone</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/archives/historical-buildings/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Apr 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/archives/historical-buildings/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.opgenorth.net/wp-content/uploads/2010/04/worksonmymachinestarburst.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img style=&#34;border-bottom: 0px; border-left: 0px; margin: 0px 10px 0px 0px; display: inline; border-top: 0px; border-right: 0px&#34; title=&#34;works-on-my-machine-starburst&#34; border=&#34;0&#34; alt=&#34;works-on-my-machine-starburst&#34; align=&#34;left&#34; src=&#34;http://www.opgenorth.net/wp-content/uploads/2010/04/worksonmymachinestarburst_thumb.jpg&#34; width=&#34;154&#34; height=&#34;149&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Well, for the brave, criminally insane, curious, or otherwise bored I have a alpha version of Historical Buildings – &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.opgenorth.net/misc/HistoricalBuildings.apk&#34;&gt;download the APK&lt;/a&gt; if you want to try it out.&amp;#160; This is just, at this time, the application just shows a simple list of &lt;a href=&#34;http://data.edmonton.ca/DataBrowser.aspx?Container=coe&amp;amp;EntitySet=HistoricalBuildings&#34;&gt;historical buildings&lt;/a&gt; in Edmonton (according to the &lt;a href=&#34;http://data.edmonton.ca/&#34;&gt;City of Edmonton&#39;s Open Data Catalogue&lt;/a&gt;).&amp;#160; Click on a building, and it will show you on Google Maps where the building is in the city.&amp;#160; The &lt;a href=&#34;http://github.com/topgenorth/historicalbuildings&#34;&gt;code&lt;/a&gt; for this is, in my opinion (and to say the least) - rough.&amp;#160; But it is a start.&amp;#160; Definitely needs some improvement.&amp;#160; Or maybe I just need to change my thinking to more of a Android/Java mindset.&amp;#160; Anyway the usual caveats apply:&amp;#160; use at your own risk / batteries not include / do not eat / void where prohibited by law, etc, etc, etc&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Android, MapView, and your Google apiKey: Part 1</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/archives/android-mapview-and-your-google-apikey-part-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Apr 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/archives/android-mapview-and-your-google-apikey-part-1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.opgenorth.net/wp-content/uploads/2010/04/MapList1.png&#34;&gt;&lt;img style=&#34;display: inline; margin-left: 10px; margin-right: 0px&#34; title=&#34;MapList&#34; border=&#34;0&#34; alt=&#34;MapList&#34; align=&#34;right&#34; src=&#34;http://www.opgenorth.net/wp-content/uploads/2010/04/MapList_thumb1.png&#34; width=&#34;164&#34; height=&#34;244&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;Thanks to the &lt;a href=&#34;http://developer.android.com/guide/tutorials/views/hello-mapview.html&#34;&gt;MapView&lt;/a&gt;, it’s drop dead easy to put Google Maps into your application.&amp;#160; There are lots of posts out there how to do it.&amp;#160; Interestingly (to me anyway), when I did a quick search of the Android developers mailing list, I was surprised to see that a lot of people had the same problem:&amp;#160; basically, when you look at your MapView, you end up with a grid of white squares.&amp;#160; It kind of sucks.&amp;#160; There are a lot of blog posts and articles out there on how to fix this problem, but this one is for me, and to help me remember it.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MVP in C# For 2010</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/archives/mvp-in-c-for-2010/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Apr 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/archives/mvp-in-c-for-2010/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I guess I forgot to mention this:&amp;#160; On April 1, 2010, I received an e-mail from Microsoft that my &lt;a href=&#34;https://mvp.support.microsoft.com/profile=31F1E181-79EC-4497-B792-FA8F83D34936&#34;&gt;MVP in C#&lt;/a&gt; was renewed for the third year.&amp;#160; This makes me a happy, because with Resharper 5 (and therefore Visual Studio 2010) and Windows Mobile 7, I’m hoping that this will be an exciting year for the .NET crowd.&amp;#160; &lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;Well, okay, perhaps I didn’t forget.&amp;#160; Given that it was April 1st when I got the e-mail, I like to give things a few days to settle down.&amp;#160; I am acquainted with some mischievous pranksters who would think it was a funny April Fools joke.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Me, Android, and YEG OpenData</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/archives/me-android-and-yeg-opendata/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Apr 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/archives/me-android-and-yeg-opendata/</guid>
      <description>&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.opgenorth.net/wp-content/uploads/2010/04/YegDataList1.png&#34;&gt;&lt;img style=&#34;display: inline; margin-left: 10px; margin-right: 0px; border: 0px initial initial;&#34; title=&#34;YegDataList&#34; src=&#34;http://www.opgenorth.net/wp-content/uploads/2010/04/YegDataList_thumb1.png&#34; border=&#34;0&#34; alt=&#34;YegDataList&#34; width=&#34;164&#34; height=&#34;244&#34; align=&#34;right&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Not that long ago, the City of Edmonton announced it&#39;s &lt;a href=&#34;http://data.edmonton.ca/&#34;&gt;Open Data Catalogue&lt;/a&gt;.  I noticed that one of the data catalogues was a list of &lt;a href=&#34;http://data.edmonton.ca/DataBrowser.aspx?Container=coe&amp;amp;EntitySet=HistoricalBuildings&#34;&gt;historical buildings&lt;/a&gt; in the city.  Yeah, I know that some people in other cities might consider this a pretty weak list.  I mean, the oldest building in Edmonton isn’t even 150 years old.  I’d wager that some parts of the world consider 150 year old buildings to be “new construction”.  Anyway, as I&#39;ve been dabbling with &lt;a href=&#34;http://developer.android.com&#34;&gt;Android&lt;/a&gt; now for about the past year, I thought a handy little project to try out would be to write an app for Android that would show me where the historical buildings are in the city.&#xA;&#xA;I&#39;ve got the foundation of a simple application started over a GitHub called, not surprisingly, &lt;a href=&#34;http://github.com/topgenorth/historicalbuildings&#34;&gt;Historical Buildings&lt;/a&gt; (if you pull the source code, then just a heads up that I use &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.jetbrains.com/idea/&#34;&gt;IntelliJ&lt;/a&gt; for my Android development).  This application currently works in the emulator, my next step is to installing it on my phone and trying it out for real.  Right now all the application does is present you with a list of buildings.  You click on one, and you&#39;ll see on Google Maps where the building.&#xA;&#xA;Some other ideas for features that may or may not happen:&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&#x9;&lt;li&gt;Figure out the whole unit testing story in Android.  Then setup a build script.  Then a build server.  CI rocks, but as I’m trying to learn the Android framework and figure out what all the parts are, I’m not to focused on that at the moment.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&#x9;&lt;li&gt;Don’t always fetch the data – store it locally&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&#x9;&lt;li&gt;I don’t think the way I’m parsing the JSON result is very efficient or “proper”, but it does get the job done.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&#x9;&lt;li&gt;Notify the user when they are within a certain distance of a historical building.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&#x9;&lt;li&gt;Currently YEG has a PDF explaining the significance of the building.  Not very friendly/convenient for mobile devices.  Need something better.&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&#x9;&lt;li&gt;One thought would be to create Wikipedia entries and link to that.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&#x9;&lt;li&gt;Another thought is to petition the City of Edmonton to convert their PDF’s to a more neutral format (HTML anyone)?&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&#x9;&lt;li&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.epl.ca&#34;&gt;Edmonton Public Library&lt;/a&gt; has some information about the “&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.epl.ca/EPLPhotoBuildings.cfm&#34;&gt;Lost Building of Edmonton&lt;/a&gt;”.  Maybe incorporate that somehow – perhaps showing what buildings used to exist at a given address?&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&#x9;&lt;li&gt;Perhaps allow the user to update their coordinates for YEG’s historical buildings.  I’ve notice (on the emulator) that sometimes the lat/long isn’t exactly accurate.  If you look at the image below for the old Arlington Apartments, you notice that the marker should be over the pile of rubble slightly to the left of where it currently is.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&#x9;&lt;li&gt;Maybe include buildings that aren’t necessarily designated as historical, but are interesting architecturally or otherwise.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&#x9;&lt;li&gt;Instead of using YEG OpenData, perhaps an independent cloud based data store (&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.microsoft.com/windowsazure/&#34;&gt;Azure&lt;/a&gt; maybe?)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;If you’ve got any other suggestions, I’m happy to hear them.&#xA;&#xA;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.opgenorth.net/wp-content/uploads/2010/04/MapList.png&#34;&gt;&lt;img style=&#34;display: block; float: none; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; border: 0px;&#34; title=&#34;MapList&#34; src=&#34;http://www.opgenorth.net/wp-content/uploads/2010/04/MapList_thumb.png&#34; border=&#34;0&#34; alt=&#34;MapList&#34; width=&#34;219&#34; height=&#34;326&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&lt;div class=&#34;zemanta-pixie&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;zemanta-pixie-img&#34; src=&#34;http://img.zemanta.com/pixy.gif?x-id=e1a8a615-56c6-883e-b52b-35084586f039&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Where Did the Time Go?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/archives/where-did-the-time-go/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Jan 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/archives/where-did-the-time-go/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.opgenorth.net/wp-content/uploads/2010/01/tumbleweed1.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img title=&#34;tumbleweed&#34; style=&#34;border-right: 0px; border-top: 0px; display: inline; margin-left: 0px; border-left: 0px; margin-right: 0px; border-bottom: 0px&#34; height=&#34;75&#34; alt=&#34;tumbleweed&#34; src=&#34;http://www.opgenorth.net/wp-content/uploads/2010/01/tumbleweed_thumb1.jpg&#34; width=&#34;90&#34; align=&#34;left&#34; border=&#34;0&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Yeah, I’ve been kind of quiet as of late.&amp;#160; So quiet, I suspect that some people might be wondering if something happened.&amp;#160; I was a bit surprised to see that the last time I had blogged was after TechDays in Calgary.&amp;#160; Well, nothing significant has happened - just a bit of laziness augmented by a touch of tech-burnout compounded by the odd bit of single malt scotch.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Followup: TechDays 2009 in Calgary</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/archives/techdays-2009-in-calgary-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Nov 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/archives/techdays-2009-in-calgary-2/</guid>
      <description>Yesterday I was at TechDays 2009 in Calgary for the day (well, the morning really).  I wasn&#39;t there as an attendee, but as a speaker.  Thanks to everybody who came out to my two talks, the first one on an &lt;em&gt;Introduction to ASP.NET MVC&lt;/em&gt; and the second one on &lt;em&gt;SOLIDifying your ASP.NET MVC Application&lt;/em&gt;.  There were a few hiccups along the way:  as usual, I fell victim to the Technical Presentation Time Dilation Syndrome (i.e. ran out of time) on both talks.  I guess I&#39;m just to long-winded for my own good.  As well, because I was running a &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.jetbrains.net/confluence/display/ReSharper/ReSharper+Early+Access+Program&#34;&gt;EAP of Resharper 5&lt;/a&gt;, I had some Visual Studio 2008 issues - namely VS2008 would hang on me from time to time.  Note to self: maybe don&#39;t use the bleeding edge tools in a talk.  And I really should break myself of wanting to type all the code - using snippets would really save me time.&#xA;&#xA;Two things that suprised me:&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&#x9;&lt;li&gt;That there was still that much interest in ASP.NET MVC intro talks.  I just figured that everybody knew/knows about it.  Or maybe I just spend to much time with guys who have drunk the ASP.NET MVC Flavor Aid.  Either way, I think that there were some in the crowd that will convert from WebForms to ASP.NET MVC.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&#x9;&lt;li&gt;I asked how many people wrote unit tests or developing their software using Test Driven Development was the number of people who didn&#39;t raise their hands.  While I didn&#39;t expect the majority of the crowd, I did expect a lot more people than I saw.  Maybe it was a quiet crowd, and people didn&#39;t feel like saying they wrote unit tests.  Maybe I live in a bubble, and my perception of what is actually going on in the .NET world is skewed (that is to say, perhaps writing tests is the exception rather than the rule).  It did kind of make me a bit concerned, as I truly believe that TDD does help one write better software overall.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;Anyway, here&#39;s to hoping that TechDays 2010 will stop off in Edmonton.  And hopefully have a track that will focus on developer fundamentals, like TechDays had in Toronto and Vancouver.&#xA;&lt;div class=&#34;zemanta-pixie&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;zemanta-pixie-img&#34; src=&#34;http://img.zemanta.com/pixy.gif?x-id=2eb31f71-f855-83ff-bf64-795e87c1b4f0&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Compiling ASP.NET MVC on Mono 2.4.3</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/archives/compiling-asp-net-mvc-on-mono-2-4-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Nov 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/archives/compiling-asp-net-mvc-on-mono-2-4-3/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Out of intellectual curiosity, I sparked up &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.monodevelop.com&#34;&gt;MonoDevelop&lt;/a&gt; and decided to see what would happen when I tried to compile the &lt;a href=&#34;http://aspnet.codeplex.com/Release/ProjectReleases.aspx?ReleaseId=24471&#34;&gt;ASP.NET MVC source code&lt;/a&gt;. I figured that it would Just Work.&amp;#160; After all, I can use the .NET compiled assembly with no problems on &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.go-mono.com&#34;&gt;Mono&lt;/a&gt;, so there really shouldn&#39;t be any problems trying to compile the code.&amp;#160; Bad news is that there is one minor glitch.&amp;#160; Good news is the glitch is easy to work around and has already been fixed so it shouldn&#39;t be a problem for future version of Mono. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Sad Day in Whoville</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/archives/a-sad-day-in-whoville/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Nov 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/archives/a-sad-day-in-whoville/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Well, today was a rather sad around the household.&amp;#160; This morning I had to take &lt;a href=&#34;http://picasaweb.google.ca/opgenorth/Bailey&#34;&gt;Bailey&lt;/a&gt;, my dog, to the vet to be put down.&amp;#160; She had just turned 14 years old in September of this year, and age had finally caught up with her.&amp;#160; Her hips were going and we were getting concerned that one day she would be stuck on the floor and wouldn&#39;t be able to walk anymore.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>TechDays 2009 In Calgary</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/archives/techdays-2009-in-calgary/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Nov 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/archives/techdays-2009-in-calgary/</guid>
      <description>Just a heads up that &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.microsoft.com/canada/techdays/default.aspx&#34;&gt;TechDays Canada 2009&lt;/a&gt; is happening in Calgary next week on November 17 and 18.  Yours truly will be there for the whole morning of November 18th talking about ASP.NET MVC and SOLID (note that this is &lt;strong&gt;not&lt;/strong&gt; the same SOLID talk from the DevFundamentals track at TechDays Vancouver and TechDays Toronto).  If you happen to be there, don&#39;t be afraid to come on by and say hello.&#xA;&lt;div class=&#34;zemanta-pixie&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;zemanta-pixie-img&#34; src=&#34;http://img.zemanta.com/pixy.gif?x-id=398917f8-5ef2-8681-9044-b9ab8d709d26&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ubuntu 9.04 &amp; Microsoft Notebook Mouse 5000</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/archives/ubuntu-9-04-microsoft-notebook-mouse-5000/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Nov 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/archives/ubuntu-9-04-microsoft-notebook-mouse-5000/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A while ago I picked up a &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.microsoft.com/hardware/mouseandkeyboard/productdetails.aspx?pid=099&#34;&gt;Microsoft Notebook Mouse 5000&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;#160; Finally decided to use it on my laptop.&amp;#160; I figured that having a bluetooth mouse would mean that I wouldn’t have a USB receiver hanging off my laptop all the time.&amp;#160; Plus, I thought it would be nice to use &lt;a href=&#34;http://blueproximity.sourceforge.net&#34;&gt;Blue Proximity&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;Now, the hiccup came when setting up the new mouse on Ubuntu 9.04 64-bit.&amp;#160; It seems that you have to do a little bit extra to get the mouse working. I found the solution on the &lt;a href=&#34;http://ubuntuforums.org/showpost.php?p=7374310&amp;amp;postcount=8&#34;&gt;Ubuntu forums&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;#160; For my one selfish purposes, I will repeat the instructions here:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Git Resources</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/archives/git-resources/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/archives/git-resources/</guid>
      <description>At the end of my talk on &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.git-scm.org&#34;&gt;Git&lt;/a&gt; at the Edmonton Code Camp, somebody asked if I would put the links to the various git resources up on my website.  Here they are:&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&#x9;&lt;li&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;http://git-scm.org&#34;&gt;git website&lt;/a&gt;, of course.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&#x9;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://progit.org&#34;&gt;Pro GIT&lt;/a&gt; - an awesome book about git.  You can either order the dead tree version, or read it online.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&#x9;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=4XpnKHJAok8&#34;&gt;Linus Torvalds talking about git&lt;/a&gt;.  If you&#39;re an SVN fan-boy, or have thin skin, you might want to skip this.  &#34;...you are ugly and stupid...&#34;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&#x9;&lt;li&gt;A fellow by the name of &lt;a href=&#34;http://excess.org/article/2008/07/ogre-git-tutorial/&#34;&gt;Bart Trojanowksi gave an awesome talk&lt;/a&gt; to some Ottawa ruby group.  This is long, but worth it.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&#x9;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.lostechies.com/blogs/jason_meridth/default.aspx&#34;&gt;Jason Meredith&lt;/a&gt;, of Los Techies fame, has a three part series on &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.lostechies.com/blogs/jason_meridth/archive/2009/06/01/git-for-windows-developers-git-series-part-1.aspx&#34;&gt;git for the Windows Developer&lt;/a&gt;.  Jason has some other good git stuff on his blog too.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;There you go, enjoy, and be distributed.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>So, what do you need to do to be considered Agile?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/archives/so-what-do-you-need-to-do-to-be-considered-agile/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Sep 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/archives/so-what-do-you-need-to-do-to-be-considered-agile/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;One question that has been bouncing around in my mind is what, exactly, does one have to do to be considered Agile?&amp;#160; Let’s look at the &lt;a href=&#34;http://agilemanifesto.org/&#34;&gt;Agile Manifesto&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;blockquote&gt;   &lt;p&gt;Individuals and interactions over processes and tools      &lt;br /&gt;Working software over comprehensive documentation       &lt;br /&gt;Customer collaboration over contract negotiation       &lt;br /&gt;Responding to change over following a plan&lt;/p&gt;    &lt;p&gt;That is, while there is value in the items on      &lt;br /&gt;the right, we value the items on the left more. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Getting Starting with my ADP1</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/archives/getting-starting-with-my-adp1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Sep 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/archives/getting-starting-with-my-adp1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;After a bit of tinkering, I managed to provision my ADP1 setup without a SIM card.&amp;#160; A bit of google, and here is what I did&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;ol&gt;   &lt;li&gt;Download the Android SDK.&amp;#160; In my case, I unzipped it to C:\android-sdk-windows-1.1_r1. &lt;/li&gt;    &lt;li&gt;Connection the phone via the USB cable to my computer.&amp;#160; When the phone asks for a device. &lt;/li&gt;    &lt;li&gt;You’ll get the new hardware dialog, when prompted for the drivers, you’ll need to specify the location.&amp;#160; The Android SDK has the drivers, in my case they were at C:\android-sdk-windows-1.1_r1\usb_driver\x86. &lt;/li&gt;    &lt;li&gt;Once you have the drivers installed cd to c:\android-sdk-windows-1.1_r1\tools. &lt;/li&gt;    &lt;li&gt;Type adb devices.&amp;#160; This should list all the Android devices that you have connected.&amp;#160; If you don’t see any devices listed, then you have a problem. &lt;/li&gt;    &lt;li&gt;Type adb shell.&amp;#160; This will direct your commands to your ADP1 &lt;/li&gt;    &lt;li&gt;Now while at the adb shell, su to root, then :&amp;#160; &lt;/li&gt;    &lt;li&gt;cd /data/data/com.android/providers.settings/databases/ &lt;/li&gt;    &lt;li&gt;sqlite3 settings.db &lt;/li&gt;    &lt;li&gt;INSERT INTO system (name, value) VALUES (‘device_provisioned’, 1); &lt;/li&gt;    &lt;li&gt;.quit &lt;/li&gt;    &lt;li&gt;Reboot the phone &lt;/li&gt;    &lt;li&gt;adb shell &lt;/li&gt;    &lt;li&gt;am start –a android.intent.action.MAIN –n com.android.settings/.Settings &lt;/li&gt; &lt;/ol&gt;  &lt;p&gt;Once all that is done, you should be enable to use your ADP1 as if you had a SIM card in it (we’ll except for the phoning part).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Good Bug Reports and Tracking</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/archives/good-bug-reports-and-tracking/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/archives/good-bug-reports-and-tracking/</guid>
      <description>Every developer, no matter how experienced, has to dig in and fix bugs.  This is, in my experience, the typical cycle:&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&#x9;&lt;li&gt;bug is reported&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&#x9;&lt;li&gt;bug is assigned to developer&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&#x9;&lt;li&gt;developer thinks the bug is fixed&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&#x9;&lt;li&gt;developer marks bug as resolved&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&#x9;&lt;li&gt;tester checks to see bug is fixed, but it isn’t.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&#x9;&lt;li&gt;tester reopens bug, assigns it back to developer&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&#x9;&lt;li&gt;back to step number two.  Repeat until developer (or tester) climbs to the top of a 307 foot administrative building with high-powered rifles to demonstrate USMC-worthy marksmanship.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;Now, even if you aren’t into the whole Lean Software development philosophy (i.e. eliminating waste), you can probably appreciate that it can be pretty wasteful of time and patience every time that #6 happens, so please indulge me as I elaborate on some of the finer points of bug reporting.  Now, where I say “bug reporter”, I typically mean somebody who is in a QA role – their job is to find bugs and report them.  This doesn’t always have to be the case though.&#xA;&#xA;If you check out most open source projects, you will often find rules/guidelines for reporting bugs.  In the case that doesn’t exist then perhaps the following might be of use: When you log a bug, be explicit, and give lots of details.  Don’t be lazy.  If it’s hard to duplicate your bug, then odds are it either won’t get looked at, or won’t be fixed properly.  And when it doesn’t get fixed properly, there will be a lot of churn.&#xA;&#xA;At the very least, when reporting a bug you should provide:&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&#x9;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A detailed description of the &lt;em&gt;problem&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;.  Note the emphasis on problem.  Odds are you don’t have the solution, so don’t bother.  Let the programmer figure out the solution.  For example:  Using version 3.1415 of the application on 28-July-2009, I was expected a date to be calculated a certain way based on some values.  The application didn’t crash, but the correct date was not calculated.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&#x9;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What you expect to happen&lt;/strong&gt;.  If you have some sort of formal spec, repeat it here, and cite how to find the spec.  i.e.  According to Page 1054, in section 1095.4.3.2 the new date is to be calculated as follows :  add the value of  &lt;em&gt;((a - b)- 10) &lt;/em&gt;/2 (rounding down) to the date &lt;em&gt;Y&lt;/em&gt; for a new date of &lt;em&gt;Z&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&#x9;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What actually happened&lt;/strong&gt;.  i.e.  Using these values a=300, b= 150 and Y of 1-Sep-2009 I expected that the new date Z should be 2-Oct-2009&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&#x9;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A step-by-step description&lt;/strong&gt; of HOW to duplicate the bug.  This means explaining in excruciating detail HOW the programmer can duplicate what your reporting, i.e.&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&#x9;&lt;li&gt;Go to the URL &lt;a href=&#34;http://myproblem.com/is/here&#34;&gt;http://myproblem.com/is/here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&#x9;&lt;li&gt;Click on the text box next to the label “Value A:” and enter a value of 300&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&#x9;&lt;li&gt;From the drop down list by “Value B:” and click the value 150 from the drop down list&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&#x9;&lt;li&gt;Use the tab key to navigate to the “Calculate new date” button.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&#x9;&lt;li&gt;Hit Enter&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&#x9;&lt;li&gt;The text box by the “New Date:” label now has the date of 4-July-1943.  I expected 2-Oct-2009.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&#x9;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How the developer can get a hold of you&lt;/strong&gt;.  This comes in handy when for some reason the developer can’t duplicate your bug or doesn’t understand what you were doing.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;When the developer flags the bug as resolved and it turns out not to be fixed, don’t just re-open the bug with curt “This is still broken”.&#xA;&#xA;Ah, but now aren’t I the smug developer – shifting my inability to quickly resolve a bug to the poor reporting capabilities of my tester.  I’m pretty ungrateful too.  I mean, somebody took the time to test out my application, and then enter a bug like “I tried to calculate the new date and it didn’t work.  Please fix”.  Well, fear not – there is a lot developers should be doing as well, but that is the subject of a later post.&#xA;&#xA;Of course, the key part in all of this is &lt;strong&gt;COMMUNICATION&lt;/strong&gt;.  Don’t be afraid, as someone reporting a bug, to actually talk to the developer.  Nothing really beats face-to-face communication (or a phone call) if things seem unclear. Odds are you won’t have an empty whisky bottle thrown at you.  Most likely the personal grooming standards of the developer will be higher than that of a middle age serf during the Black Plague.  In theory, as a tester, you’re on the same side as the developer trying to fix the bug.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Edmonton Code Camp: What Do You Want?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/archives/edmonton-code-camp-what-do-you-want/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Aug 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/archives/edmonton-code-camp-what-do-you-want/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Well, it’s coming up on fall, which is traditionally the time of year for the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.edmontoncodecamp.com&#34;&gt;Edmonton Code Camp&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;#160; It seems that there is still a spot or two left for speakers, so if you’re in Edmonton why not think of something programmy and give a talk.&amp;#160; Doesn’t have to be .NET – anything that is related to software development will do.&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;Anyway, I’ve put my name down for a talk at ECC.&amp;#160; There are several options available for me and I’m not sure which one to go with.&amp;#160; So, I figured that perhaps a straw poll would help me decide.&amp;#160; Feel free to add a comment about which topic you’d prefer:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Using IntelliJ for Android Development</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/archives/using-intellij-for-android-development-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Jun 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/archives/using-intellij-for-android-development-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;(Note:&amp;#160; this article is pretty dated, and used IntelliJ 8.&amp;#160; I plan a follow-up covering IntelliJ 9)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;So I have this semi-fancy Google &lt;a href=&#34;http://developer.android.com/guide/developing/device.html&#34;&gt;Android Dev Phone 1&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;#160; Lately I&#39;ve been devoting part of my spare time to learning about programming for &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.android.com/&#34;&gt;Android&lt;/a&gt; (the OS of the phone).&amp;#160; Google (probably because they didn&#39;t ask for my opinion and/or input) decided to use Java as the lingua franca for Android programming.&amp;#160; If you ask me - and I know you will - they should have used C# and Mono (I might be a bit biased here).&amp;#160; Luckily, years ago I had done Java programming, so I wasn&#39;t that intimidated by the use of Java on Android.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>NAS-less in the North</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/archives/nas-less-in-the-north/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/archives/nas-less-in-the-north/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Over the Easter long weekend, I experience my own resurrection of sorts.&amp;#160; On Thursday just before Easter I noticed that my NAS, a Thecus N3200 Pro with three Seagate Barracuda 7200.11 drives in a RAID5 array, was beeping and displaying a “RAID degraded” message.&amp;#160; I didn’t worry about it to much, as it was late on Thursday, and I figured I was safe/okay with three drives in a RAID5 array.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Getting Started Coding for my Android Dev Phone 1</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/archives/getting-started-coding-for-my-android-dev-phone-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Mar 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/archives/getting-started-coding-for-my-android-dev-phone-1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Figured I was due to spend some time setting up a Linux VM and learning how to program my Android Dev Phone 1.&amp;#160; &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.eclipse.org&#34;&gt;Eclipse&lt;/a&gt; is what is recommended, so I thought I’d give that a try first.&amp;#160; So, with the help of &lt;a href=&#34;www.susestudio.com&#34;&gt;Suse Studio&lt;/a&gt;, I quick built myself a VM with Java 1.6 (&lt;em&gt;Aside:&amp;#160; I love Suse Studio, I can provision a VM in minutes&lt;/em&gt;).&amp;#160; I figured it would be pretty straight forward.&amp;#160; The docs on the Android Developer site for &lt;a href=&#34;http://developer.android.com/guide/developing/tools/adt.html#installingplugin&#34;&gt;installing ADT plug-in&lt;/a&gt; seem pretty straight forward and simple, and I remember Eclipse having a very rich ecosystem of plug-ins that were easy to install (something I wish Visual Studio had – hint, hint Microsoft).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Common Service Locator</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/archives/common-service-locator/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Mar 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/archives/common-service-locator/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;One of the nice things about &lt;a href=&#34;http://martinfowler.com/articles/injection.html&#34;&gt;Dependency Injection&lt;/a&gt; is that it can really help write a more flexible, modular application.&amp;#160; These days, it seems that there is no shortage of choice in the .NET community when it comes to IoC frameworks:&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;ul&gt;   &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://structuremap.sourceforge.net&#34;&gt;StructureMap&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.castleproject.org/container/index.html&#34;&gt;Castle Windsor&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ninject.org&#34;&gt;Ninject&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://code.google.com/p/autofac/&#34;&gt;Autofac&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.codeplex.com/unity&#34;&gt;Unity&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.springframework.net/&#34;&gt;Spring.NET&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;    &lt;li&gt;And probably others that I’m missing. &lt;/li&gt; &lt;/ul&gt;  &lt;p&gt;Ironically, when you first start using an IoC framework, you might find that in trying to make a loosely-coupled, modular, application you end up shackling yourself to the framework you’re using for IoC. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Getting Started with My ADP1</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/archives/getting-started-with-my-adp1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Mar 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/archives/getting-started-with-my-adp1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;After a bit of tinkering, I managed to provision my ADP1 setup without a SIM card.&amp;#160; A bit of google, and here is what I did:&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;ol&gt;   &lt;li&gt;Download the Android SDK.&amp;#160; In my case, I unzipped it to C:\android-sdk-windows-1.1_r1. &lt;/li&gt;    &lt;li&gt;Connection the phone via the USB cable to my computer.&amp;#160; When the phone asks for a device. &lt;/li&gt;    &lt;li&gt;You&#39;ll get the new hardware dialog, when prompted for the drivers, you&#39;ll need to specify the location.&amp;#160; The Android SDK has the drivers, in my case they were at C:\android-sdk-windows-1.1_r1\usb_driver\x86. &lt;/li&gt;    &lt;li&gt;Once you have the drivers installed cd to c:\android-sdk-windows-1.1_r1\tools. &lt;/li&gt;    &lt;li&gt;Type adb devices.&amp;#160; This should list all the Android devices that you have connected.&amp;#160; If you don&#39;t see any devices listed, then you have a problem. &lt;/li&gt;    &lt;li&gt;Type adb shell.&amp;#160; This will direct your commands to your ADP1 &lt;/li&gt;    &lt;li&gt;Now while at the adb shell, su to root, then :&amp;#160; &lt;/li&gt;    &lt;li&gt;cd /data/data/com.android/providers.settings/databases/ &lt;/li&gt;    &lt;li&gt;sqlite3 settings.db &lt;/li&gt;    &lt;li&gt;INSERT INTO system (name, value) VALUES (&#39;device_provisioned&#39;, 1); &lt;/li&gt;    &lt;li&gt;.quit &lt;/li&gt;    &lt;li&gt;Reboot the phone &lt;/li&gt;    &lt;li&gt;adb shell &lt;/li&gt;    &lt;li&gt;am start -a android.intent.action.MAIN -n com.android.settings/.Settings &lt;/li&gt; &lt;/ol&gt;  &lt;p&gt;Once all that is done, you should be enable to use your ADP1 as if you had a SIM card in it (we&#39;ll except for the phoning part).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Got my Google Dev Phone 1</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/archives/got-my-google-dev-phone-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Mar 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/archives/got-my-google-dev-phone-1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;After an uneventful flight from YEG to PSP, I&#39;m settled in with my family.&amp;#160; After spending some time with beer at the pool, I&#39;m sitting down with my Android Dev Phone 1 that I ordered last week (ship to PSP).&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;First impressions:&amp;#160; it seems like a nice phone, and I like the fact it has a keyboard.&amp;#160; I don&#39;t have a SIM card to help with provisioning the phone, so all I get is this message saying &amp;quot;No SIM in phone&amp;quot; and &amp;quot;Emergency call&amp;quot;.A quick search on Google &lt;a href=&#34;http://android-tricks.blogspot.com/2009/01/using-adp1-without-sim-card.html&#34;&gt;tells me&lt;/a&gt; that how to get around this and use WiFi.&amp;#160; So, that&#39;s my task for tonight. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Every Time you [Ignore] a Test, a Puppy Dies</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/archives/every-time-you-ignore-a-test-a-puppy-dies/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/archives/every-time-you-ignore-a-test-a-puppy-dies/</guid>
      <description>&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.opgenorth.net/wp-content/uploads/2010/03/image001_2.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img style=&#34;display: inline; border: 0px;&#34; title=&#34;image001_2&#34; src=&#34;http://www.opgenorth.net/wp-content/uploads/2010/03/image001_2_thumb.jpg&#34; border=&#34;0&#34; alt=&#34;image001_2&#34; width=&#34;244&#34; height=&#34;174&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&#xA;If you using a unit testing framework such as &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.nunit.org&#34;&gt;NUnit&lt;/a&gt;, you&#39;re no doubt familiar with the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.nunit.org/index.php?p=ignore&amp;amp;r=2.4.8&#34;&gt;[Ignore]&lt;/a&gt; attribute.  (Note:  I haven&#39;t used &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.mbunit.com&#34;&gt;MbUnit&lt;/a&gt; in a while, but I&#39;m pretty sure that all this applies there as well.) For those who aren&#39;t, when you adorn your [Test] with this attribute, then your test runner should pay no heed to this particular [Test].  Instead of going green or red, your test turns up as yellow in your test runner. At first blush, this seems handy - rather than deleting a failing or broken test you can have it [Ignore]d, much like your typical computer geek at a high school dance before the punch get&#39;s spiked. Now you can deal with the wayward test on your own time with the pesky failure cluttering up your CI build (you do have a CI build box set up, right?).&#xA;&#xA;Please bear with me while I submit to you: This isn&#39;t a good idea. This is a bad idea. An ugly idea. The kind of bad, ugly idea than even &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.igloocoder.com&#34;&gt;Belcham&lt;/a&gt;-esque quantities of scotch couldn&#39;t make pretty. Why? Well, the whole point to having a unit test is to &lt;strong&gt;test something&lt;/strong&gt;. If your test is failing, that means something is broken.  You should be addressing the cause of the failure and dealing with the problem now. Covering up the failure with some attribute kind of defeats the purpose of having the unit test in the first place. I mean, really, if you had open, festering lesions on your skin would you just cover them up with a band-aid and pretend nothing was wrong?  Odds are you&#39;d go to a doctor and get that checked out.&#xA;&#xA;Alternately, perhaps the test isn&#39;t valid anymore: your application has changed/evolved and the code that you were testing isn&#39;t around anymore. Then, get rid of the test! Delete it from your test fixtures, and don&#39;t look back.&#xA;&#xA;Granted the world we live in is not black and while.  Sometimes we&#39;re working on things, and we only want tests to run when it is explicitly asked to run.  To handle this scenario, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.nunit.org&#34;&gt;NUnit&lt;/a&gt; provides the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.nunit.org/index.php?p=explicit&amp;amp;r=2.4.8&#34;&gt;[Explicit]&lt;/a&gt; attribute.  This is a kinder, more gentle kind of ignore.  This instructs &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.nunit.org&#34;&gt;NUnit&lt;/a&gt; to only run the test when it is told to run the test.  If you add a comment to the attribute, then it helps those going through the build log understand why the test is being run.  However it is still possible to run the test if desired.&#xA;&lt;pre style=&#34;border: 1px solid #cecece; padding: 5px; overflow: auto; background-color: #fbfbfb; min-height: 40px; width: 650px;&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;pre style=&#34;margin: 0em; background-color: #fbfbfb; width: 100%; font-family: consolas,&#39;Courier New&#39;,courier,monospace; font-size: 12px;&#34;&gt;[Explicit(&#34;&lt;span style=&#34;color: #8b0000;&#34;&gt;This test takes a really really really long time to run so we don&#39;t want to run it in this test suite every time&lt;/span&gt;&#34;)]&#xA;&lt;/pre&gt;&#xA;&lt;pre style=&#34;margin: 0em; background-color: #fbfbfb; width: 100%; font-family: consolas,&#39;Courier New&#39;,courier,monospace; font-size: 12px;&#34;&gt;[Test]&#xA;&lt;/pre&gt;&#xA;&lt;pre style=&#34;margin: 0em; background-color: #fbfbfb; width: 100%; font-family: consolas,&#39;Courier New&#39;,courier,monospace; font-size: 12px;&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color: #0000ff;&#34;&gt;public&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color: #0000ff;&#34;&gt;void&lt;/span&gt; My_very_important_test()&#xA;&lt;/pre&gt;&#xA;&lt;pre style=&#34;margin: 0em; background-color: #fbfbfb; width: 100%; font-family: consolas,&#39;Courier New&#39;,courier,monospace; font-size: 12px;&#34;&gt;{&#xA;&lt;/pre&gt;&#xA;&lt;pre style=&#34;margin: 0em; background-color: #fbfbfb; width: 100%; font-family: consolas,&#39;Courier New&#39;,courier,monospace; font-size: 12px;&#34;&gt;    &lt;span style=&#34;color: #008000;&#34;&gt;// Test valuable things here&lt;/span&gt;&#xA;&lt;/pre&gt;&#xA;&lt;pre style=&#34;margin: 0em; background-color: #fbfbfb; width: 100%; font-family: consolas,&#39;Courier New&#39;,courier,monospace; font-size: 12px;&#34;&gt;}&lt;/pre&gt;&#xA;&lt;/pre&gt;&#xA;I know some people are going to protest my advice. So I will offer up this one last piece.  If you are going to [Ignore] a [Test] then please take advantage of the fact that you can add a comment to the Ignore which will show up when &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.nunit.org&#34;&gt;NUnit&lt;/a&gt; ignores the test:&#xA;&lt;pre style=&#34;border: 1px solid #cecece; padding: 5px; overflow: auto; background-color: #fbfbfb; min-height: 40px; width: 650px;&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;pre style=&#34;margin: 0em; background-color: #fbfbfb; width: 100%; font-family: consolas,&#39;Courier New&#39;,courier,monospace; font-size: 12px;&#34;&gt;[Ignore(&#34;&lt;span style=&#34;color: #8b0000;&#34;&gt;This test is ignored as I wish to incur the wrath of Cthulhu (or his proxy)&lt;/span&gt;&#34;)]&#xA;&lt;/pre&gt;&#xA;&lt;pre style=&#34;margin: 0em; background-color: #fbfbfb; width: 100%; font-family: consolas,&#39;Courier New&#39;,courier,monospace; font-size: 12px;&#34;&gt;[Test]&#xA;&lt;/pre&gt;&#xA;&lt;pre style=&#34;margin: 0em; background-color: #fbfbfb; width: 100%; font-family: consolas,&#39;Courier New&#39;,courier,monospace; font-size: 12px;&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color: #0000ff;&#34;&gt;public&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color: #0000ff;&#34;&gt;void&lt;/span&gt; My_very_important_test()&#xA;&lt;/pre&gt;&#xA;&lt;pre style=&#34;margin: 0em; background-color: #fbfbfb; width: 100%; font-family: consolas,&#39;Courier New&#39;,courier,monospace; font-size: 12px;&#34;&gt;{&#xA;&lt;/pre&gt;&#xA;&lt;pre style=&#34;margin: 0em; background-color: #fbfbfb; width: 100%; font-family: consolas,&#39;Courier New&#39;,courier,monospace; font-size: 12px;&#34;&gt;    &lt;span style=&#34;color: #008000;&#34;&gt;// Test valuable things here.&lt;/span&gt;&#xA;&lt;/pre&gt;&#xA;&lt;pre style=&#34;margin: 0em; background-color: #fbfbfb; width: 100%; font-family: consolas,&#39;Courier New&#39;,courier,monospace; font-size: 12px;&#34;&gt;}&lt;/pre&gt;&#xA;&lt;/pre&gt;&#xA;Now when your CI server runs your unit tests, you will have a nice friendly message that will inform others as to why the test is not running.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Common Sevice Locator</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/archives/common-sevice-locator/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/archives/common-sevice-locator/</guid>
      <description>One of the nice things about &lt;a href=&#34;http://martinfowler.com/articles/injection.html&#34;&gt;Dependency Injection&lt;/a&gt; is that it can really help write a more flexible, modular application.  These days, it seems that there is no shortage of choice in the .NET community when it comes to IoC frameworks:&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&#x9;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://structuremap.sourceforge.net&#34;&gt;StructureMap&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&#x9;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.castleproject.org/container/index.html&#34;&gt;Castle Windsor&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&#x9;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ninject.org&#34;&gt;Ninject&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&#x9;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://code.google.com/p/autofac/&#34;&gt;Autofac&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&#x9;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.codeplex.com/unity&#34;&gt;Unity&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&#x9;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.springframework.net/&#34;&gt;Spring.NET&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&#x9;&lt;li&gt;And probably others that I&#39;m missing.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;Ironically, when you first start using an IoC framework, you might find that in trying to make a loosely-coupled, modular, application you end up shackling yourself to the framework you&#39;re using for IoC.&#xA;&#xA;For example, you start off using your own homegrown IoC framework, and then decide at some point in the future to use a different framework, like say StructureMap.  Going through your codebase to make these changes can be quite the exercise in pain.&#xA;&#xA;There are a couple of ways to isolate yourself from this kind of situation.  I won&#39;t get into all of them but instead will focus on the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.codeplex.com/CommonServiceLocator&#34;&gt;Common Service Locator&lt;/a&gt;. What is Common Service Locator?  Well, allow me to cut and paste some text from the web site:&#xA;&#xA;&#34;&lt;em&gt;The Common Service Locator library contains a shared interface for service location which application and framework developers can reference. The library provides an abstraction over IoC containers and service locators. Using the library allows an application to indirectly access the capabilities without relying on hard references. The hope is that using this library, third-party applications and frameworks can begin to leverage IoC/Service Location without tying themselves down to a specific implementation.&lt;/em&gt;&#34;&#xA;&#xA;Blah blah blah - so what does all that mean?  Well, in my own words, CSL is basically a wrapper around your IoC container which separates how you  initialize/configure your IoC container from how you use it.  This separation allows you to use your IoC container without knowing anything about it.&#xA;&#xA;This separation is achieved by use of adapters for the particular IoC container that you want to use.  These adapters are what do the dirty work of finding the service you need, in their own special way and totally transparent from your application code.  Currently, the Common Service Locator has adapters for &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.codeplex.com/CommonServiceLocator/Wiki/View.aspx?title=StructureMap%20Adapter&amp;amp;referringTitle=Home&#34;&gt;StructureMap&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.codeplex.com/CommonServiceLocator/Wiki/View.aspx?title=Castle%20Windsor%20Adapter&amp;amp;referringTitle=Home&#34;&gt;Castle Windows&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.codeplex.com/CommonServiceLocator/Wiki/View.aspx?title=Unity%20Adapter&amp;amp;referringTitle=Home&#34;&gt;Unity&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.codeplex.com/CommonServiceLocator/Wiki/View.aspx?title=Spring%20.NET%20Adapter&amp;amp;referringTitle=Home&#34;&gt;Spring.NET&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.codeplex.com/CommonServiceLocator/Wiki/View.aspx?title=Autofac%20Adapter&amp;amp;referringTitle=Home&#34;&gt;autofac&lt;/a&gt;.&#xA;&#xA;Now, allow me an example of using the Common Service Locator with StructureMap. There is no special reason as to why StructureMap - it just happens to be what I find myself using these days.&#xA;&#xA;Now, say I use the the following &lt;a href=&#34;http://structuremap.sourceforge.net/RegistryDSL.htm&#34;&gt;registry&lt;/a&gt; to configure StructureMap:&#xA;&lt;pre&gt;   1: public class DefaultStructureMapRegistry: Registry&lt;/pre&gt;&#xA;&lt;pre&gt;   2: {&lt;/pre&gt;&#xA;&lt;pre&gt;   3:     public DefaultStructureMapRegistry()&lt;/pre&gt;&#xA;&lt;pre&gt;   4:     {&lt;/pre&gt;&#xA;&lt;pre&gt;   5:         ForRequestedType&amp;lt;IDb4oConfiguration&amp;gt;()&lt;/pre&gt;&#xA;&lt;pre&gt;   6:             .TheDefaultIsConcreteType&amp;lt;SimpleDb4oConfiguration&amp;gt;();&lt;/pre&gt;&#xA;&lt;pre&gt;   7:     }&lt;/pre&gt;&#xA;&lt;pre&gt;   8: }&lt;/pre&gt;&#xA;In a nutshell this says that every time StructureMap is asked to provided an object of type IDb4oConfiguration, it should instantiate a SimpleDb4oConfiguration object and return that.  So, to get an instance of IDb4oConfiguration with StructureMap, I would do something like this:&#xA;&lt;pre&gt;   1: var db4oConfig = ObjectFactory.GetInstance&amp;lt;IDb4oConfiguration&amp;gt;();&lt;/pre&gt;&#xA;Pretty simple, but it does kind of tightly couples me to StructureMap.  If I need/feel like/am forced at gunpoint to change my IoC container to something that is Not StructureMap, you can bet that there will be much wailing and gnashing of teeth on my part as I hunt through my code to make these changes.&#xA;&#xA;Now enter the Common Service Locator.  First, let&#39;s take a peek at some interfaces for CSL.  First an interface:&#xA;&lt;pre&gt;   1: namespace Microsoft.Practices.ServiceLocation&lt;/pre&gt;&#xA;&lt;pre&gt;   2: {&lt;/pre&gt;&#xA;&lt;pre&gt;   3:     public interface IServiceLocator : IServiceProvider&lt;/pre&gt;&#xA;&lt;pre&gt;   4:     {&lt;/pre&gt;&#xA;&lt;pre&gt;   5:         object GetInstance(Type serviceType);&lt;/pre&gt;&#xA;&lt;pre&gt;   6:         object GetInstance(Type serviceType, string key);&lt;/pre&gt;&#xA;&lt;pre&gt;   7:         IEnumerable&amp;lt;object&amp;gt; GetAllInstances(Type serviceType);&lt;/pre&gt;&#xA;&lt;pre&gt;   8:         TService GetInstance&amp;lt;TService&amp;gt;();&lt;/pre&gt;&#xA;&lt;pre&gt;   9:         TService GetInstance&amp;lt;TService&amp;gt;(string key);&lt;/pre&gt;&#xA;&lt;pre&gt;  10:         IEnumerable&amp;lt;TService&amp;gt; GetAllInstances&amp;lt;TService&amp;gt;();&lt;/pre&gt;&#xA;&lt;pre&gt;  11:     }&lt;/pre&gt;&#xA;&lt;pre&gt;  12: }&lt;/pre&gt;&#xA;The IServiceLocator is an interface that your application will use when it requests something from your IoC container.&#xA;&#xA;Another thing that CSL provides is a static class that your application would use to use a current IServiceLocator to request services.  That static class looks something like:&#xA;&lt;pre&gt;   1: namespace Microsoft.Practices.ServiceLocation&lt;/pre&gt;&#xA;&lt;pre&gt;   2: {&lt;/pre&gt;&#xA;&lt;pre&gt;   3:     public static class ServiceLocator&lt;/pre&gt;&#xA;&lt;pre&gt;   4:     {&lt;/pre&gt;&#xA;&lt;pre&gt;   5:         public static IServiceLocator Current { get; }&lt;/pre&gt;&#xA;&lt;pre&gt;   6:         public static void SetLocatorProvider(ServiceLocatorProvider newProvider) {};&lt;/pre&gt;&#xA;&lt;pre&gt;   7:     }&lt;/pre&gt;&#xA;&lt;pre&gt;   8: }&lt;/pre&gt;&#xA;So, now lets see how we would request the default implementation of the IDb4oConfiguration service using CSL.  First, we would initialize CSL:&#xA;&lt;pre&gt;   1: var registry = new DefaultStructureMapRegistry();&lt;/pre&gt;&#xA;&lt;pre&gt;   2: var container = new global::StructureMap.Container(registry);&lt;/pre&gt;&#xA;&lt;pre&gt;   3: var smServiceLocator = new StructureMapServiceLocator(container);&lt;/pre&gt;&#xA;&lt;pre&gt;   4: ServiceLocator.SetLocatorProvider(() =&amp;gt; smServiceLocator );&lt;/pre&gt;&#xA;What is going on here? Allow me to provide a quick line by line explanation:&#xA;&#xA;Line 1 we instantiate a new StructureMap registry.  We then feed that registry to a StructureMap container in line 2.  With line 3, we see that StructureMap container is then fed to the StructureMapServiceLocator, which is the SM adapter for the Common Service Locator.  Finally, with line 4 we provide a lambda that CSL will use to fulfill future requests for services.&#xA;&#xA;Now when our application wants to get an instance of IDb4oConfiguration it just politely asks CSL:&#xA;&lt;pre&gt;   1: var db4oConfig = ServiceLocator.Current.GetService&amp;lt;IDb4oConfiguration&amp;gt;();&lt;/pre&gt;&#xA;Pretty simple and clean, &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Eh#Canada&#34;&gt;eh&lt;/a&gt;?  Now, when radical group the &lt;em&gt;Foundation for Unity as the Dominate IoC Container&lt;/em&gt; sneaks into your cube and forces you at the point of a nerf gun to switch to Unity, you can do so with minimal disruption to your application. With a properly layered application, it would be as simple as coding a new UnityConfiguration layer and then using that instead of your StructureMapConfiguration layer on application startup.&#xA;&#xA;Now, granted this is pretty trivialized example.  There are other ways to solve this problem, but CSL does seem to take are of the grunt work for you so that you can just get going with things.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>You Can&#39;t Change a &lt;input type=&#34;checkbox&#34; If You&#39;re IE?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/archives/you-cant-change-a-input-typecheckbox-if-youre-ie/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/archives/you-cant-change-a-input-typecheckbox-if-youre-ie/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Update November 20th:&amp;#160; Well, a quick search of &lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.stackoverflow.com&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;StackOverflow.com&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;, and it turns out that I’m not exactly alone in this matter.&amp;#160; According to this &lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://stackoverflow.com/questions/208471/getting-jquery-to-recognise-change-in-ie&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;post&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt; (and Grant in the comments of this post), in versions of IE &amp;lt; 8, one must use the click event, and not the change event.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;I ran into an interesting issue today.&amp;#160; I don&#39;t really know the answer, but I figured I would blog about it so that I don&#39;t completely forget it.&amp;#160; While I highly doubt the two readers of my blog (my brother and sister) have any idea of what I&#39;m talking about, I&#39;m sure that eventually somebody (smart) will stumble upon this via Google.&amp;#160; What will happen in that case is anybodies guess, but I digress...&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Off to Austin</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/archives/off-to-austin/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/archives/off-to-austin/</guid>
      <description>Well, in a scant few hours I&#39;ll be off to Austin, Texas, for &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.KaizenConf.com&#34;&gt;KaizenConf&lt;/a&gt;.  It will be a fun packed couple of day dealing with some very &lt;a href=&#34;http://codebetter.com/blogs/david_laribee/archive/2008/10/27/kaizenconf-workshops-schedule.aspx&#34;&gt;interesting topics&lt;/a&gt;.  In all honestly, I don&#39;t exactly know which of the topics I want to attend - the pretty much all are of interest to me.  Makes me wish I could clone myself.&#xA;&#xA;My plane lands early afternoon, so if you&#39;re kicking around Austin and want to entertain an easily amused Canuck, give me a holler (comments here, or on twitter).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>TypeMock, TestDriven.NET, and Red Tests</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/archives/typemock-testdriven-net-and-red-tests-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Oct 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/archives/typemock-testdriven-net-and-red-tests-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Lately I&#39;ve been experimenting with &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.typemock.com/&#34;&gt;TypeMock Isolator&lt;/a&gt;,&amp;#160; and it&#39;s new AAA syntax.&amp;#160; For the past two years I&#39;ve been a diehard Rhino.Mocks kind of guy, but figured that it&#39;s time to check out other tools.&amp;#160; Anyway, I had a situation where a unit test of mine was failing when I ran it with &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.testdriven.net/&#34;&gt;TestDriven.NET&lt;/a&gt;, but would pass when I ran it using the unit test runner in &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.jetbrains.com/resharper&#34;&gt;Resharper 4.1&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;Usually when I develop, I write individual tests and then run individually with TestDriven.NET and collectively with Resharper.&amp;#160; In this case, as I was writing one unit test, it kept failing with TestDriven.NET.&amp;#160; At first I thought it was just me being stupid (always a good place to start), and then I was worried that perhaps the documentation for TypeMock was to blame.&amp;#160; So, I sent a email to Avi at TypeMock, mostly expecting confirmation of my stupidity. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>TypeMock, TestDriven.NET, and Red Tests</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/archives/typemock-testdriven-net-and-red-tests/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Oct 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/archives/typemock-testdriven-net-and-red-tests/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Lately I&#39;ve been experimenting with &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.typemock.com/&#34;&gt;TypeMock Isolator&lt;/a&gt;,&amp;#160; and it&#39;s new AAA syntax.&amp;#160; For the past two years I&#39;ve been a diehard Rhino.Mocks kind of guy, but figured that it&#39;s time to check out other tools.&amp;#160; Anyway, I had a situation where a unit test of mine was failing when I ran it with &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.testdriven.net/&#34;&gt;TestDriven.NET&lt;/a&gt;, but would pass when I ran it using the unit test runner in &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.jetbrains.com/resharper&#34;&gt;Resharper 4.1&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;Usually when I develop, I write individual tests and then run individually with TestDriven.NET and collectively with Resharper.&amp;#160; In this case, as I was writing one unit test, it kept failing with TestDriven.NET.&amp;#160; At first I thought it was just me being stupid (always a good place to start), and then I was worried that perhaps the documentation for TypeMock was to blame.&amp;#160; So, I sent a email to Avi at TypeMock, mostly expecting confirmation of my stupidity.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Where Windows Beats Linux</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/archives/where-windows-beats-linux/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/archives/where-windows-beats-linux/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Most who know me are aware that, despite being a .NET developer and a Microsoft MVP, I&#39;m a bit of a Linux freak at heart.&amp;#160; I actually prefer Linux to Windows.&amp;#160; Linux has come a long way in the past 18 years, although I&#39;ve only been tinkering with it off and on for the past 9 years or so.&amp;#160; I will admit that perhaps Linux on the desktop isn&#39;t quite there for the average consumer, but for me it.&amp;#160; And, when it comes to servers, there is no question:&amp;#160;&amp;#160; use Linux unless you&#39;ve got a pretty compelling reason to run Windows.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ruminations</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/archives/ruminations/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/archives/ruminations/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Today was my last full time day on this contract.&amp;#160; Tomorrow I start up full-time with another.&amp;#160; Personally, I&#39;ve gotten in the habit of looking a my past contract and conducting my own personal retrospective on what I learned or how I would do things differently.&amp;#160; I figured that because my memory is getting worse in my old age, I&#39;d started putting these things down on my blog.&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;For a greenfield project, don&#39;t use the database someone hands off to you&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Whatâs In A Name?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/archives/whats-in-a-name/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Aug 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/archives/whats-in-a-name/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As I was driving home today, I couldn&#39;t help notice something.&amp;#160; Microsoft&#39;s ASP.NET MVC framework is still in beta, and was only announced last October.&amp;#160; To my knowledge, there are currently three projects in the &lt;a href=&#34;http://maps.google.ca/maps?q=Edmonton,+Alberta&amp;amp;ie=UTF8&amp;amp;oe=utf-8&amp;amp;client=firefox-a&amp;amp;ll=53.540307,-113.510742&amp;amp;spn=18.606218,57.128906&amp;amp;z=5&amp;amp;iwloc=addr&#34;&gt;Edmonton&lt;/a&gt; area based off this framework.&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;Castle Monorail has been around for much longer, three years or so?&amp;#160; It&#39;s still listed as a release candidate on it&#39;s website, but I&#39;d say Monorail is suitable for production.&amp;#160; Currently, I am not aware of any projects in the Edmonton that are based off this framework.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Squawking About The Manning Early Access Program</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/archives/squawking-about-the-manning-early-access-program/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Aug 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/archives/squawking-about-the-manning-early-access-program/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Note:&amp;#160; I originally wrote this post on August 23, 2008.&amp;#160; As things change with the book NHibernate in Action, I will be updating this post and resetting the date.&amp;#160; &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;I&#39;d like to take a break from boring you two readers of my blog about my experience with Linux and VMware, and take a moment to annoy you with a rant.&amp;#160; Diversity is the spice of life after all.&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;This little remonstration of mine is about the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.manning.com/about/meap.html&#34;&gt;Manning Early Access Program&lt;/a&gt; (MEAP).&amp;#160; Well, specifically just&amp;#160; &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.manning.com/kuate/&#34;&gt;one book&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;#160; I&#39;ve got my eye on a couple of other books available with MEAP to see how they pan out before considering the whole &amp;quot;early access&amp;quot; useless.&amp;#160; Anyway...&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unit Testing in JavaScript</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/archives/unit-testing-in-javascript/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Aug 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/archives/unit-testing-in-javascript/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Well, I don&#39;t know why it&#39;s taken me so long to get to get around to this: but I must say that there are now a couple of &amp;quot;must haves&amp;quot; in my web developer&#39;s tool box.&amp;#160; One of them is &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.jquery.com&#34;&gt;jQuery,&lt;/a&gt; and now the other is &lt;a href=&#34;http://docs.jquery.com/QUnit&#34;&gt;QUnit&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.lostechies.com/blogs/chad_myers/default.aspx&#34;&gt;Chad Myers&lt;/a&gt; has a good, quick, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.lostechies.com/blogs/chad_myers/archive/2008/08/28/getting-started-with-jquery-qunit-for-client-side-javascript-testing.aspx&#34;&gt;post introducing QUnit&lt;/a&gt;, I&#39;d &lt;em&gt;strongly suggest&lt;/em&gt; checking it out if you do web development (which, IMHO, implies some use of JavaScript, right?).&amp;#160; Chad&#39;s post covers the basics pretty good, and I think I would just be duplicating/plagiarizing Chad&#39;s work if I were to blog the hour or two I spent getting to know QUnit here.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How Much TDD is Enough?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/archives/how-much-tdd-is-enough/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Aug 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/archives/how-much-tdd-is-enough/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;At the last &lt;a href=&#34;http://groups.google.com/group/eamug&#34;&gt;Edmonton Agile Methods User Group&lt;/a&gt; meeting, we had a brief discussion around &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Code_coverage&#34;&gt;code coverage&lt;/a&gt;, and what should be an acceptable number to shoot for.&amp;#160; Is it okay when the unit tests cover 80% of the code?&amp;#160; Or should 100% be the only acceptable value?&amp;#160; After all, how can you be confident in your code knowing that 20% of it isn&#39;t tested.&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;Allow me to go out on a limb here, and state with absolute certainty that the correct answer is &amp;quot;It depends on your situation&amp;quot;.&amp;#160; Allow me to elaborate.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rod Paddock at EDMUG</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/archives/rod-paddock-at-edmug/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Jun 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/archives/rod-paddock-at-edmug/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Last night (Thursday, June 26th) &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.dashpoint.com/&#34;&gt;Rod Paddock&lt;/a&gt; gave a talk on using &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.silverlight.net&#34;&gt;Silverlight&lt;/a&gt; 2.0 to the Edmonton .NET User Group.&amp;#160; I&#39;d say that Rod did a pretty good job, despite the fact that the beta of both &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.silverlight.net&#34;&gt;Silverlight&lt;/a&gt; and Expression Blend didn&#39;t exactly want to play nice all the time.&amp;#160; It&#39;s definitely perked my interest in the technology, and I can see a lot of business potential for it. &lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;The rich user experience that &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.silverlight.net&#34;&gt;Silverlight&lt;/a&gt; brings to the web-browser, will, I think raise the bar for what web applications will do for businesses.&amp;#160; Forget all the buzz about ASP.NET MVC or MonoRail or ASP.NET 3.5.&amp;#160; This is just another layer of makeup on the tired, old, hooker that is application development in .NET.&amp;#160; &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.silverlight.net&#34;&gt;Silverlight&lt;/a&gt; is what will make business users oh and ah and get excited about web apps again.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Experiment, Days 3 &amp; 4</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/archives/the-experiment-days-3-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Jun 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/archives/the-experiment-days-3-4/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Just a quick recap of days 3 &amp;amp; 4 of running with openSUSE 11 as my primary OS.&amp;#160; By far and large, not a lot of complaints.&amp;#160; As I do most of my work on a laptop, I tend to keep my VM&#39;s on external HDD&#39;s connected via USB2.&amp;#160; I&#39;ve been doing this for a while now, under Windows.&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;I&#39;m not to sure I&#39;m a big fan of how openSUSE mounts (or tries to mount) my external HDD.&amp;#160; It just doesn&#39;t seem as...seamless...as how Windows XP does it.&amp;#160; I&#39;m use to just plugging in my external HDD, and not worrying about it until it&#39;s time to disconnect.&amp;#160; openSUSE seems to get a big confused with automounting, and I always seem to have to help it along.&amp;#160; It&#39;s something I can live with for now. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Experiment Begins</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/archives/the-experiment-begins/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Jun 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/archives/the-experiment-begins/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&#39;ve decided to try a little experiment, and see how things will go, computing-wise, if I minimize my dependence on Windows.&amp;#160; Now, I don&#39;t want to run out and buy a Mac (not yet, anyway), so I&#39;m taking a middle ground.&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;I first repartitioned my hard drive (thanks &lt;a href=&#34;http://gparted.sourceforge.net/&#34;&gt;gparted&lt;/a&gt;), and set aside a 15GB partition.&amp;#160; On this partition, I installed &lt;a href=&#34;http://software.opensuse.org/&#34;&gt;OpenSUSE 11&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;My plan is to run &lt;a href=&#34;http://software.opensuse.org/&#34;&gt;OpenSUSE 11&lt;/a&gt; as the host OS, and then use &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.vmware.com&#34;&gt;VMware&lt;/a&gt; to run VM&#39;s for my work and such.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ASP.NET Web Services and jQuery/AJAX</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/archives/asp-net-web-services-and-jqueryajax/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 May 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/archives/asp-net-web-services-and-jqueryajax/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As far as web developer&#39;s go, I&#39;ll freely admit that my Javascript is not one of my strong points.&amp;#160; I don&#39;t have a real good reason for this, it&#39;s just that over the past few years I haven&#39;t had much call/need to polish and hone my Javascript skills.&amp;#160; Recently I discovered &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.jquery.com&#34;&gt;jQuery&lt;/a&gt;, and I must say that I wish I had know about this library earlier.&amp;#160; The more I use &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.jquery.com&#34;&gt;jQuery&lt;/a&gt;, the more I like it.&amp;#160; The simple things are simple, and the hard things are possible.&amp;#160; Take calling a simple webservice when the user clicks a button on a form.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>On the Functional Apex of Mainstream Build Tools in .NET</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/archives/on-the-functional-apex-of-mainstream-build-tools-in-net/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/archives/on-the-functional-apex-of-mainstream-build-tools-in-net/</guid>
      <description>Wordy title.  To wordy.  Kind of like build files these days.&#xA;&#xA;I remember when I first discovered Ant, and then &lt;a href=&#34;http://nant.sourceforge.net&#34;&gt;Nant&lt;/a&gt;* .  I was pretty happy, as it allow a decent way to compile my Java (and C#) without using make files.  Life was good as I could finally introduce some structure into HOW code was compiled.  The build process was no longer using whatever &#34;build&#34; command the IDE exposed, hoping that I didn&#39;t forget a compiler directive or a file or a reference to some other library along the way.  Other programmers could also compile the code with out fear as well.  Having a tool like Nant is pretty crucial to the whole concept of continuous integration.&#xA;&#xA;Somewhere along the way, though, Nant lost it&#39;s shine.  It isn&#39;t to hard to find these monster Nant scripts with all kinds of crazy things happening inside them.  Trying to work with these files can be a bit of a burden, to say the least.&#xA;&#xA;This takes me back to the title:  it seems to me that build tools like Nant have kind of peaked, functionally speaking.  What does that mean?  We can always add more tasks (created in a real programming language) to do things for us, but in a lot of ways Nant is constrained by the fact that it is just XML.  We can always add tasks to Nant, but somethings just can&#39;t be handled by out of the box, one size fits all tasks from Nant (or &lt;a href=&#34;http://nantcontrib.sourceforge.net&#34;&gt;NantContrib&lt;/a&gt;).  As soon as you run into those things, you need to start writing code.  XML is good for config files (to a point).  It&#39;s bad for programming logic.  It is not at all uncommon to see in build files if statements doing all kinds of things.  We don&#39;t need to (and should not) make XML into another programming language. &#xA;&#xA;I spent a bit of time tonight playing with &lt;a href=&#34;http://code.google.com/p/boo-build-system/&#34;&gt;Bake&lt;/a&gt;.  For those who don&#39;t know, &lt;a href=&#34;http://code.google.com/p/boo-build-system/&#34;&gt;Bake&lt;/a&gt; is to &lt;a href=&#34;http://boo.codehaus.org&#34;&gt;boo&lt;/a&gt; what &lt;a href=&#34;http://rake.rubyforge.org&#34;&gt;Rake&lt;/a&gt; is to &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ruby-lang.org&#34;&gt;ruby&lt;/a&gt;.  Or, in other terms, think of a build system that is actually based on a programming language, and not a configuration file.  Why did I pick Bake?  Well, it&#39;s boo, and I want to learn boo.  Boo is .NET, so I can leverage what I already know.  Plus, I&#39;m reading &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ayende.com&#34;&gt;Ayende&#39;&lt;/a&gt;s book &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.manning.com/rahien/&#34;&gt;Building Domain Specific Languages in Boo&lt;/a&gt;, so Bake just seems to be a natural fit.&#xA;&#xA;So far, I&#39;m liking it.  In the span of a couple hours, I managed to figure out how to create a quick bake script (~ 40 lines of boo) to compile some code.  I&#39;d say that this script more readable (or soluble, to use the words of Scott Bellware) when compared to a Nant script.  Being pretty new, Bake doesn&#39;t have as many tasks as Nant.  However, it does seem pretty easy to create tasks for Bake.  Plus, I have all the expressiveness of a programming language available to me now&#xA;&#xA;I did have one glitch that is worth mentioning:  the task to compile my code was using the &lt;a href=&#34;http://code.google.com/p/boo-build-system/issues/detail?id=3&#34;&gt;CSC.EXE from .NET 2.0&lt;/a&gt;.  This is a problem when you&#39;re working with a .NET 3.5 codebase.  But, no fear, I hacked out a quick fix inside of about 15 minutes, and all is well again.&#xA;&#xA;I imagine that someone soon will blog about using Rake to build your .NET projects.  I eagerly await such a post.  In the meantime, I&#39;m going to continue on with Bake, and see if it will meet my needs.&#xA;&#xA;* &lt;em&gt;NOTE:  I lump MSBuild in with NAnt as MSBuild, IMHO, is a clone of NAnt&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>EDMUG Presentation on MonoRail</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/archives/edmug-presentation-on-monorail/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Apr 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/archives/edmug-presentation-on-monorail/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;On Thursday, April 24, at the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.edmug.net&#34;&gt;Edmonton .NET User&#39;s Group&lt;/a&gt;, I did a presentation on &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.castleproject.org/monorail/index.html&#34;&gt;MonoRail&lt;/a&gt; (and a bit on &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.castleproject.org/container/index.html&#34;&gt;Windsor&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.castleproject.org/activerecord/index.html&#34;&gt;ActiveRecord&lt;/a&gt;).&amp;#160; Thanks to all for coming out hear me talk.&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;I found it to be a pretty hard topic to cover in not quite 120 minutes.&amp;#160; There is just so much to cover and explain.&amp;#160; As well, it seemed that there were a couple in the crowd that felt a bit overloaded.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ALT.NET Session #6: Maintaining A Framework</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/archives/alt-net-session-6-maintaining-a-framework/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Apr 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/archives/alt-net-session-6-maintaining-a-framework/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://codebetter.com/blogs/jeremy.miller/&#34;&gt;Jeremy Miller&lt;/a&gt; talking about the trials and tribulations of keeping a &lt;a href=&#34;http://structuremap.sourceforge.net/Default.htm&#34;&gt;codebase&lt;/a&gt; viable and useful over the past four years.&amp;#160; A lot of tips and explanations were backed with diagrams on the whiteboard.&amp;#160; Kind of hard to blog that stuff, so this will probably be just a collection of bullets.&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;Lessons learned - a lot of them relate back to what are considered good, OO practices:&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;ul&gt;   &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Don&#39;t_repeat_yourself&#34;&gt;DRY&lt;/a&gt;, especially with the very small things.&amp;#160; When Jeremy was adding support for .NET 2.0, the generic support was problematic.&amp;#160;&amp;#160; &lt;br /&gt;Example:&amp;#160; Want to resolve a Repository&amp;lt;T&amp;gt;.&amp;#160; You can&#39;t just look for the class Repository`1: i.e. was trying to resolve the class by using&amp;#160; typeof(Repository`1).&amp;#160; This did not work. &lt;/li&gt;    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://c2.com/cgi/wiki?TellDontAsk&#34;&gt;Tell, Don&#39;t Ask&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;#160; Didn&#39;t follow this to heavily at first, and so now effort has to be taken to rewrite code to adhere to this principle. &lt;/li&gt;    &lt;li&gt;Using a lot of Double Dispatch (&lt;em&gt;hah!&amp;#160; look Jeremy the picture did turn out&lt;/em&gt;):       &lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.opgenorth.net/wp-content/uploads/2010/03/SSPX0289_2.png&#34;&gt;&lt;img style=&#34;border-bottom: 0px; border-left: 0px; display: inline; border-top: 0px; border-right: 0px&#34; title=&#34;SSPX0289_2&#34; border=&#34;0&#34; alt=&#34;SSPX0289_2&#34; src=&#34;http://www.opgenorth.net/wp-content/uploads/2010/03/SSPX0289_2_thumb.png&#34; width=&#34;244&#34; height=&#34;222&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;    &lt;li&gt;If you need to refactor, do it now.&amp;#160; Procrastination only makes it (refactoring) harder and more costly. &lt;/li&gt;    &lt;li&gt;If you want to build a .NET framework and keep it around for four to five years, you should probably learn a bit about the fundamentals of .NET. &lt;/li&gt;    &lt;li&gt;Small steps, frequent commits to source code. &lt;/li&gt;    &lt;li&gt;Good solid battery of unit tests really helps with major changes. &lt;/li&gt;    &lt;li&gt;Moving more towards coarser grained tests.&amp;#160; Does the test check the functionality?&amp;#160; Not to worried about the intermediate steps.      &lt;ul&gt;       &lt;li&gt;Assertions based on side effects really don&#39;t work well.&amp;#160; Not very expressive, sometimes hard to figure out what what you&#39;re trying to test. &lt;/li&gt;     &lt;/ul&gt;   &lt;/li&gt;    &lt;li&gt;It helps have tooling inside your tests in order to help you quickly create tests, especially the difficult to setup/create tests.&amp;#160; Will result in a faster feedback cycle.&amp;#160; This infrastructure is more strategic, can be very help. &lt;/li&gt;    &lt;li&gt;Jeremy recommends &amp;quot;Pragmatic Programmers&amp;quot; &lt;/li&gt; &lt;/ul&gt;  &lt;p&gt;Brief discussion about where to start learning all these pattern.&amp;#160; Advice is given to learn principles first (DRY, OCP, SRP, SOC, etc) as this will greatly help with the understanding and proper use of design patterns.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ALT.NET Session #4: Sprocs Good Or Evil / NHibernate with Cartoon Bears</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/archives/alt-net-session-4-sprocs-good-or-evil-nhibernate-with-cartoon-bears/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Apr 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/archives/alt-net-session-4-sprocs-good-or-evil-nhibernate-with-cartoon-bears/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Two topics merged into one.&amp;#160; Rod Paddock wants to talk about stored procs, and others want to learn how to explain NHibernate to other people who aren&#39;t familiar with it (and minimize the jargon).&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;Rod uses a custom code-gen solution based heavily on sprocs - a data driven approach.&amp;#160; Sounds like it works well for him.&amp;#160; Oren concurs that this technique could be very effective in certain circumstances.&amp;#160; It will have problems with complex situations that deal with convoluted/difficult data scenarios.&amp;#160; He&#39;s giving an example, but I just can&#39;t keep up with him.&amp;#160; The point of Oren&#39;s story is that a domain driven approach will would better when you&#39;re not dealing with data but with data and behavior.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ALT.NET Session #5:  Mono â Not Just For Linux</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/archives/alt-net-session-5-mono-not-just-for-linux/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Apr 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/archives/alt-net-session-5-mono-not-just-for-linux/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Joe starts polling to see what people want to talk about.&amp;#160; Most seem to be interest the libraries for Mono (being that they also work on Windows/.NET.&amp;#160; So, Joe starts talking about libraries for/from Mono. &lt;/p&gt;  &lt;ol&gt;   &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.mono-project.com/Cecil&#34;&gt;Mono.Cecil&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;#160; For all your reflecting and assembly modification needs. &lt;/li&gt;    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.mono-project.com/Mono.Addins&#34;&gt;Mono.Addins&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;#160; I&#39;ve been looking at this off and on today, and I have to admit it looks pretty intriguing &lt;/li&gt;    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.mono-project.com/Rocks&#34;&gt;Mono.Rocks&lt;/a&gt;:&amp;#160; Handy extension methods. &lt;/li&gt;    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.mono-project.com/Mono.Zeroconf&#34;&gt;Mono.Zeroconf&lt;/a&gt;: Zero configuration networking library &lt;/li&gt;    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ndesk.org/DBusSharp&#34;&gt;DBus#&lt;/a&gt;:&amp;#160; A C# implementation of &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.freedesktop.org/wiki/Software/dbus&#34;&gt;D-Bus&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/li&gt;    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.mono-project.com/MonoCurses&#34;&gt;MonoCurses&lt;/a&gt;: An API for console based applications &lt;/li&gt;    &lt;li&gt;GTK# vs Windows:      &lt;ul&gt;       &lt;li&gt;My suggestion is to consider the target environment.&amp;#160; If you targeting Windows, stick with WinForms.&amp;#160; If you&#39;re targetting Linux/Mac, go with GTK#.&amp;#160; &lt;/li&gt;        &lt;li&gt;Another issue that might influence your decision is that the documentation for GTK# is pretty sketchy, not very good. &lt;/li&gt;     &lt;/ul&gt;   &lt;/li&gt;    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.mono-project.com/IOMap&#34;&gt;IOMap&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;#160; Turning this flag on, will help you with some of the cross-platform development issues.&amp;#160; This is a portable library that will help resolve things like directory seperators, case sensitivity in paths, and that sort of thing. &lt;/li&gt; &lt;/ol&gt;  &lt;p&gt;A short session, which isn&#39;t bad.&amp;#160; Gives me a chance to float around to check out some other things.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>EDMUG and Me</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/archives/edmug-and-me/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Apr 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/archives/edmug-and-me/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Well, this month &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.edmug.net&#34;&gt;EDMUG&lt;/a&gt; was hard up for speakers, so out of desperation they asked if I had anything to say.&amp;#160; I figured I could talk for about 30 minutes on MonoRail, and then read the newspaper out loud for the next 90 minutes.&amp;#160; Oddly, the EDMUG executive was okay with that.&amp;#160; This morning they sent out their notice to the membership:&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;blockquote&gt;   &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Thursday, April 24th&lt;/strong&gt; will not just be one of the greatest EDMUG evenings of all time, but it will also be the opportunity of a &lt;strong&gt;lifetime&lt;/strong&gt;.&amp;#160; It will be your chance to rub shoulders with&lt;strong&gt; a legend that walks like a man&lt;/strong&gt;.&amp;#160; And the name of that legend is:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>On Stored Procedures</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/archives/on-stored-procedures/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Apr 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/archives/on-stored-procedures/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Yesterday myself, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.igloocoder.com&#34;&gt;Don&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://geekswithblogs.net/dlussier/Default.aspx&#34;&gt;D&#39;Arcy&lt;/a&gt;, and Eric were wandering around Seattle, just checking out the sights after the MVP Summit.&amp;#160; We took a break from the usual &amp;quot;run down D&#39;Arcy and Manitoba&amp;quot; shtick, and actually had a serious conversation on the relevance of stored procedures for your typical database development/line of business app.&amp;#160; D&#39;Arcy &lt;a href=&#34;http://geekswithblogs.net/dlussier/archive/2008/04/18/121341.aspx&#34;&gt;blogged&lt;/a&gt; take on it already.&amp;#160; I was going to reply in his comments, but as the comments grew, I figured my own post was in order.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/archives/one-hundred-years-old/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Apr 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/archives/one-hundred-years-old/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.opgenorth.net/wp-content/uploads/2010/03/101EdmontonFusiliers_2.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img style=&#34;border-bottom: 0px; border-left: 0px; display: inline; margin-left: 0px; border-top: 0px; margin-right: 0px; border-right: 0px&#34; title=&#34;101EdmontonFusiliers_2&#34; border=&#34;0&#34; alt=&#34;101EdmontonFusiliers_2&#34; align=&#34;right&#34; src=&#34;http://www.opgenorth.net/wp-content/uploads/2010/03/101EdmontonFusiliers_2_thumb.jpg&#34; width=&#34;115&#34; height=&#34;161&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; In April, 1908 the 101st Edmonton Fusiliers were established as Alberta&#39;s first infantry regiment.&amp;#160; The first commanding office was Lieutenant-Colonel E.B. Edwards.&amp;#160; The 101st developed slowly, as most in the Edmonton area were attracted to the 19th Alberta Dragoons, a cavalry regiment which had been established in January of 1908. &lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;When war broke out in 1914, there was some question about the legality of using the existing militia regiments to fight overseas in Europe.&amp;#160; As such, the newly formed Canadian Expeditionary Force was comprised entirely of new battalions and the 101st was not allowed to go overseas.&amp;#160; The 101st Edmonton Fusilier recruited and contributed 1,200 men to these new battalions of the 1st Canadian Division, C.E.F in 1914.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Where Should Your Tests Live?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/archives/where-should-your-tests-live/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Apr 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/archives/where-should-your-tests-live/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Thanks to &lt;a href=&#34;http://haacked.com/Default.aspx&#34;&gt;Phil Haack&lt;/a&gt;&#39;s &lt;a href=&#34;http://haacked.com/archive/2008/04/09/unit-test-project-structure-poll.aspx&#34;&gt;online poll&lt;/a&gt;, there is a bit of controversy over where one&#39;s unit tests should reside:&amp;#160; should the unit tests be housed in a separate project and assembly, or do they shack up in the same project as the code that they are testing?&amp;#160; Like &lt;a href=&#34;http://weblogs.asp.net/bsimser/archive/2008/04/09/unit-test-projects-or-not.aspx&#34;&gt;Bil&lt;/a&gt;, I figured that rather than a big long blog comment, I&#39;d be better of with my post.&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;Way back when I started out with TDD, I used to put the test fixtures in the same file as the class under test, sort of like:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ASP.NET Web Services and jQuery/AJAX, Part 2</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/archives/asp-net-web-services-and-jqueryajax-part-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Mar 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/archives/asp-net-web-services-and-jqueryajax-part-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In my last post, I described how easy jQuery makes it to call an ASP.NET Web Service via AJAX.&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;Currently, I&#39;m developing on Windows XP (SP2), Resharper 4 (running inside Visual Studio 2008), and using the Visual Studio Web Server.&amp;#160; We deploy to Windows 2003 R2/IIS6.&amp;#160; When I pushed the code described in my last post to the development server to test it out there, the web service call kept failing with an HTTP Status of 500 (internal error).&amp;#160; This basically means something went wrong on the server.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ConnectionStrings.Com</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/archives/connectionstrings-com/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Mar 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/archives/connectionstrings-com/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Just figured I point out &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.connectionstrings.com&#34;&gt;ConnectionStrings.com&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;#160; I find this site rather handy because it shows you the syntax for the connection strings of pretty much every database you&#39;d want to use in .NET.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>VMware and 64-bit Ubuntu</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/archives/vmware-and-64-bit-ubuntu/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Mar 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/archives/vmware-and-64-bit-ubuntu/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Today I got a new hard drive for my web server, to replace the one that died back in February.&amp;#160; Hopefully the new 750GB drive will serve me as well as (or better) the old 200GB WD Cavair.&amp;#160; I must admit, I was a bit suprised at how cheap it was to get such a big HD.&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;The first order of business was to move my web site off it&#39;s current home and onto it&#39;s new, more permanent one.&amp;#160; I went about installing Ubunutu 7.10 64 bit, and them VMware server 1.0.4 on the new computer.&amp;#160; If you Google it, are a lot of articles on &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.google.ca/search?q=vmware+server+ubuntu+7.10&#34;&gt;installing VMware on Ubunutu&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;#160; However, I did run into one stumbling block:&amp;#160; with 64bit Ubunutu you need one more dependency: ia32-libs&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Continous Database Integration With Nant</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/archives/continous-database-integration-with-nant/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Jan 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/archives/continous-database-integration-with-nant/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Last night I spent some quality time looking at &lt;a href=&#34;http://code.google.com/p/vincent-vega/&#34;&gt;vincent-vega&lt;/a&gt;, aka Continuous Database Integration for SQL Server. This is a pretty simple and handy task for Nant that helps bring continous integration to your databases. I use updateSqlDatabase like as part of my integration tests like so:&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;ol&gt;   &lt;li&gt;Drop the database &lt;/li&gt;    &lt;li&gt;Create a new database &lt;/li&gt;    &lt;li&gt;Run some SQL scripts to bring my database up to date &lt;/li&gt;    &lt;li&gt;Run various database integration tests, repeating steps 1 -3 as necessary. &lt;/li&gt; &lt;/ol&gt;  &lt;p&gt;What this project will add a new task you: updateSqlDatabase. With this task, you can do one of three things: Add a database, Create a Database, and Update a database. updateSqlDatabase will look for SQL script files , and will execute those SQL scripts for you in the order they are found. Information about what scripts have been run are kept in a table that updateSqlDatabase creates for you when you create your database.&amp;#160; This will allow you to see the history of when your database was updated, and with scripts.&amp;#160; This   &lt;br /&gt;How to get started and use it? First, &lt;a href=&#34;http://code.google.com/p/vincent-vega/source&#34;&gt;get the code&lt;/a&gt; from Google Code. Compile the code. Next copy the output of the build to your Nant bin directory.&amp;#160; See the image below.&amp;#160; You probably won&#39;t need log4net.dll or Nant.Core.*.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mono.Rocks</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/archives/mono-rocks/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Dec 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/archives/mono-rocks/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;For those getting into .NET 3.5, you might find &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.mono-project.com/Rocks&#34;&gt;Mono.Rocks&lt;/a&gt; of interest.&amp;#160; I first saw this on &lt;a href=&#34;http://evain.net/blog/articles/2007/11/13/mono-rocks&#34;&gt;Jean-Baptiste Evain blog&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;#160; Basically, this is a collection of extension methods for the class libraries.&amp;#160; They are covered under the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.opensource.org/licenses/mit-license.php&#34;&gt;MIT licence&lt;/a&gt;, so you can pretty much use it anywhere.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Windsor and the db4o Facility</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/archives/windsor-and-the-db4o-facility/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Dec 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/archives/windsor-and-the-db4o-facility/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Once again, appealling to the niche (non-existant?) market, I give you a quick run down on using &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.db4o.com/&#34;&gt;db4o&lt;/a&gt;, and the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.castleproject.org/container/index.html&#34;&gt;Castle Windsor&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.castleproject.org/index.php/Facility:db4o&#34;&gt;db4o facility&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;#160; Yes, I know the link for the db4o facility link doesn&#39;t work.&amp;#160; That is what prompted me to do this blog post. This is because, a while ago, the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.db4o.com/&#34;&gt;db4o&lt;/a&gt; facility was pulled from the Castle Project.&amp;#160; Apparently there was a licencing concern.&amp;#160; It&#39;s my understanding that this has since been resolved, and I seen now that there is again the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.db4o.com&#34;&gt;db4o&lt;/a&gt; facility.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Code Cleanup with Resharper</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/archives/code-cleanup-with-resharper/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Dec 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/archives/code-cleanup-with-resharper/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As most Resharpies know, when you&#39;re using Resharper you can reformat your code. A nice feature is that you can use this reformat code to also organize and layout your code files the way you like it.&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;For example, &lt;a href=&#34;http://codebetter.com/blogs/kyle.baley/archive/2007/12/17/removing-regions-or-quot-how-to-keep-your-code-expanded-quot.aspx&#34;&gt;Kyle Baley did post&lt;/a&gt; on how to how to use the format code to get rid of regions. His techique is a bit unrefined - his revolutionary, dogmatic zeal he will clobber all regions and do nothing else - but still handy.&amp;#160;&amp;#160; Myself, I&#39;m a bit more compulsive / fussy when it comes to the layout of my code. Not only do I want regions gone, but I want the code to appear in a certain order. Lucky for me that Reformat Code does this for me. Here is the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.opgenorth.net/Data/Sites/1/Files/ResharperPatterns.xml&#34;&gt;Type Member Layout pattern I use&lt;/a&gt;. If you want to use it, just paste it into the type member layout window in Resharper.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>We Donât Want External Code</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/archives/we-dont-want-external-code/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Dec 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/archives/we-dont-want-external-code/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;One of the biggest discussions that I typically get when I try to introduce things like NHibernate (i.e. OSS) on a new contract goes like this:&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;&lt;em&gt;We&#39;re a bit reluctant to use that because it will introduce more code into our code base that isn&#39;t ours. Because it&#39;s OSS, there&#39;s no support, and if there was a bug in it, we&#39;d have to maintain it ourselves. That being case, we&#39;d rather just write our own code, because that way we know what is going on with it and can maintain it better. We don&#39;t want to have to figure out somebody elses code.&lt;/em&gt;&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fun with Open Source: OpenDental</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/archives/fun-with-open-source-opendental/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Nov 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/archives/fun-with-open-source-opendental/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The past week I&#39;ve been dabbling with an open source program called &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.open-dent.com/&#34;&gt;Open Dental&lt;/a&gt; - mostly trying to see if can get it to compile under Mono, and running under Linux.&amp;#160; I figure that this would be a good opportunity to and work with a cross platform application. &lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;According to their website, Open Dental has been supported under Linux since v4.7.&amp;#160; Here are some notes of my efforts so far.&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;You will need Mono v1.2.5.&amp;#160; It seems that there is a problem with the Linux binary installer ( a known bug that will be corrected in 1.2.6).&amp;#160; I used the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.mono-project.com/Downloads&#34;&gt;OpenSUSE 10.2 VMWare image&lt;/a&gt; which had a 1.2.5 install all set up.&amp;#160; That solved my problem of getting a current Linux distro with the most recent version of Mono.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Javascript Didnât Rape My Dog</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/archives/javascript-didnt-rape-my-dog/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Nov 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/archives/javascript-didnt-rape-my-dog/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;One thing I noticed since I started doing ASP.NET programming back in 2002: I started using Javascript a lot less, and my copy of JavaScript: The Definitive Guide sits on the shelf gathering dust.&amp;#160; I&#39;ve noticed a lot of developers I&#39;ve worked with are the same way. In fact, I&#39;d say that most of the ASP.NET programmers I&#39;ve worked with these days really don&#39;t know much about Javascript.&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;I don&#39;t blame Javascript itself for this - I blame ASP.NET. Developers just get used to dropping the server side controls on their WebForms, and then doing everything server side. I&#39;ve also worked at clients which had a &amp;quot;no client-side javascript&amp;quot; rule. All of this combines to cause our (my) Javascript skills to atrophy and wither. Kind of shame, really. (note: to a degree, I think the same can be said about CSS).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What is Right About .NET?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/archives/what-is-right-about-net/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Nov 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/archives/what-is-right-about-net/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Recently, on one of the mailing lists I subscribe to, a member starting bashing .NET. A bit curious as to why there was this strong hatred of .NET, I posed a simple question:&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;What is wrong with .NET?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;The answer I got back somewhat suprised me:&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;I guess the standard reply is, what is right about .NET?&amp;#160; .NET was invented so that M$ could provide software as a service. You would end up with a minimal OS on the disk, and no applications. When you turned your computer on, it would download whatever applications you needed, or did so on demand; if your subscription was paid up.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why I Love NHibernate</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/archives/why-i-love-nhibernate/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Oct 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/archives/why-i-love-nhibernate/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Why I love &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.nhibernate.org&#34;&gt;NHibernate&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;I am rather please by the fact that a database schema change involving the creation of six new tables, three one-to-many relationships, and a many-to-many relationship (which includes a sort order on the join table) can be taken care of inside of seven easy hours.&amp;#160; It probably would/could have been less, but I crafted the HBM and class files by hand and had a few typos which hide themselves well.&amp;#160; This also included the time it took to create some quick integration tests to ensure that CRUD is working.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Edmonton Code Camp 2007</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/archives/edmonton-code-camp-2007/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Oct 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/archives/edmonton-code-camp-2007/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This Saturday past we had the Edmonton Code Camp.&amp;#160; I&#39;d say things went pretty well.&amp;#160; It&#39;s my understanding that some 80 people showed up to hear a variety of topics.&amp;#160; I kicked off the day in &amp;quot;Track #2&amp;quot; with a Introduction to Test Driven Development.&amp;#160; For those who are interested in my presentation / code, you can download it &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.opgenorth.net/Data/Sites/1/Files/ECC2007_TDDAndUnitTesting.zip&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>NHibernate and Parent/Child Collections</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/archives/nhibernate-and-parentchild-collections/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Sep 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/archives/nhibernate-and-parentchild-collections/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;On a project that I&#39;m currently involved with, I&#39;m using NHibernate and a persistance-ignorant domain. Today NHibernate threw me a &amp;quot;&lt;em&gt;You may not dereference an collection with cascade=&amp;quot;all-delete-orphan&amp;quot;&lt;/em&gt;&amp;quot; error. This kind of had me confused for a bit. What this error means is this: When you have a parent-child relation in your domain, say something like this:&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;pre&gt;&lt;pre style=&#34;background-color: #ffffff; margin: 0em; width: 100%; font-family: consolas,&amp;#39;Courier New&amp;#39;,courier,monospace; font-size: 12px&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color: #0000ff&#34;&gt;public&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color: #0000ff&#34;&gt;class&lt;/span&gt; Parent&#xA;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;pre style=&#34;background-color: #ffffff; margin: 0em; width: 100%; font-family: consolas,&amp;#39;Courier New&amp;#39;,courier,monospace; font-size: 12px&#34;&gt;{&#xA;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;pre style=&#34;background-color: #ffffff; margin: 0em; width: 100%; font-family: consolas,&amp;#39;Courier New&amp;#39;,courier,monospace; font-size: 12px&#34;&gt;     ISet&amp;lt;Child&amp;gt; _children;&#xA;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;pre style=&#34;background-color: #ffffff; margin: 0em; width: 100%; font-family: consolas,&amp;#39;Courier New&amp;#39;,courier,monospace; font-size: 12px&#34;&gt;}&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;You can&#39;t do something like this in the parent class:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unit Testing Data Access</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/archives/unit-testing-data-access/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Sep 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/archives/unit-testing-data-access/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;One thing that I don&#39;t like about writing tests is some of the jiggery-pokery that goes on with testing database access code. Jiggery-pokery being: ensuring the tables are there, up to date, and are holding the data that they are supposed to hold before and after the test has run. If you don&#39;t pay attention to these details, you get a lot of false negatives on your unit tests. This will result in a loss of confidence in your unit tests. When this happens you stop running them, and loose confidence in your ability to refactor without fear.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Desert Code Camp 2007 Code &amp; PowerPoint</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/archives/desert-code-camp-2007-code-powerpoint/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Sep 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/archives/desert-code-camp-2007-code-powerpoint/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;For those who are interested, I put the PowerPoint slides and code from my Intro to Test Driven Development and Unit Test talk at &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.desertcodecamp.com/default.aspx&#34;&gt;Desert Code Camp 2007&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.opgenorth.net/Data/Sites/1/Files/DCC2007_TDDAndUnitTesting.zip&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;The presentation is in PowerPoint 2007.&amp;#160; If you need me to convert it to another format (PowerPoint 2003, OpenOffice Impress), let me know.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Coding for Fun:  Spying on Serial Ports</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/archives/coding-for-fun-spying-on-serial-ports/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Jul 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/archives/coding-for-fun-spying-on-serial-ports/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Yesterday I was house-bound looking after a sick eight year old boy.&amp;#160; To help pass time, I decided to play around with my chronograph (to clarify: in this context a chronograph is a tool to help you measure the velocity of projecticles, i.e. bullets).&amp;#160; I happen to own a &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.shootingchrony.com/&#34;&gt;Shooting Chrony&lt;/a&gt; Beta Master, which you can, in theory, hook up via a serial port to your computer, download the velocities of up to 60 shots, and use that data to help you with building up some ballisitic tables for your firearm and hand-loaded ammunition.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>VisualSVN and VS2008</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/archives/visualsvn-and-vs2008/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Jul 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/archives/visualsvn-and-vs2008/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;So last night I installed Visual Studio 2008 RTM on my laptop.&amp;#160; This was a clean install - I did not have any beta versions of VS2008 installed.&amp;#160; When I went to try and do anything in VS2008, I kept getting the message &#39;Visual Studio has encountered an unexpected error.&amp;quot;.&amp;#160; This error happens when I try to do anything, including VS2008.&amp;#160; The only way to close VS2008 was using Task Manager.&amp;#160; Most annoying.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Handy Rhino.Mocks Tip</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/archives/handy-rhino-mocks-tip/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Jul 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/archives/handy-rhino-mocks-tip/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I just pulled this &lt;a href=&#34;http://groups.google.com/group/RhinoMocks/tree/browse_frm/thread/fddb4a51e77b144/220886956ad923ad?rnum=1&amp;amp;hl=en&amp;amp;_done=%2Fgroup%2FRhinoMocks%2Fbrowse_frm%2Fthread%2Ffddb4a51e77b144%3Fhl%3Den%26#doc_b4fb8f3276ccfbf4&#34;&gt;handy tip&lt;/a&gt; from the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ayende.com/projects/rhino-mocks.aspx&#34;&gt;Rhino.Mocks&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://groups.google.com/group/RhinoMocks?hl=en&#34;&gt;mailing list&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;If you would like to see more details of the expectations that you are recording and matching, try adding this in your test setup:&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;pre&gt;RhinoMocks.Logger = New TextWriterExpectationLogger (Console.Out)&lt;/pre&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;You should then see all the logging messages in the Output window of Visual Studio.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Trying to Mock the Unmockable</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/archives/trying-to-mock-the-unmockable/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Jun 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/archives/trying-to-mock-the-unmockable/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;(or, &lt;em&gt;DataRowView How I Hate Thee&lt;/em&gt;)     &lt;br /&gt;Recently I had to enhance an ASP.NET 2.0 &lt;a href=&#34;http://msdn2.microsoft.com/en-us/library/system.web.ui.webcontrols.gridview.aspx&#34;&gt;GridView&lt;/a&gt; on a Web Form.&amp;#160; Basically, the idea is that, if a certain field in the grid was false, I would strike-through all the text in that row.&amp;#160; It seems simple enough: just use the &lt;a href=&#34;http://msdn2.microsoft.com/en-us/library/system.web.ui.webcontrols.gridview.rowdatabound.aspx&#34;&gt;RowDataBound&lt;/a&gt; event of the &lt;a href=&#34;http://msdn2.microsoft.com/en-us/library/system.web.ui.webcontrols.gridview.aspx&#34;&gt;GridView&lt;/a&gt; control and&amp;#160; apply the formating.&amp;#160; Wanting to make this as testable as possible, I thought that perhaps some sort of decorator class would do the trick, something like: &lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Not So Deep Thoughts on Stored Procedures</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/archives/not-so-deep-thoughts-on-stored-procedures/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Apr 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/archives/not-so-deep-thoughts-on-stored-procedures/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Lately I&#39;ve come to the conclusion that stored procedures are more of a specialist&#39;s tool than a generalist.&amp;#160; To me, stored procedures are the kind of thing you use when you need to optimize your data access, or you have to do something DB specific.&amp;#160; Sure, I&#39;ve seen lots (and written lots) of stored procedures to do the basic CRUD (mostly in &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.microsoft.com/sql&#34;&gt;SQL Server&lt;/a&gt;, but also in &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.postgresql.org&#34;&gt;PostgreSQL&lt;/a&gt;). These days though, I almost think that one doesn&#39;t need stored procedures for the basic CRUD, only for specific and special cases.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Converting between VB.NET and C#</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/archives/converting-between-vb-net-and-c/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Apr 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/archives/converting-between-vb-net-and-c/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Ever have a need to convert some VB.NET code to C# (or vis versa)?&amp;#160; &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.telerik.com/&#34;&gt;Telerik&lt;/a&gt; has a &lt;a href=&#34;http://converter.telerik.com/&#34;&gt;online code converter&lt;/a&gt; that seems to do the trick.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>NHibernate Best Practices</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/archives/nhibernate-best-practices/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Apr 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/archives/nhibernate-best-practices/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Well, I see that &lt;a href=&#34;http://devlicio.us/blogs/billy_mccafferty/default.aspx&#34;&gt;Billy McCafferty&lt;/a&gt; has updated his article &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.codeproject.com/aspnet/NHibernateBestPractices.asp&#34;&gt;NHibernate Best Practices with ASP.NET&lt;/a&gt; to cover &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.nhibernate.org&#34;&gt;NHibernate&lt;/a&gt; 1.2.&amp;#160; Excellent article, I&#39;d suggest taking the time to read it.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Embedded Database and .NET</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/archives/embedded-database-and-net/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Feb 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/archives/embedded-database-and-net/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As mentioned in some of my previous blog entries, I&#39;m looking for am embedded database.&amp;#160; At the present, I think that I will remove SQL Server CE for now.&amp;#160; The biggest reason is that, as part of my pet project, the application to run on &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.mono-project.com/Main_Page&#34;&gt;Mono&lt;/a&gt; as well.&amp;#160; So, that kind of leaves &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.sqlite.org/&#34;&gt;SQLite&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.firebirdsql.org&#34;&gt;Firebird&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;#160; &lt;br /&gt;Now, in theory, it should matter much between the two for what I want to do.&amp;#160; I&#39;m planning to use &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.castleproject.org/activerecord/index.html&#34;&gt;ActiveRecord&lt;/a&gt; for my data layer, and I see that both &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.sqlite.org/&#34;&gt;SQLite&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.firebirdsql.org&#34;&gt;Firebird&lt;/a&gt; are supported.&amp;#160; So, switching between &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.sqlite.org/&#34;&gt;SQLite&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.firebirdsql.org&#34;&gt;Firebird&lt;/a&gt; will be pretty minimal.&amp;#160; What about stored procedures, I hear you say?&amp;#160; Well, truth be told, in my old age, I&#39;ve sort of drifted away from stored procedures and look at them with a suspicious eye.&amp;#160; So, the fact that &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.sqlite.org/&#34;&gt;SQLite&lt;/a&gt; doesn&#39;t have stored procedures really doesn&#39;t bother or impact me at all.    &lt;br /&gt;I&#39;ll do a bit more comparison between the two, and then decided from there which database to use.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Active Record Entry #1.5/Genom-e Express</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/archives/active-record-entry-1-5genom-e-express/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Sep 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/archives/active-record-entry-1-5genom-e-express/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Well, as predicted something did distract me from my &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.castleproject.org/index.php/ActiveRecord&#34;&gt;ActiveRecord&lt;/a&gt; experiment.&amp;#160; I got a copy of &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.genom-e.com&#34;&gt;Genome Express&lt;/a&gt; while at an &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.edmug.net/&#34;&gt;EDMUG&lt;/a&gt; meeting recently.&amp;#160; Given that my copy of Genome Express was shiny and new, I installed it and began playing.&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;My initialize impression is that it&#39;s promising.&amp;#160; I was able to very quickly reverse engineer a SQL 2005 schema and get a heirarchical data model going.&amp;#160; I was able to generate working DAL code for a 12 table database inside of a couple of hours.&amp;#160; About 75% of this time was spent reading the documentation.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Active Record Entry #1</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/archives/active-record-entry-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Aug 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/archives/active-record-entry-1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Well, after playing with &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.castleproject.org/index.php/ActiveRecord&#34;&gt;ActiveRecord&lt;/a&gt; for about a week and a bit now, and I can say it&#39;s kind of a love-hate relationship.&amp;#160; I like how easy it is to drop in a class, or to make changes to the DB schema and have that reflected in your model.&amp;#160; Contrawise, changing databases should be just as easy. &lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;Troubleshooting is a real bitch, and I find the documenatation a bit on the light side.&amp;#160; Also, on the surface, the parent/child relationships seem pretty easy to setup and configure, but I seem to be having some issues with it.&amp;#160; Also, a familiarity with &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.nhibernate.org&#34;&gt;NHibernate&lt;/a&gt; definately seems to be helpful when debugging/troubleshoot.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A First Impression of MSBuild</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/archives/a-first-impression-of-msbuild/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Dec 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/archives/a-first-impression-of-msbuild/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Lately I&#39;ve been playing with MSBuild, the new build tool that ships with Visual Studio 2005.&amp;#160; Before, I&#39;ve always used &lt;a href=&#34;http://nant.sourceforge.net&#34;&gt;Nant&lt;/a&gt; for my automated builds.&amp;#160; I&#39;ve been using nant since 2002 or so, and found it to be a pretty useful, stable tool to take the drudgery out of deploying builds.&amp;#160; Figured I would give MSBuild a try, just for comparison sake.&amp;#160; &lt;br /&gt;I must say, MSBuild isn&#39;t bad.&amp;#160; One thing that I&#39;ve found interesting about is that it has been ridiculously easy to port tasks from &lt;a href=&#34;http://nant.sourceforge.net&#34;&gt;nant&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://nantcontrib.sourceforge.net&#34;&gt;nantcontrib&lt;/a&gt; to MSBuild.&amp;#160; So far I&#39;ve written tasks to apply a label to VSS, and to help me create a zip file holding the deployables of the build. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
