<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on opgenorth.net</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on opgenorth.net</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 22 Apr 2019 08:39:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>.22LR Ammo Evaluation - Sterling Cross</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/22LR-ammo-sterling-cross/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/22LR-ammo-sterling-cross/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Over the past couple of years there has been a surge of interest in .22 Rimfire in Canada (at least from my perspective). Arguably, it could be traced to the start of &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.mapleseedrifleman.com&#34;&gt;Project Mapleseed&lt;/a&gt; back in 2017, which then spawned the &lt;a href=&#34;https://rimfireprecision.ca&#34;&gt;Canadian Rimfire Precision Series&lt;/a&gt; in 2018, and now this year the &lt;a href=&#34;https://outlawrimfire.com&#34;&gt;Outlaw Rimfire Precision Series&lt;/a&gt;. My friends south of the border have &lt;a href=&#34;https://appleseedinfo.org&#34;&gt;Project Appleseed&lt;/a&gt; and the &lt;a href=&#34;https://nrl-22.org&#34;&gt;National Rimfire League&lt;/a&gt;. As you can see, plenty of opportunity to participate/compete with the humble .22LR cartridge.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reforming Brass: From One Cartridge to Another</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/reforming-brass-for-8mm/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/reforming-brass-for-8mm/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The 8mm Mauser (7.92x57mm) round, in it&amp;rsquo;s current incarnation, has been around since 1903. It is a improvement of the original 7.92x57mm cartridge that was developed in 1888 by Peter Paul Mauser.  Arguably, 8mm Mauser has been one of the world&amp;rsquo;s most popular cartridges, having seen significant military and civilian use over the past 100+ year. It also influenced the design of many of today&amp;rsquo;s cartridges, such as .30-06.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/images/2018-09-28-reforming-brass-for-8mm/01.png&#34; alt=&#34;8mm Mauser cartridges&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ballistics of the Norinco 7.62x51</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/norinco-762x51-ballistics/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/norinco-762x51-ballistics/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;After an amateur attempt at trying to calculate the &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/blog/2017/05/07/norinco-762x39-ballistics/&#34;&gt;BC of the Norinco 7.62x39mm&lt;/a&gt; ammunition, I thought I would do the same thing with Norinco&amp;rsquo;s 7.62x51mm ammo. As one would expect, this stuff is fairly inexpensive as well, running aroun $0.50/round. I don&amp;rsquo;t think this is &amp;ldquo;precision ammo&amp;rdquo;, but it works well enough in my rifle.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/images/Norc76251.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;First off, I pulled one bullet apart, and weight it. The projecticle itself weight 146.1 grains, so I guess this is supposed to be 147gr ammo. I measured ~ 42.0 grains of &amp;ldquo;mystery gun powder&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ballistics of the Norinco 7.62x39</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/norinco-762x39-ballistics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/norinco-762x39-ballistics/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;On of the great things about 7.62x39mm rifles (like the SKS) is that (for the time being) ammo is fairly inexpensive. A fellow who keeps his eye open for a deal can find 7.62x39mm in the range of $0.16CAD (for corrosive) to $0.30CAD (for non-corrosive) ammo. Of course being surplus ammo, finding ballistics data on this ammunition can be a bit of a trick. Granted, the 7.62x39 cartridge isn&amp;rsquo;t exactly a &amp;ldquo;precision&amp;rdquo; round, but intellectual curiousity had me wondering what the ballistic coefficient (BC) of this Norinco ammo was.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Don&#39;t Let Crud, Corruption, and Communism Kill Your Smart Watch</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/dont-let-crud-corruption-and-communism-kill-your-smartwatch/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/dont-let-crud-corruption-and-communism-kill-your-smartwatch/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I have a &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.samsung.com/global/microsite/gear/gearlive_design.html&#34;&gt;Samsung Gear Live&lt;/a&gt;. One day, all of sudden, it wouldn&amp;rsquo;t turn on after I had it charging in it&amp;rsquo;s little charging dock. I thought the problem was with the watch, and Google the symptoms led me to one of two conclusions:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The watch was defective, and I should send it back under warranty.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;I could fix the problem by taking the watch apart, disconnecting the battery for a minute, and then reconnecting the battery. Or something like that.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I was a bit dismayed that for a device not even a year old that these were my options. I was mulling over the options, and I flipped the watch over to see what tools I would need to take the watch apart (who doesn&amp;rsquo;t like disassembling electronics), when I notice that the contact points on the watch were filthy (as one the NCOs on my infantry course used to say when inspecting rifles – &amp;ldquo;crud, corruption, and communism&amp;rdquo;). You can see the contacts for the charging dock right in the picture below:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Getting Started with Data Binding in Android</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/android-data-binding-intro/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/android-data-binding-intro/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;(Note: This is an updated version of a post from June, 2015)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In May, 2015 at Google announced &lt;a href=&#34;https://developer.android.com/tools/data-binding/guide.html&#34;&gt;a data binding library for Android&lt;/a&gt;. The data binding library is currently in beta, so things might change and make what I am saying here irrelevant/obsolete. When in doubt, consult the official documentation.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s long overdue – developers no longer have to come up with their own schemes for displaying or retrieving data from their views. With two-way data binding, it&amp;rsquo;s possible to remove a lot of redundant boilerplate code from the activities and fragments that make up an application.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Wiring Up a Nest</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/wiring-up-a-nest/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/wiring-up-a-nest/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This weekend I finally broke down and installed a &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.nest.com&#34;&gt;Nest thermostat&lt;/a&gt; in my house. They have a nice &lt;a href=&#34;https://nest.com/widget/compatibility/&#34;&gt;compatibility wizard&lt;/a&gt; which does a pretty good job of showing you how to wire up your Nest based on the wires you can see in your existing thermostat.  There were two gotchas that their wiring diagram didn&amp;rsquo;t cover. Here is a picture of the old thermostat (a Rodgers-White):&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/assets/old_thermostat.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Notice that there were two &lt;code&gt;W&lt;/code&gt; wires. I&amp;rsquo;m not to sure what is up with that, I suspect that that one wire leads up to the humidifier. I ended up splicing the two wires together with a marette, and then connecting the spliced wire to the &lt;code&gt;W&lt;/code&gt; connection on the Nest. This was not documented anywhere on the Nest website.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The other thing that the &lt;code&gt;Rc&lt;/code&gt; post on the thermostat was jumpered over to the &lt;code&gt;Rh&lt;/code&gt; post. All I had to do here is remove the jumper and just plug the wire into the &lt;code&gt;Rh&lt;/code&gt; connection on my Nest. This issue was &lt;a href=&#34;https://nest.com/ca/support/article/How-do-I-install-Nest-if-my-old-thermostat-had-a-short-wire-connecting-Rh-and-Rc&#34;&gt;documented on the Nest website&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;All in all, the process was quick and easy. Now to see if the Nest actually makes a difference in my energy bill.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>My First QuadCopter</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/my-first-quadcopter/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jul 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/my-first-quadcopter/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Just recently I acquired a new quadcopter – a WL Toys 959. Total cost to me was about $75.00 and I ordered from Amazon.ca. I picked this because of the low cost and the fact that it came with camera that can do both photo and video and it was relatively inexpensive.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;First attempts at flying the quadcopter proved somewhat crash prone, so I ended up reading the manual and checking out some YouTube vidoes on quadcopter flight. Most informative was &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=LCret4rv0HE&#34;&gt;this YouTube video&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Vortex_ring_state&#34;&gt;Vortex Ring State&lt;/a&gt; and how to deal with it (thanks to colleague Joel Martinez for the tip). I have a video of my first flight – it&amp;rsquo;s nothing fancy I just wanted to take off, hover, and then land.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reloading 8mm Mauser</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/reloading-8mm-mauser/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jul 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/reloading-8mm-mauser/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;8mm Mauser is a great round, problem is that in North America it&amp;rsquo;s not always easy to find good 8x57mm ammunition. When you do manage to find it, it tends to bit a bit expensive, &amp;gt; $1.00/round. Here is where hand loading pays itself off. I used to handload my own 8x57mm, however I stopped for a few years and now I can&amp;rsquo;t seem to find my old load data.  This isn&amp;rsquo;t a horrible thing as it means I get to go to the range to test out new recipes.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nexus 5 Retrieving Shots from Shooting Chrony Beta Master</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/nexus-5-retrieving-shots-from-shooting-chrony-beta-master/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/nexus-5-retrieving-shots-from-shooting-chrony-beta-master/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I spent a little bit of time since Christmas working on an Android application that will download velocities from my Shooting Chrony Beta Master. First I pair my Android phone to my Shooting Chrony &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.opgenorth.net/blog/2015/01/21/adding-bluetooth-to-your-shooting-chrony/&#34;&gt;via bluetooth&lt;/a&gt;. A couple of taps on the screen, and lo, shot data is retrieved:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://s3.amazonaws.com/opgenorthnet-blog/hayha_0-2-1-8.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The app itself isn&amp;rsquo;t ready for public consumption, but as a proof of concept it is encouraging to see. I uploaded a &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=f86lG9KTMf8&#34;&gt;video of this to YouTube&lt;/a&gt; so you can see the application in action.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Adding Bluetooth to your Shooting Chrony</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/adding-bluetooth-to-your-shooting-chrony/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/adding-bluetooth-to-your-shooting-chrony/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;re into reloading, you know about chronographs. Odds are you might have a &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.shootingchrony.com/&#34;&gt;Shooting Chrony&lt;/a&gt;. I myself happen to own a &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.shootingchrony.com/products_SCMMCM.htm&#34;&gt;Shooting Chrony Beta Master&lt;/a&gt;. These are pretty well made devices, and Shooting Chrony has a no nonsense replacement policy.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The only way to interact with the device is via a proprietary &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.shootingchrony.com/products_ibmpcinterface.htm&#34;&gt;9-pin-female RS-232 cable&lt;/a&gt;, like an old modem. Now, this techique was all the rage circa 1994 when dial-up internet was king and everybody had PC&amp;rsquo;s with two or more serial ports. This is really sub-par when you want to try and connect your smartphone to a Shooting Chrony (yes, this is possible, but more on this later).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Using Estimotes with Xamarin.Android</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/using-estimotes-with-xamarin-dot-android/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Feb 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/using-estimotes-with-xamarin-dot-android/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I recently bought some &lt;a href=&#34;http://estimote.com/&#34;&gt;Estimote&lt;/a&gt; beacons (a 3rd party iBeacon-like device) - largely because they seem like a cool and nerdy kind of thing. It has an &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/Estimote/Android-SDK&#34;&gt;Android SDK&lt;/a&gt; which will allow Android devices to interaction with devices. With a little big of effort, I managed to create &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/topgenorth/Estimotes-Xamarin/&#34;&gt;Xamarin.Android binding&lt;/a&gt; and port the sample Android project provided by the Estimote SDK.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;You can see an example of the app in these screenshots:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://s3.amazonaws.com/opgenorthnet-blog/estimote1.png&#34; alt=&#34;image&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Measuring Distance with Arduino</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/measuring-distance-with-arduino/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/measuring-distance-with-arduino/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.parallax.com/product/28015&#34;&gt;Ping)))&lt;/a&gt; is ultrasonic range finder that is pretty easy to use in an Arduino project. In my case, I&amp;rsquo;m using it to monitor the water level in a sump pump. I have an Arduino Uno R3 (with Ethernet Shield) connected to a Ping))) and a &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.sparkfun.com/products/10988&#34;&gt;TMP36&lt;/a&gt; temperature sensor that is perched above my sump pump. Every 2 minutes the Uno will send out a ping, and figure out the distance to the water below. The TMP36 is used to account for the air temperature in the speed of sound calculations.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Animate a ListView deletion in Xamarin.Android</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/animate-a-listview-deletion-in-xamarin-dot-android/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Sep 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/animate-a-listview-deletion-in-xamarin-dot-android/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A visually pleasant effect when deleting items from a ListView is to animate the row being deleted by gradually change the &lt;code&gt;.Alpha&lt;/code&gt; value of the view from 1.0 to 0.0. If you&amp;rsquo;ve tried to animate the deletion of a row from a &lt;a href=&#34;http://developer.android.com/reference/android/widget/ListView.html&#34;&gt;ListView&lt;/a&gt; in a Xamarin.Android application, you may observe some curious behaviour when rapidly scrolling through a ListView with many rows: the animation may appear on rows other than then one that is being deleted.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sublime Text 2 and Arduino</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/sublime-text-2-and-arduino/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/sublime-text-2-and-arduino/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;re looking to get into Arduino, and you&amp;rsquo;re a programmer, the first thing that will jump out at you is the Arduino IDE. It&amp;rsquo;s best described as &amp;ldquo;spartan&amp;rdquo; (to say the least). As I&amp;rsquo;m used to full featured IDE&amp;rsquo;s I started looking for a replacement to the default Arduino IDE.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;There are extensions to use Visual Studio, but that means me starting up a VM to run Windows which I don&amp;rsquo;t really want to do for Arduino development. There is a another IDE which looks promising called Maria Mole - but it&amp;rsquo;s Windows only so not really a contender for me.  I need something for OS X. I looked at setting up Eclipse as my default IDE, but ran into some issues with that. Nothing to major, but as I don&amp;rsquo;t like Eclipse in the first place I wasn&amp;rsquo;t to motivated to sort things out, so I abandoned Eclipse as an IDE choice.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The next thing I tried was &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.sublimetext.com/&#34;&gt;Sublime Text&lt;/a&gt;. There is an Ardunio plugin called &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/Robot-Will/Stino&#34;&gt;Stino&lt;/a&gt; that turns Sublime into a not bad IDE. In terms of writing your programs, Stino can pretty much do everything the Arduino IDE can do: compile programs, upload them to your Arduino board, import libraries, etc.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Writing GPS information to a JPEG</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/writing-gps-information-to-a-jpeg/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Feb 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/writing-gps-information-to-a-jpeg/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;One of the handy things about the JPEG format is the ability to store meta-data inside the image using &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Exchangeable_image_file_format&#34;&gt;EXIF&lt;/a&gt;. There are a few libraries out there for the various programming languages that can help you out with this, and Android actually has something built in to the SDK - the class &lt;a href=&#34;http://developer.android.com/reference/android/media/ExifInterface.html&#34;&gt;ExifInterface&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Google&amp;rsquo;s documentation on writing latitude and longitude to a JPEG are a bit light on details - they loosely hint at the format that latitude or longitude should have. (See the documentation for &lt;a href=&#34;http://developer.android.com/reference/android/media/ExifInterface.html#TAG_GPS_LATITUDE&#34;&gt;ExifInterface.TAG_GPS_LATITUDE&lt;/a&gt;). The API itself is pretty straight forward, but what Google doesn&amp;rsquo;t tell you is HOW the GPS coordinates should encoded.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>rake your Xamarin.Android Application</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/rake-your-mono-for-android-application/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Feb 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/rake-your-mono-for-android-application/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Deploy early, deploy often is a popular goal in Agile methodologies. One easy way to support this to automate your build process. Last year at this time I would just use &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.finalbuilder.com/finalbuilder.aspx&#34;&gt;FinalBuilder&lt;/a&gt; to automate the builds of my Xamarin.Android pet projects. It doesn&amp;rsquo;t take much to set FinalBuilder, and it does provide support for a lot of tasks such as versioning .NET assemblies, manipulating XML, dealing with the file system, and so on.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The problem is that FinalBuilder is Windows only. OS X and Linux types are left out in the cold. As I find myself working almost exclusive in OS X when developing my Xamarin.Android applications, I was looking for a Windows free way to automate my builds.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Enter &lt;a href=&#34;http://rake.rubyforge.org/&#34;&gt;rake&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://albacorebuild.net/&#34;&gt;albacore&lt;/a&gt;. rake is, of course the build system for Ruby.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
