<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Android on opgenorth.net</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/Android/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Android on opgenorth.net</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 14 Sep 2015 21:45:32 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/Android/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Getting Started with Data Binding in Android</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/android-data-binding-intro/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/android-data-binding-intro/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;(Note: This is an updated version of a post from June, 2015)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In May, 2015 at Google announced &lt;a href=&#34;https://developer.android.com/tools/data-binding/guide.html&#34;&gt;a data binding library for Android&lt;/a&gt;. The data binding library is currently in beta, so things might change and make what I am saying here irrelevant/obsolete. When in doubt, consult the official documentation.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s long overdue – developers no longer have to come up with their own schemes for displaying or retrieving data from their views. With two-way data binding, it&amp;rsquo;s possible to remove a lot of redundant boilerplate code from the activities and fragments that make up an application.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nexus 5 Retrieving Shots from Shooting Chrony Beta Master</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/nexus-5-retrieving-shots-from-shooting-chrony-beta-master/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/nexus-5-retrieving-shots-from-shooting-chrony-beta-master/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I spent a little bit of time since Christmas working on an Android application that will download velocities from my Shooting Chrony Beta Master. First I pair my Android phone to my Shooting Chrony &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.opgenorth.net/blog/2015/01/21/adding-bluetooth-to-your-shooting-chrony/&#34;&gt;via bluetooth&lt;/a&gt;. A couple of taps on the screen, and lo, shot data is retrieved:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://s3.amazonaws.com/opgenorthnet-blog/hayha_0-2-1-8.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The app itself isn&amp;rsquo;t ready for public consumption, but as a proof of concept it is encouraging to see. I uploaded a &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=f86lG9KTMf8&#34;&gt;video of this to YouTube&lt;/a&gt; so you can see the application in action.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Adding Bluetooth to your Shooting Chrony</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/adding-bluetooth-to-your-shooting-chrony/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/adding-bluetooth-to-your-shooting-chrony/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;re into reloading, you know about chronographs. Odds are you might have a &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.shootingchrony.com/&#34;&gt;Shooting Chrony&lt;/a&gt;. I myself happen to own a &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.shootingchrony.com/products_SCMMCM.htm&#34;&gt;Shooting Chrony Beta Master&lt;/a&gt;. These are pretty well made devices, and Shooting Chrony has a no nonsense replacement policy.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The only way to interact with the device is via a proprietary &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.shootingchrony.com/products_ibmpcinterface.htm&#34;&gt;9-pin-female RS-232 cable&lt;/a&gt;, like an old modem. Now, this techique was all the rage circa 1994 when dial-up internet was king and everybody had PC&amp;rsquo;s with two or more serial ports. This is really sub-par when you want to try and connect your smartphone to a Shooting Chrony (yes, this is possible, but more on this later).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Using Estimotes with Xamarin.Android</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/using-estimotes-with-xamarin-dot-android/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Feb 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/using-estimotes-with-xamarin-dot-android/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I recently bought some &lt;a href=&#34;http://estimote.com/&#34;&gt;Estimote&lt;/a&gt; beacons (a 3rd party iBeacon-like device) - largely because they seem like a cool and nerdy kind of thing. It has an &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/Estimote/Android-SDK&#34;&gt;Android SDK&lt;/a&gt; which will allow Android devices to interaction with devices. With a little big of effort, I managed to create &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/topgenorth/Estimotes-Xamarin/&#34;&gt;Xamarin.Android binding&lt;/a&gt; and port the sample Android project provided by the Estimote SDK.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;You can see an example of the app in these screenshots:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://s3.amazonaws.com/opgenorthnet-blog/estimote1.png&#34; alt=&#34;image&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Animate a ListView deletion in Xamarin.Android</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/animate-a-listview-deletion-in-xamarin-dot-android/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Sep 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/animate-a-listview-deletion-in-xamarin-dot-android/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A visually pleasant effect when deleting items from a ListView is to animate the row being deleted by gradually change the &lt;code&gt;.Alpha&lt;/code&gt; value of the view from 1.0 to 0.0. If you&amp;rsquo;ve tried to animate the deletion of a row from a &lt;a href=&#34;http://developer.android.com/reference/android/widget/ListView.html&#34;&gt;ListView&lt;/a&gt; in a Xamarin.Android application, you may observe some curious behaviour when rapidly scrolling through a ListView with many rows: the animation may appear on rows other than then one that is being deleted.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Writing GPS information to a JPEG</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/writing-gps-information-to-a-jpeg/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Feb 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/writing-gps-information-to-a-jpeg/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;One of the handy things about the JPEG format is the ability to store meta-data inside the image using &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Exchangeable_image_file_format&#34;&gt;EXIF&lt;/a&gt;. There are a few libraries out there for the various programming languages that can help you out with this, and Android actually has something built in to the SDK - the class &lt;a href=&#34;http://developer.android.com/reference/android/media/ExifInterface.html&#34;&gt;ExifInterface&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Google&amp;rsquo;s documentation on writing latitude and longitude to a JPEG are a bit light on details - they loosely hint at the format that latitude or longitude should have. (See the documentation for &lt;a href=&#34;http://developer.android.com/reference/android/media/ExifInterface.html#TAG_GPS_LATITUDE&#34;&gt;ExifInterface.TAG_GPS_LATITUDE&lt;/a&gt;). The API itself is pretty straight forward, but what Google doesn&amp;rsquo;t tell you is HOW the GPS coordinates should encoded.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>rake your Xamarin.Android Application</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/rake-your-mono-for-android-application/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Feb 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/rake-your-mono-for-android-application/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Deploy early, deploy often is a popular goal in Agile methodologies. One easy way to support this to automate your build process. Last year at this time I would just use &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.finalbuilder.com/finalbuilder.aspx&#34;&gt;FinalBuilder&lt;/a&gt; to automate the builds of my Xamarin.Android pet projects. It doesn&amp;rsquo;t take much to set FinalBuilder, and it does provide support for a lot of tasks such as versioning .NET assemblies, manipulating XML, dealing with the file system, and so on.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The problem is that FinalBuilder is Windows only. OS X and Linux types are left out in the cold. As I find myself working almost exclusive in OS X when developing my Xamarin.Android applications, I was looking for a Windows free way to automate my builds.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Enter &lt;a href=&#34;http://rake.rubyforge.org/&#34;&gt;rake&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://albacorebuild.net/&#34;&gt;albacore&lt;/a&gt;. rake is, of course the build system for Ruby.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Windows 8 64-bit and Android Debug Bridge (Where is my Galaxy Nexus?)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/archives/windows-8-64-bit-and-android-debug-bridge-where-is-my-galaxy-nexus/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Sep 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/archives/windows-8-64-bit-and-android-debug-bridge-where-is-my-galaxy-nexus/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Setting up a new VM for development - this one based on Windows 8 64 bit. Not that I really want to, but it seems that I need to for work (yes, yes, first world problems). So the usual fun with standing up a new VM:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Install OS&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Download Chrome and Firefox and ditch IE&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Download Resharper&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Remember that you need Visual Studio for Resharper so install that.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Install Java SDK&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Install Android SDK&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Install Intellij and Eclipse&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;etc.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Of course, then I notice that my phone, a Galaxy Nexus, isn&amp;rsquo;t being recognized by Android Debug Bridge.  This is a problem as I much prefer to develop using a device as opposed slow emulator that Google ships for Android, and you can&amp;rsquo;t deploy to the device without ADB.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>PreferenceFragment.getPreferencesFromIntent</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/archives/preferencefragment-getpreferencesfromintent/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 May 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/archives/preferencefragment-getpreferencesfromintent/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;One of the new classes that Honeycomb introduced was the &lt;a href=&#34;http://developer.android.com/reference/android/preference/PreferenceFragment.html&#34;&gt;PreferenceFragment&lt;/a&gt;. This class is meant to simplify the creatation of a setting / preferences screen in Android applications. It handles a lot of the displaying, saving, and changing of an application&amp;rsquo;s settings. There are a couple of ways to create a &lt;code&gt;PreferenceFragment&lt;/code&gt;. The simplest way is to subclass, override &lt;code&gt;onCreate()&lt;/code&gt; and then use either &lt;code&gt;getPreferencesFromResource&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;getPreferencesFromIntent&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;There are many examples on how to use &lt;code&gt;getPreferencesFromResource&lt;/code&gt;, but I noticed that there aren&amp;rsquo;t that many on how to use &lt;code&gt;getPreferencesFromIntent&lt;/code&gt;. Here is one such quick example.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Galaxy Nexus - Why don&#39;t you stay connected?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/archives/galaxy-nexus/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 May 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/archives/galaxy-nexus/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I recently got a Galaxy Nexus, and like a typical geek I &lt;a href=&#34;http://androidforums.com/international-galaxy-nexus-all-things-root/452146-how-root-gsm-hspa-samsung-galaxy-nexus.html&#34;&gt;unlocked the bootloader and then rooted it&lt;/a&gt;. Life was good running Android 4.0.1. Well sort of. I had problems tethering my MacBook Pro via the WiFi hotspot, but no problems using Bluetooth. So nothing I couldn&amp;rsquo;t work around.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Then I received an OTA update to Android 4.0.4 recently.  And this was when things started going not so good - specifically, for some blasted reason, I kept losing connectivity to Wind Mobile&amp;rsquo;s network. At first I thought it was Wind Mobile having issues. This would be odd, because for me, Wind Mobile has been pretty solid. To troubleshoot I pulled my SIM card and dropped it into my Nexus One. Everything worked fine. So apparently something with my phone.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Using AutoCompleteTextView and SimpleCursorAdapter</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/archives/using-autocompletetextview-and-simplecursoradapter-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Sep 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/archives/using-autocompletetextview-and-simplecursoradapter-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I have a simple little pet project (for Android), and one of the things I wanted to do was to to have a text field that would show me previous values as I typed in the text box (see screenshot below). Of course, this control is already a part of the Android SDK - it&#39;s our good friend the &lt;a href=&#34;http://developer.android.com/reference/android/widget/AutoCompleteTextView.html&#34;&gt;AutoCompleteTextView&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://www.opgenorth.net/wp-content/uploads/2011/09/AutoCompleteTextView.png&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;To populate the drop-down, I have an SQLite table called vehicle_descriptions, which looks something like the screenshot below. What I want is for a given vehicle (a value derived from another control on my Activity) to show me the value of the description column in the table.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Slide deck and code from Prairie Developers Conference 2011</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/archives/slide-deck-and-code-from-prairie-developers-conference-2011/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jun 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/archives/slide-deck-and-code-from-prairie-developers-conference-2011/</guid>
      <description>For those wanted the slide-decks and code from my talks at &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.prairiedevcon.com/&#34;&gt;Prairie Developer&#39;s Conference 2011&lt;/a&gt;, you can find them up on &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/topgenorth/PrDC2011&#34;&gt;GitHub&lt;/a&gt;. Thanks to all who attended.&amp;nbsp; Maybe we&#39;ll see you again next year.&lt;br /&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>WIND Mobile and my Nexus One</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/archives/wind-mobile-and-my-nexus-one/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Dec 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/archives/wind-mobile-and-my-nexus-one/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Just recently I switch my mobile carrier from Rogers to &lt;a title=&#34;WIND mobile&#34; href=&#34;../../www.windmobile.ca&#34;&gt;WIND Mobile&lt;/a&gt;. Their &lt;a title=&#34;Holiday Miracle Plan&#34; href=&#34;http://www2.windmobile.ca/en/Pages/unlimitedtalktextdata.aspx&#34;&gt;Holiday Miracle plan&lt;/a&gt; was just to good to pass up - even paying the penalty to break my Rogers contract I will still save money in the long run.&#xA;&#xA;Anyway, once the number got transferred over, I didn&#39;t have a 3G connection, even after selecting the WIND Home APN. &amp;nbsp;After a bit of google, it seems that what I had to do is to setup an APN. &amp;nbsp;In case I can&#39;t find it later, here are the APN settings:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>YEG Open Data, the 2010 Edmonton Municipal Election, and Android</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/archives/yeg-open-data-the-2010-edmonton-municipal-election-and-android/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Oct 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/archives/yeg-open-data-the-2010-edmonton-municipal-election-and-android/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;(Or, things to do when you have a sick kid)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;&lt;img style=&#34;border-right-width: 0px; display: inline; border-top-width: 0px; border-bottom-width: 0px; margin-left: 0px; border-left-width: 0px; margin-right: 0px&#34; title=&#34;election&#34; border=&#34;0&#34; alt=&#34;election&#34; align=&#34;right&#34; src=&#34;http://www.opgenorth.net/wp-content/uploads/2010/10/election.jpg&#34; width=&#34;126&#34; height=&#34;162&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;One of the new &lt;a href=&#34;http://data.edmonton.ca/&#34;&gt;data catalogues&lt;/a&gt; that the City of Edmonton has put up is the &lt;a href=&#34;http://data.edmonton.ca/DataBrowser/coe/Election2010Results#param=NOFILTER--DataView--Results&#34;&gt;2010 Election Results&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;#160; This Thanksgiving Long Weekend I was kind of “grounded” at home when my son came down with a nasty inner ear infection.&amp;#160; I was hanging out with him, and thought I could use the time to see how hard it would be and how quickly I could put together an Android application that would poll these results and show leading candidate in each contest for a given ward.&amp;#160; Turns out it was not that hard at all.&amp;#160; Development time was less than one day, and then I had the application running on my phone for a couple of days.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>New Version of YEG Buildings up</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/archives/new-version-of-yeg-buildings-up/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Aug 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/archives/new-version-of-yeg-buildings-up/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Last night I pushed a new build of &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.androidzoom.com/android_applications/reference/yeg-buildings_icyx.html&#34;&gt;YEG Buildings&lt;/a&gt; out to the Android Market. The two changes with this one:&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;ul&gt;   &lt;li&gt;Rather than showing the latitude/longitude of were you are, the application will try to translate that into a more human-friendly address.&amp;#160; Note that the address might not be 100% accurate.&amp;#160; It depends on how much accuracy the GPS has.&lt;/li&gt;    &lt;li&gt;The application no longer uses Google Maps and a KML feed when show where all the historical buildings in Edmonton are.&amp;#160; The map of Edmonton is now rendered locally, and all &lt;/li&gt; &lt;/ul&gt;  &lt;p&gt;Just for fun, I also &lt;a href=&#34;http://contest.apps4edmonton.ca/apps/21&#34;&gt;submitted YEG Buildings&lt;/a&gt; as part of the &lt;a href=&#34;http://contest.apps4edmonton.ca/&#34;&gt;Apps4Edmonton contest&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;#160; So, feel free to check out the contest page – there are a lot of neat applications there.&amp;#160; Also feel free to vote mine up.&amp;#160; :)&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>New Version of YEG Buildings (formerly Historical Buildings)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/archives/new-version-of-yeg-buildings-formerly-historical-buildings/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Aug 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/archives/new-version-of-yeg-buildings-formerly-historical-buildings/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;After a few months of neglect, I put a new version of my Edmonton Historical Buildings application up on the Android Market.&amp;#160; I’ve renamed it to just &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.androidzoom.com/android_applications/reference/yeg-buildings_icyx.html&#34;&gt;YEG Buildings&lt;/a&gt;, as I’d like to eventually include buildings that aren’t historical, but interesting in general for some reason.&amp;#160; The previous version had a nasty bug that would crash when you tried to view the location of a building on the map.&amp;#160; Was one of those curious things where it worked in the emulator but not on a real device.&amp;#160; I’ve tried it out on my HTC Dream running &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.cyanogenmod.com/&#34;&gt;Cyanogen 6.0 RC3&lt;/a&gt; (this is Android 2.2), and it seemed to work.&amp;#160; &lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Using IntelliJ for Android Development â the Sequel</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/archives/using-intellij-for-android-development-the-sequel/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Aug 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/archives/using-intellij-for-android-development-the-sequel/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A while ago, I posted a blog article about &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.opgenorth.net/2009/06/19/using-intellij-for-android-development-2/&#34;&gt;using IntelliJ for Android development&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;#160; Given that was a year ago, and one version of IntelliJ later, I thought I would do a follow up post.&amp;#160; Long story short (and to sound like a TV commercial):&amp;#160; I liked IntelliJ IDEA 9 so much, I bought a license.&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;Since I blogged last year, the Android plug-in for IntelliJ has really matured.&amp;#160; I guess the only draw back to it is that you only get the Android plug-in when you buy the Unlimited Edition of IntelliJ – it’s not in the Community Edition.&amp;#160; Here are some general comments/thoughts/observations of mine:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Android, MapView, and your Google apiKey: Part 2</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/archives/android-mapview-and-your-google-apikey-part-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Aug 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/archives/android-mapview-and-your-google-apikey-part-2/</guid>
      <description>Just to follow up on my &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.opgenorth.net/2010/04/07/android-mapview-and-your-google-apikey-part-1/&#34;&gt;last post&lt;/a&gt; about embedding Google Maps into your Android application (this part is kind of anti-climatic).&#xA;&#xA;So, by now you’ve signed your application.  This is the “hardest” (i.e. busiest part) of the whole process.  The next part, getting your Goggle apiKey, is the easy part.  First you  need to get the MD5 fingerprint of your keystore:&#xA;&#xA;keytool -list -alias androiddebugkey -keystore &amp;lt;path_to_debug_keystore&amp;gt;.keystore -storepass android -keypass android&#xA;&#xA;Once that is done, you and register for a &lt;a href=&#34;http://code.google. com/android/maps-api-signup.html&#34;&gt;Google Maps API key&lt;/a&gt;.  You need a Google account, and have to agree to some terms of service legal mumbo-jumbo, but it’s pretty simple.  Once you click “Generate API Key”, you will get your key string.  You then simply add the Maps API key to your MapView in your application.  There are a couple of ways to do this, heres how you would do it if you were using the XML layout files:&#xA;&#xA;Of course, after all this is done, the next trick is managing these keys.  You see, when you are working locally, your application is automatically signed using a debug key.  This is fine and dandy for most development.  However, when you deploy your application, you sign the application using your keystore that you created in &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.opgenorth.net/2010/04/07/android-mapview-and-your-google-apikey-part-1/&#34;&gt;Step 1&lt;/a&gt;.  You may have a brief moment of clarity here and realize that the apiKey from your debug keystore and your deployment keystore are different.  I’ve got some ideas on how to deal with that that, but that will be for another day.&#xA;&#xA;&lt;a href=&#34;http://code.google.com/android/add-ons/google-apis/mapkey.html&#34;&gt;Full documentation&lt;/a&gt; for all this can be found on the Android developer’s website.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Induction Into the Android Army â the Aftermath</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/archives/induction-into-the-android-army-the-aftermath/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Jun 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/archives/induction-into-the-android-army-the-aftermath/</guid>
      <description>Thanks to all who attended my “Induction into the Android Army” talk this afternoon at the monthly &lt;a href=&#34;http://groups.google.com/group/ejug&#34;&gt;Edmonton Java User’s Group&lt;/a&gt; meeting.&amp;#160; I’d say it was a good turn out, especially when one considers that this is only the second monthly meeting for EJUG.&amp;#160; It was a pretty basic talk, and didn’t dive to deeply into the “fun” Android stuff.&amp;#160; If anybody from EJUG wants a follow up presentation that’s a bit more in depth, give a shout out on the EJUG mailing list.&amp;#160; If there is enough interest, I’d be happy to put something together.  &lt;p&gt;If you want to &lt;a href=&#34;http://developer.android.com/resources/samples/NotePad/index.html&#34;&gt;browse the code&lt;/a&gt; and don’t want to download the Android SDK, you can do so at the Android website.&amp;#160; Otherwise if you have downloaded the SDK,&amp;#160; you can the samples/Notepad folder.&amp;#160; For those who want the PowerPoint slide deck, please hang tight and I’ll get a link to that shortly.&amp;#160; Basil already has a copy of it, and he’ll probably post it to the Google Group shortly as well.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Android at the Edmonton Java User Group</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/archives/android-at-the-edmonton-java-user-group/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Jun 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/archives/android-at-the-edmonton-java-user-group/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Just a heads up for those interested:&amp;#160; On Tuesday, June 15th the Edmonton Java User’s Group is having it’s monthly meeting at noon at the Canadian Western Bank Building.&amp;#160; The speaker is none other than yours truly.&amp;#160; I’ll be giving a brief introduction to application development to Android, using my trusty G1 and IntelliJ.&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;It’s free to attend, so stop by if you’re so inclined.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Gotta Love JetBrains</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/archives/gotta-love-jetbrains/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 May 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/archives/gotta-love-jetbrains/</guid>
      <description>Gotta love companies that &#34;get it&#34;.  Late last night I was hacking away on some Android stuff using IntelliJ 9.0.2 (on Ubuntu 10.04). For reasons unknown to me, none of my breakpoints seemed to be working.  In fact, IntelliJ just didn&#39;t seem to be working.  I narrowed it down to the breakpoints I was setting - it seemed that every time the breakpoints were being hit.  I managed to narrow it down to this error:&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34; style=&#34;border-collapse: separate; color: #000000; font-family: &#39;Times New Roman&#39;; font-style: normal; font-variant: normal; font-weight: normal; letter-spacing: normal; line-height: normal; orphans: 2; text-indent: 0px; text-transform: none; white-space: normal; widows: 2; word-spacing: 0px; font-size: medium;&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34; style=&#34;border-collapse: collapse; color: #444444; font-family: arial,sans-serif; font-size: 13px;&#34;&gt;[ 166030]  ERROR - lij.debugger.impl.InvokeThread - null&#xA;java.lang.UnsupportedOperationException&#xA;at com.sun.tools.jdi.ReferenceTypeImpl.sourceDebugExtension(ReferenceTypeImpl.java:774)&#xA;at org.jetbrains.plugins.ruby.jruby.debug.JRubyPositionManager.getPath(JRubyPositionManager.java:141)&#xA;at org.jetbrains.plugins.ruby.jruby.debug.JRubyPositionManager.getPsiFileByLocation(JRubyPositionManager.java:156)&#xA;at org.jetbrains.plugins.ruby.jruby.debug.JRubyPositionManager.getSourcePosition(JRubyPositionManager.java:51)&#xA;at com.intellij.debugger.engine.CompoundPositionManager.getSourcePosition(CompoundPositionManager.java:51)&#xA;at com.intellij.debugger.engine.ContextUtil.getSourcePosition(ContextUtil.java:63)&#xA;at com.intellij.debugger.impl.DebuggerSession$MyDebugProcessListener$2.compute(DebuggerSession.java:462)&#xA;at com.intellij.debugger.impl.DebuggerSession$MyDebugProcessListener$2.compute(DebuggerSession.java:460)&#xA;at com.intellij.psi.impl.PsiDocumentManagerImpl$3.run(PsiDocumentManagerImpl.java:298)&#xA;at com.intellij.psi.impl.PsiDocumentManagerImpl$4.run(PsiDocumentManagerImpl.java:321)&#xA;at com.intellij.openapi.application.impl.ApplicationImpl.runReadAction(ApplicationImpl.java:695)&#xA;at com.intellij.psi.impl.PsiDocumentManagerImpl.commitAndRunReadAction(PsiDocumentManagerImpl.java:317)&#xA;at com.intellij.psi.impl.PsiDocumentManagerImpl.commitAndRunReadAction(PsiDocumentManagerImpl.java:296)&#xA;at com.intellij.debugger.impl.DebuggerSession$MyDebugProcessListener.paused(DebuggerSession.java:460)&#xA;at com.intellij.debugger.engine.DebugProcessAdapterImpl.paused(DebugProcessAdapterImpl.java:28)&#xA;at sun.reflect.NativeMethodAccessorImpl.invoke0(Native Method)&#xA;at sun.reflect.NativeMethodAccessorImpl.invoke(NativeMethodAccessorImpl.java:57)&#xA;at sun.reflect.DelegatingMethodAccessorImpl.invoke(DelegatingMethodAccessorImpl.java:43)&#xA;at java.lang.reflect.Method.invoke(Method.java:616)&#xA;at com.intellij.util.EventDispatcher.dispatch(EventDispatcher.java:87)&#xA;at com.intellij.util.EventDispatcher.access$100(EventDispatcher.java:33)&#xA;at com.intellij.util.EventDispatcher$1.invoke(EventDispatcher.java:64)&#xA;at $Proxy84.paused(Unknown Source)&#xA;at com.intellij.debugger.engine.SuspendManagerImpl.notifyPaused(SuspendManagerImpl.java:306)&#xA;at com.intellij.debugger.engine.SuspendManagerImpl.b(SuspendManagerImpl.java:299)&#xA;at com.intellij.debugger.engine.SuspendManagerImpl.voteSuspend(SuspendManagerImpl.java:318)&#xA;at com.intellij.debugger.engine.DebugProcessEvents$1.contextAction(DebugProcessEvents.java:412)&#xA;at com.intellij.debugger.engine.events.SuspendContextCommandImpl.action(SuspendContextCommandImpl.java:62)&#xA;at com.intellij.debugger.engine.events.DebuggerCommandImpl.run(DebuggerCommandImpl.java:44)&#xA;at com.intellij.debugger.engine.DebuggerManagerThreadImpl.processEvent(DebuggerManagerThreadImpl.java:148)&#xA;at com.intellij.debugger.engine.DebuggerManagerThreadImpl.processEvent(DebuggerManagerThreadImpl.java:36)&#xA;at com.intellij.debugger.impl.InvokeThread.run(InvokeThread.java:135)&#xA;at com.intellij.debugger.impl.InvokeThread$WorkerThreadRequest.run(InvokeThread.java:52)&#xA;at com.intellij.openapi.application.impl.ApplicationImpl$5.run(ApplicationImpl.java:329)&#xA;at java.util.concurrent.Executors$RunnableAdapter.call(Executors.java:471)&#xA;at java.util.concurrent.FutureTask$Sync.innerRun(FutureTask.java:334)&#xA;at java.util.concurrent.FutureTask.run(FutureTask.java:166)&#xA;at java.util.concurrent.ThreadPoolExecutor.runWorker(ThreadPoolExecutor.java:1110)&#xA;at java.util.concurrent.ThreadPoolExecutor$Worker.run(ThreadPoolExecutor.java:603)&#xA;at java.lang.Thread.run(Thread.java:636)&#xA;at com.intellij.openapi.application.impl.ApplicationImpl$1$1.run(ApplicationImpl.java:125)&#xA;[ 166036]  ERROR - lij.debugger.impl.InvokeThread - IntelliJ IDEA 9.0.2  Build #IU-95.66&#xA;[ 166036]  ERROR - lij.debugger.impl.InvokeThread - JDK: 1.6.0_18&#xA;[ 166036]  ERROR - lij.debugger.impl.InvokeThread - VM: OpenJDK Server VM&#xA;[ 166036]  ERROR - lij.debugger.impl.InvokeThread - Vendor: Sun Microsystems Inc.&#xA;[ 166036]  ERROR - lij.debugger.impl.InvokeThread - OS: Linux&#xA;[ 166036]  ERROR - lij.debugger.impl.InvokeThread - Last Action: Debug&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;So, the problem to me seemed to be something wonky with IntelliJ.  I e-mailed Jetbrains, explaining the symptoms and the above stack trace.  This morning, I was pleased to find an e-mail from Serge  at Jetbrains.  He suggests disabling the Ruby plug-in that I have installed.&#xA;&#xA;BINGO!&#xA;&#xA;Worked like a charm.  Problem goes away, and in less than 12 hours since I asked for help.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Quick Update to HistoricalBuildings</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/archives/quick-update-to-historicalbuildings/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Apr 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/archives/quick-update-to-historicalbuildings/</guid>
      <description>I just &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.opgenorth.net/misc/HistoricalBuildings.apk&#34;&gt;uploaded an update&lt;/a&gt; to &lt;a href=&#34;http://github.com/topgenorth/historicalbuildings&#34;&gt;HistoricalBuildings&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;nbsp; The list of historical buildings used to be sorted alphabetically, by name.&amp;nbsp; Now they are sorted by the distance from your current location (assuming the GPS can figure that out).&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;zemanta-pixie&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;zemanta-pixie-img&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;http://img.zemanta.com/pixy.gif?x-id=fd558971-287a-8b68-8a02-ced06dd1630f&#34; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>YEG OpenData and their Historical Buildings on your Android phone</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/archives/historical-buildings/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Apr 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/archives/historical-buildings/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.opgenorth.net/wp-content/uploads/2010/04/worksonmymachinestarburst.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img style=&#34;border-bottom: 0px; border-left: 0px; margin: 0px 10px 0px 0px; display: inline; border-top: 0px; border-right: 0px&#34; title=&#34;works-on-my-machine-starburst&#34; border=&#34;0&#34; alt=&#34;works-on-my-machine-starburst&#34; align=&#34;left&#34; src=&#34;http://www.opgenorth.net/wp-content/uploads/2010/04/worksonmymachinestarburst_thumb.jpg&#34; width=&#34;154&#34; height=&#34;149&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Well, for the brave, criminally insane, curious, or otherwise bored I have a alpha version of Historical Buildings – &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.opgenorth.net/misc/HistoricalBuildings.apk&#34;&gt;download the APK&lt;/a&gt; if you want to try it out.&amp;#160; This is just, at this time, the application just shows a simple list of &lt;a href=&#34;http://data.edmonton.ca/DataBrowser.aspx?Container=coe&amp;amp;EntitySet=HistoricalBuildings&#34;&gt;historical buildings&lt;/a&gt; in Edmonton (according to the &lt;a href=&#34;http://data.edmonton.ca/&#34;&gt;City of Edmonton&#39;s Open Data Catalogue&lt;/a&gt;).&amp;#160; Click on a building, and it will show you on Google Maps where the building is in the city.&amp;#160; The &lt;a href=&#34;http://github.com/topgenorth/historicalbuildings&#34;&gt;code&lt;/a&gt; for this is, in my opinion (and to say the least) - rough.&amp;#160; But it is a start.&amp;#160; Definitely needs some improvement.&amp;#160; Or maybe I just need to change my thinking to more of a Android/Java mindset.&amp;#160; Anyway the usual caveats apply:&amp;#160; use at your own risk / batteries not include / do not eat / void where prohibited by law, etc, etc, etc&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Android, MapView, and your Google apiKey: Part 1</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/archives/android-mapview-and-your-google-apikey-part-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Apr 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/archives/android-mapview-and-your-google-apikey-part-1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.opgenorth.net/wp-content/uploads/2010/04/MapList1.png&#34;&gt;&lt;img style=&#34;display: inline; margin-left: 10px; margin-right: 0px&#34; title=&#34;MapList&#34; border=&#34;0&#34; alt=&#34;MapList&#34; align=&#34;right&#34; src=&#34;http://www.opgenorth.net/wp-content/uploads/2010/04/MapList_thumb1.png&#34; width=&#34;164&#34; height=&#34;244&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;Thanks to the &lt;a href=&#34;http://developer.android.com/guide/tutorials/views/hello-mapview.html&#34;&gt;MapView&lt;/a&gt;, it’s drop dead easy to put Google Maps into your application.&amp;#160; There are lots of posts out there how to do it.&amp;#160; Interestingly (to me anyway), when I did a quick search of the Android developers mailing list, I was surprised to see that a lot of people had the same problem:&amp;#160; basically, when you look at your MapView, you end up with a grid of white squares.&amp;#160; It kind of sucks.&amp;#160; There are a lot of blog posts and articles out there on how to fix this problem, but this one is for me, and to help me remember it.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Me, Android, and YEG OpenData</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/archives/me-android-and-yeg-opendata/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Apr 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/archives/me-android-and-yeg-opendata/</guid>
      <description>&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.opgenorth.net/wp-content/uploads/2010/04/YegDataList1.png&#34;&gt;&lt;img style=&#34;display: inline; margin-left: 10px; margin-right: 0px; border: 0px initial initial;&#34; title=&#34;YegDataList&#34; src=&#34;http://www.opgenorth.net/wp-content/uploads/2010/04/YegDataList_thumb1.png&#34; border=&#34;0&#34; alt=&#34;YegDataList&#34; width=&#34;164&#34; height=&#34;244&#34; align=&#34;right&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Not that long ago, the City of Edmonton announced it&#39;s &lt;a href=&#34;http://data.edmonton.ca/&#34;&gt;Open Data Catalogue&lt;/a&gt;.  I noticed that one of the data catalogues was a list of &lt;a href=&#34;http://data.edmonton.ca/DataBrowser.aspx?Container=coe&amp;amp;EntitySet=HistoricalBuildings&#34;&gt;historical buildings&lt;/a&gt; in the city.  Yeah, I know that some people in other cities might consider this a pretty weak list.  I mean, the oldest building in Edmonton isn’t even 150 years old.  I’d wager that some parts of the world consider 150 year old buildings to be “new construction”.  Anyway, as I&#39;ve been dabbling with &lt;a href=&#34;http://developer.android.com&#34;&gt;Android&lt;/a&gt; now for about the past year, I thought a handy little project to try out would be to write an app for Android that would show me where the historical buildings are in the city.&#xA;&#xA;I&#39;ve got the foundation of a simple application started over a GitHub called, not surprisingly, &lt;a href=&#34;http://github.com/topgenorth/historicalbuildings&#34;&gt;Historical Buildings&lt;/a&gt; (if you pull the source code, then just a heads up that I use &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.jetbrains.com/idea/&#34;&gt;IntelliJ&lt;/a&gt; for my Android development).  This application currently works in the emulator, my next step is to installing it on my phone and trying it out for real.  Right now all the application does is present you with a list of buildings.  You click on one, and you&#39;ll see on Google Maps where the building.&#xA;&#xA;Some other ideas for features that may or may not happen:&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&#x9;&lt;li&gt;Figure out the whole unit testing story in Android.  Then setup a build script.  Then a build server.  CI rocks, but as I’m trying to learn the Android framework and figure out what all the parts are, I’m not to focused on that at the moment.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&#x9;&lt;li&gt;Don’t always fetch the data – store it locally&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&#x9;&lt;li&gt;I don’t think the way I’m parsing the JSON result is very efficient or “proper”, but it does get the job done.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&#x9;&lt;li&gt;Notify the user when they are within a certain distance of a historical building.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&#x9;&lt;li&gt;Currently YEG has a PDF explaining the significance of the building.  Not very friendly/convenient for mobile devices.  Need something better.&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&#x9;&lt;li&gt;One thought would be to create Wikipedia entries and link to that.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&#x9;&lt;li&gt;Another thought is to petition the City of Edmonton to convert their PDF’s to a more neutral format (HTML anyone)?&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&#x9;&lt;li&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.epl.ca&#34;&gt;Edmonton Public Library&lt;/a&gt; has some information about the “&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.epl.ca/EPLPhotoBuildings.cfm&#34;&gt;Lost Building of Edmonton&lt;/a&gt;”.  Maybe incorporate that somehow – perhaps showing what buildings used to exist at a given address?&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&#x9;&lt;li&gt;Perhaps allow the user to update their coordinates for YEG’s historical buildings.  I’ve notice (on the emulator) that sometimes the lat/long isn’t exactly accurate.  If you look at the image below for the old Arlington Apartments, you notice that the marker should be over the pile of rubble slightly to the left of where it currently is.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&#x9;&lt;li&gt;Maybe include buildings that aren’t necessarily designated as historical, but are interesting architecturally or otherwise.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&#x9;&lt;li&gt;Instead of using YEG OpenData, perhaps an independent cloud based data store (&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.microsoft.com/windowsazure/&#34;&gt;Azure&lt;/a&gt; maybe?)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;If you’ve got any other suggestions, I’m happy to hear them.&#xA;&#xA;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.opgenorth.net/wp-content/uploads/2010/04/MapList.png&#34;&gt;&lt;img style=&#34;display: block; float: none; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; border: 0px;&#34; title=&#34;MapList&#34; src=&#34;http://www.opgenorth.net/wp-content/uploads/2010/04/MapList_thumb.png&#34; border=&#34;0&#34; alt=&#34;MapList&#34; width=&#34;219&#34; height=&#34;326&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&lt;div class=&#34;zemanta-pixie&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;zemanta-pixie-img&#34; src=&#34;http://img.zemanta.com/pixy.gif?x-id=e1a8a615-56c6-883e-b52b-35084586f039&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Where Did the Time Go?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/archives/where-did-the-time-go/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Jan 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/archives/where-did-the-time-go/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.opgenorth.net/wp-content/uploads/2010/01/tumbleweed1.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img title=&#34;tumbleweed&#34; style=&#34;border-right: 0px; border-top: 0px; display: inline; margin-left: 0px; border-left: 0px; margin-right: 0px; border-bottom: 0px&#34; height=&#34;75&#34; alt=&#34;tumbleweed&#34; src=&#34;http://www.opgenorth.net/wp-content/uploads/2010/01/tumbleweed_thumb1.jpg&#34; width=&#34;90&#34; align=&#34;left&#34; border=&#34;0&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Yeah, I’ve been kind of quiet as of late.&amp;#160; So quiet, I suspect that some people might be wondering if something happened.&amp;#160; I was a bit surprised to see that the last time I had blogged was after TechDays in Calgary.&amp;#160; Well, nothing significant has happened - just a bit of laziness augmented by a touch of tech-burnout compounded by the odd bit of single malt scotch.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Getting Starting with my ADP1</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/archives/getting-starting-with-my-adp1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Sep 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/archives/getting-starting-with-my-adp1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;After a bit of tinkering, I managed to provision my ADP1 setup without a SIM card.&amp;#160; A bit of google, and here is what I did&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;ol&gt;   &lt;li&gt;Download the Android SDK.&amp;#160; In my case, I unzipped it to C:\android-sdk-windows-1.1_r1. &lt;/li&gt;    &lt;li&gt;Connection the phone via the USB cable to my computer.&amp;#160; When the phone asks for a device. &lt;/li&gt;    &lt;li&gt;You’ll get the new hardware dialog, when prompted for the drivers, you’ll need to specify the location.&amp;#160; The Android SDK has the drivers, in my case they were at C:\android-sdk-windows-1.1_r1\usb_driver\x86. &lt;/li&gt;    &lt;li&gt;Once you have the drivers installed cd to c:\android-sdk-windows-1.1_r1\tools. &lt;/li&gt;    &lt;li&gt;Type adb devices.&amp;#160; This should list all the Android devices that you have connected.&amp;#160; If you don’t see any devices listed, then you have a problem. &lt;/li&gt;    &lt;li&gt;Type adb shell.&amp;#160; This will direct your commands to your ADP1 &lt;/li&gt;    &lt;li&gt;Now while at the adb shell, su to root, then :&amp;#160; &lt;/li&gt;    &lt;li&gt;cd /data/data/com.android/providers.settings/databases/ &lt;/li&gt;    &lt;li&gt;sqlite3 settings.db &lt;/li&gt;    &lt;li&gt;INSERT INTO system (name, value) VALUES (‘device_provisioned’, 1); &lt;/li&gt;    &lt;li&gt;.quit &lt;/li&gt;    &lt;li&gt;Reboot the phone &lt;/li&gt;    &lt;li&gt;adb shell &lt;/li&gt;    &lt;li&gt;am start –a android.intent.action.MAIN –n com.android.settings/.Settings &lt;/li&gt; &lt;/ol&gt;  &lt;p&gt;Once all that is done, you should be enable to use your ADP1 as if you had a SIM card in it (we’ll except for the phoning part).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Using IntelliJ for Android Development</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/archives/using-intellij-for-android-development-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Jun 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/archives/using-intellij-for-android-development-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;(Note:&amp;#160; this article is pretty dated, and used IntelliJ 8.&amp;#160; I plan a follow-up covering IntelliJ 9)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;So I have this semi-fancy Google &lt;a href=&#34;http://developer.android.com/guide/developing/device.html&#34;&gt;Android Dev Phone 1&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;#160; Lately I&#39;ve been devoting part of my spare time to learning about programming for &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.android.com/&#34;&gt;Android&lt;/a&gt; (the OS of the phone).&amp;#160; Google (probably because they didn&#39;t ask for my opinion and/or input) decided to use Java as the lingua franca for Android programming.&amp;#160; If you ask me - and I know you will - they should have used C# and Mono (I might be a bit biased here).&amp;#160; Luckily, years ago I had done Java programming, so I wasn&#39;t that intimidated by the use of Java on Android.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Getting Started Coding for my Android Dev Phone 1</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/archives/getting-started-coding-for-my-android-dev-phone-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Mar 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/archives/getting-started-coding-for-my-android-dev-phone-1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Figured I was due to spend some time setting up a Linux VM and learning how to program my Android Dev Phone 1.&amp;#160; &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.eclipse.org&#34;&gt;Eclipse&lt;/a&gt; is what is recommended, so I thought I’d give that a try first.&amp;#160; So, with the help of &lt;a href=&#34;www.susestudio.com&#34;&gt;Suse Studio&lt;/a&gt;, I quick built myself a VM with Java 1.6 (&lt;em&gt;Aside:&amp;#160; I love Suse Studio, I can provision a VM in minutes&lt;/em&gt;).&amp;#160; I figured it would be pretty straight forward.&amp;#160; The docs on the Android Developer site for &lt;a href=&#34;http://developer.android.com/guide/developing/tools/adt.html#installingplugin&#34;&gt;installing ADT plug-in&lt;/a&gt; seem pretty straight forward and simple, and I remember Eclipse having a very rich ecosystem of plug-ins that were easy to install (something I wish Visual Studio had – hint, hint Microsoft).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Getting Started with My ADP1</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/archives/getting-started-with-my-adp1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Mar 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/archives/getting-started-with-my-adp1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;After a bit of tinkering, I managed to provision my ADP1 setup without a SIM card.&amp;#160; A bit of google, and here is what I did:&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;ol&gt;   &lt;li&gt;Download the Android SDK.&amp;#160; In my case, I unzipped it to C:\android-sdk-windows-1.1_r1. &lt;/li&gt;    &lt;li&gt;Connection the phone via the USB cable to my computer.&amp;#160; When the phone asks for a device. &lt;/li&gt;    &lt;li&gt;You&#39;ll get the new hardware dialog, when prompted for the drivers, you&#39;ll need to specify the location.&amp;#160; The Android SDK has the drivers, in my case they were at C:\android-sdk-windows-1.1_r1\usb_driver\x86. &lt;/li&gt;    &lt;li&gt;Once you have the drivers installed cd to c:\android-sdk-windows-1.1_r1\tools. &lt;/li&gt;    &lt;li&gt;Type adb devices.&amp;#160; This should list all the Android devices that you have connected.&amp;#160; If you don&#39;t see any devices listed, then you have a problem. &lt;/li&gt;    &lt;li&gt;Type adb shell.&amp;#160; This will direct your commands to your ADP1 &lt;/li&gt;    &lt;li&gt;Now while at the adb shell, su to root, then :&amp;#160; &lt;/li&gt;    &lt;li&gt;cd /data/data/com.android/providers.settings/databases/ &lt;/li&gt;    &lt;li&gt;sqlite3 settings.db &lt;/li&gt;    &lt;li&gt;INSERT INTO system (name, value) VALUES (&#39;device_provisioned&#39;, 1); &lt;/li&gt;    &lt;li&gt;.quit &lt;/li&gt;    &lt;li&gt;Reboot the phone &lt;/li&gt;    &lt;li&gt;adb shell &lt;/li&gt;    &lt;li&gt;am start -a android.intent.action.MAIN -n com.android.settings/.Settings &lt;/li&gt; &lt;/ol&gt;  &lt;p&gt;Once all that is done, you should be enable to use your ADP1 as if you had a SIM card in it (we&#39;ll except for the phoning part).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Got my Google Dev Phone 1</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/archives/got-my-google-dev-phone-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Mar 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/archives/got-my-google-dev-phone-1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;After an uneventful flight from YEG to PSP, I&#39;m settled in with my family.&amp;#160; After spending some time with beer at the pool, I&#39;m sitting down with my Android Dev Phone 1 that I ordered last week (ship to PSP).&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;First impressions:&amp;#160; it seems like a nice phone, and I like the fact it has a keyboard.&amp;#160; I don&#39;t have a SIM card to help with provisioning the phone, so all I get is this message saying &amp;quot;No SIM in phone&amp;quot; and &amp;quot;Emergency call&amp;quot;.A quick search on Google &lt;a href=&#34;http://android-tricks.blogspot.com/2009/01/using-adp1-without-sim-card.html&#34;&gt;tells me&lt;/a&gt; that how to get around this and use WiFi.&amp;#160; So, that&#39;s my task for tonight. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
