<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Arduino on Opgenorth.NET</title><link>https://topgenorth.github.io/tags/arduino/</link><description>Recent content in Arduino on Opgenorth.NET</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2013 17:02:40 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://topgenorth.github.io/tags/arduino/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Measuring Distance with Arduino</title><link>https://topgenorth.github.io/posts/measure-distance-with-arduino/</link><pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2013 17:02:40 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://topgenorth.github.io/posts/measure-distance-with-arduino/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href="http://www.parallax.com/product/28015"&gt;Ping)))&lt;/a&gt; is ultrasonic range finder that is pretty easy to use in an Arduino project. In my case, I&amp;rsquo;m using it to monitor the water level in a sump pump. I have an Arduino Uno R3 (with Ethernet Shield) connected to a Ping))) and a &lt;a href="https://www.sparkfun.com/products/10988"&gt;TMP36&lt;/a&gt; temperature sensor that is perched above my sump pump. Every 2 minutes the Uno will send out a ping, and figure out the distance to the water below. The TMP36 is used to account for the air temperature in the speed of sound calculations.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Sublime Text 2 and Arduino</title><link>https://topgenorth.github.io/posts/sublime-text-and-arduino/</link><pubDate>Sat, 09 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://topgenorth.github.io/posts/sublime-text-and-arduino/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;re looking to get into Arduino, and you&amp;rsquo;re a programmer, the first thing that will jump out at you is the Arduino IDE. It&amp;rsquo;s best described as &amp;ldquo;spartan&amp;rdquo; (to say the least). As I&amp;rsquo;m used to full featured IDE&amp;rsquo;s I started looking for a replacement to the default Arduino IDE.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are extensions to use Visual Studio, but that means me starting up a VM to run Windows which I don&amp;rsquo;t really want to do for Arduino development. There is a another IDE which looks promising called Maria Mole - but it&amp;rsquo;s Windows only so not really a contender for me. I need something for OS X. I looked at setting up Eclipse as my default IDE, but ran into some issues with that. Nothing to major, but as I don&amp;rsquo;t like Eclipse in the first place I wasn&amp;rsquo;t to motivated to sort things out, so I abandoned Eclipse as an IDE choice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The next thing I tried was &lt;a href="http://www.sublimetext.com/"&gt;Sublime Text&lt;/a&gt;. There is an Ardunio plugin called &lt;a href="https://github.com/Robot-Will/Stino"&gt;Stino&lt;/a&gt; that turns Sublime into a not bad IDE. In terms of writing your programs, Stino can pretty much do everything the Arduino IDE can do: compile programs, upload them to your Arduino board, import libraries, etc.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>